<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-514"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-514"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-514"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-514/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-514/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-514/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-514/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_514">
          <num>17a-514</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-194d). Emergency confinement in hospital for psychiatric disabilities of inmates of correctional institutions</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 17a-514. (Formerly Sec. 17-194d). Emergency confinement in hospital for psychiatric disabilities of inmates of correctional institutions.Any person who is in the custody of the Commissioner of Correction who has suddenly become in need of care and treatment in a hospital for a psychiatric disorder, other than drug dependence, whom a physician designated by the Commissioner of Correction finds is a danger to himself or others or to the security or order of the institution wherein he is confined may be confined in a hospital under an emergency certificate as hereinafter provided, for not more than fifteen days without order of any court. If a written complaint for commitment of such person has been filed in the court of probate for the district wherein such person is hospitalized prior to the expiration of such fifteen days such confinement shall be continued under such emergency certificate for an additional thirty days, without further order, not more than forty-five days in all, until the completion of the probate proceedings. At any time such person is found not to be a person with psychiatric disabilities, the superintendent of such hospital shall immediately return him to any institution administered by the Department of Correction as the Commissioner of Correction shall designate, unless his custody in the Commissioner of Correction has terminated, in which case he shall be discharged. The emergency certificate provided for in this section shall be left with the person in charge of such hospital at the time of delivery of the person to such hospital and such certificate shall be dated not more than three days prior to its delivery, signed by a physician licensed to practice medicine and surgery under the provisions of chapter 370, who is designated by the Commissioner of Correction. Such certificate shall state the date of the personal examination of the person to be confined, which shall be not more than three days prior to the date of signature of the certificate, shall state the findings of the physician relative to the physical and mental condition of the person and the history of the case, if known, and shall state that it is the opinion of the physician that the person examined by him is in need of immediate care in a hospital. Prior to hospitalization under the provisions of this section, any person shall have the right to be examined by a physician of his own choosing, and if such physician concludes from his examination that such person does not have psychiatric disabilities, such person shall not be admitted to or detained in a hospital under the provisions of this section. If a person with psychiatric disabilities has been admitted to any hospital under the provisions of this section, the person in charge thereof shall cause proceedings to be instituted for the commitment, pursuant to the provisions of section17a-498, of such person in the court of probate having jurisdiction in the town where such hospital is located. Any irregularity in the temporary confinement of such person shall be deemed cured by the judge of probate ordering his commitment, and no such commitment shall be invalid because of such irregularity.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>