<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-509"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-509"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-509"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-509/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-509/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-509/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-509/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_509">
          <num>17a-509</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-191). Placement of persons with psychiatric disabilities in residential care homes or chronic and convalescent hospitals</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_509__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section17a-458, may place any person with psychiatric disabilities committed to such state-operated facility, if such person is no longer in need of active psychiatric treatment in such state-operated facility, in a residential care home licensed by the Department of Public Health in accordance with sections19a-490to19a-503, inclusive, or a chronic and convalescent hospital, provided such person shall, despite such transfer, remain subject to the medical supervision of the superintendent or director of such state-operated facility, and such superintendent or director may, if medically indicated, order and provide for the return of any such patient to such state-operated facility, subject to any limitations of the term of commitment contained in the order of commitment under which such patient was committed to such state-operated facility. The provisions of this section shall not apply to any person who is under a term of imprisonment or who has not met the requirements of the condition of release set to provide the reasonable assurance of such person's appearance in court.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>