<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-467"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-467"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-467"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-467/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-467/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-467/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-467/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_467">
          <num>17a-467</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-211b). Private treatment of patients in Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services facilities. Payment for treatment</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_467__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services may allow any physician or psychiatrist licensed to practice in this state to conduct private treatment of any of his patients who have been admitted to any of the facilities of the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services. Any such private treatment carried out in any of said facilities shall be conducted jointly with the staff of the facility and shall be subject to the approval of the superintendent or director of the facility who shall retain ultimate responsibility for the care and treatment of all patients under his control.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_467__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any patient, or the family or guardian of, or any other person having legal responsibility for, such patient who, while such patient is in a facility of the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services, engages the private services of a physician or psychiatrist under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_467__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section shall be responsible for and pay all fees and other charges of such physician or psychiatrist for such services. If the superintendent or director of a facility of the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services gives his consent for a patient, under his care, to obtain and receive any such private treatment while the patient is in the facility, such consent shall not confer any responsibility or otherwise impose any liability on the department or on any other state department or agency for the treatment, fees or other charges of any such physician or psychiatrist.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>