<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-548"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-548"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-548"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-548/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-548/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-548/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-548/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_548">
          <num>17a-548</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-206i). Patient's rights re clothing, possessions, money and access to records. List of rights to be posted</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_548__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any patient shall be permitted to wear his or her own clothes; to keep and use personal possessions including toilet articles; to be present during any search of his or her personal possessions, except a patient hospitalized in the maximum security service of Whiting Forensic Hospital when such search is conducted by police officers and probable cause exists that contraband or hazardous items are hidden in the patient's living area; to have access to individual storage space for such possessions; and in such manner as determined by the facility to spend a reasonable sum of his or her own money for canteen expenses and small purchases. These rights shall be denied only if the superintendent, director or his or her authorized representative determines that it is medically harmful to the patient to exercise such rights. An explanation of such denial shall be placed in the patient's permanent clinical record.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_548__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In connection with any litigation related to hospitalization, or at any time following discharge from the facility, any patient or his or her attorney shall have the right, upon written request, to inspect all of such patient's hospital records, and to make copies thereof. Unless the request is made in connection with any litigation related to hospitalization, a mental health facility, as defined in subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_548__subsec_b__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of section52-146d, may refuse to disclose any portion of a patient's record which the mental health facility determines:</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_548__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Would create a substantial risk that the patient would inflict life-threatening injury to self or to others or experience a severe deterioration in mental state;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_548__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>would constitute an invasion of privacy of another person; or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_548__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>would violate an assurance of confidentiality furnished to another person, provided only such portion of the record the disclosure of which would not constitute an invasion of privacy of another person or violate an assurance of confidentiality furnished to another person shall be disclosed. Any patient aggrieved by a facility's refusal to disclose under this subsection may petition the Superior Court for relief in the same manner as a patient proceeding under section4-105, except that in addition to notice and a hearing, the court may conduct an in camera review of the record. The court shall order disclosure of the record by such facility unless the court determines that the disclosure (A) would create a substantial risk that the patient would inflict life-threatening injury to self or to others or experience a severe deterioration in mental state, or (B) would constitute an invasion of privacy of another person, or (C) would violate an assurance of confidentiality furnished to another person, provided if the court orders disclosure of the record, only such portion of the record the disclosure of which would not constitute an invasion of privacy of another person or violate an assurance of confidentiality furnished to another person shall be disclosed.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_548__subsec_b__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>would create a substantial risk that the patient would inflict life-threatening injury to self or to others or experience a severe deterioration in mental state, or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_548__subsec_b__subsec_3__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>would constitute an invasion of privacy of another person, or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_548__subsec_b__subsec_3__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>would violate an assurance of confidentiality furnished to another person, provided if the court orders disclosure of the record, only such portion of the record the disclosure of which would not constitute an invasion of privacy of another person or violate an assurance of confidentiality furnished to another person shall be disclosed.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_548__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A list of all in-hospital rights shall be prominently posted in each ward where mental health services are provided. Such list shall include, but not be limited to, the right to leave, as afforded by subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_548__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section17a-506, the right to a hearing, as afforded by subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_548__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section17a-502, and the right to file a complaint, as afforded by the hospital's complaint procedure.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_548__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_548__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section shall limit a patient's right of access to his records under section4-104.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>