<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-520"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-520"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-520"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-520/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-520/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-520/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-520/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_520">
          <num>17a-520</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-197). Commitment at expiration of term of imprisonment</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 17a-520. (Formerly Sec. 17-197). Commitment at expiration of term of imprisonment.When any person has been transferred from any correctional institution to a state hospital for persons with psychiatric disabilities and is confined in such hospital at the time of the expiration of the term of imprisonment for which he was committed and then has psychiatric disabilities, the superintendent of such hospital shall cause proceedings for the commitment of such person to be instituted in the court of probate having jurisdiction in the town where such hospital is located, unless such person is already under an order of commitment of a court of probate. The court of probate shall appoint two physicians of recognized standing, and such physicians shall fully investigate the facts of the case and report to the court. If such physicians report that such person has psychiatric disabilities and the court so finds, it may order such person detained in such hospital until he has recovered his sanity. Any person committed under the provisions of this section may be paroled under the provisions of section17a-521or placed in a licensed boarding home under the provisions of section17a-509. During the pendency of any application for commitment under the provisions of this section, any person may be detained at any state hospital for persons with psychiatric disabilities for a period not exceeding thirty days beyond the expiration of his sentence. Any person aggrieved by any order of a probate court under the provisions hereof may within thirty days appeal to the superior court for the judicial district having jurisdiction.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>