<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-453j"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-453j"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-453j"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-453j/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-453j/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-453j/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-453j/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_453j">
          <num>17a-453j</num>
          <heading>Program for persons diagnosed with recent-onset schizophrenia spectrum disorder. Report</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_453j__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services, in consultation with the Commissioner of Children and Families, shall establish, within available appropriations, a program for persons diagnosed with recent-onset schizophrenia spectrum disorder for specialized treatment early in such persons' psychosis. Such program shall serve as a hub for the state-wide dissemination of information regarding best practices for the provision of early intervention services to persons diagnosed with a recent-onset schizophrenia spectrum disorder. Such program shall address</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453j__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the limited knowledge of (A) region-specific needs in treating such disorder, (B) the prevalence of first-episode psychosis in persons diagnosed with such disorder, and (C) disparities across different regions in treating such disorder,</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_453j__subsec_a__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>region-specific needs in treating such disorder,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_453j__subsec_a__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the prevalence of first-episode psychosis in persons diagnosed with such disorder, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_453j__subsec_a__subsec_1__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>disparities across different regions in treating such disorder,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453j__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>uncertainty regarding the availability and readiness of clinicians to implement early intervention services for persons diagnosed with such disorder and such persons' families, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453j__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>funding of and reimbursement for early intervention services available to persons diagnosed with such disorder.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_453j__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The program established pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_453j__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section shall perform the following functions:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453j__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Develop structured curricula, online resources and videoconferencing-based case conferences to disseminate information for the development of knowledge and skills relevant to patients with first-episode psychosis and such patients' families;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453j__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Assess and improve the quality of early intervention services available to persons diagnosed with a recent-onset schizophrenic spectrum disorder across the state;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453j__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provide expert input on complex cases of a recent-onset schizophrenic spectrum disorder and launch a referral system for consultation with persons having expertise in treating such disorders;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453j__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Share lessons and resources from any campaigns aimed at reducing the duration of untreated psychosis to improve local pathways to care for persons with such disorders;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453j__subsec_a__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Serve as an incubator for new evidence-based treatment approaches and pilot such approaches for deployment across the state;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453j__subsec_a__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Advocate for policies addressing the financing, regulation and provision of services for persons with such disorders; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453j__subsec_a__subsec_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Collaborate with state agencies to improve outcomes for persons diagnosed with first-episode psychosis in areas including, but not limited to, crisis services and employment services.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_453j__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Not later than January 1, 2025, and annually thereafter, the Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services shall report, in accordance with the provisions of section11-4a, to the joint standing committee of the General Assembly having cognizance of matters relating to public health, regarding the functions and outcomes of the program for specialized treatment early in psychosis and any recommendations for legislation to address the needs of persons diagnosed with recent-onset schizophrenic spectrum disorders.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>