<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-488a"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-488a"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-488a"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-488a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-488a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-488a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-488a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_488a">
          <num>17a-488a</num>
          <heading>Investigation of report. Findings, recommendations and disclosure of results. Registry. Confidentiality. Right of access to records</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_488a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services, upon receiving a report under section17a-488that a patient is being or has been abused, shall investigate the report to determine the condition of the patient and what action and services, if any, are required. The investigation shall include</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_488a__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>an in-person visit to the named patient,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_488a__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>consultation with those individuals having knowledge of the facts surrounding the particular report, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_488a__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>an interview with the patient, unless the patient refuses to consent to such interview. Upon completion of the investigation, the commissioner shall prepare written findings that shall include recommended actions. Not later than forty-five days after completion of the investigation, the commissioner shall disclose, in general terms, the result of the investigation to the person or persons who reported the suspected abuse, provided: (A) The person who made such report is legally mandated to make such report, (B) the information is not otherwise privileged or confidential under state or federal law, (C) the names of the witnesses or other persons interviewed are kept confidential, and (D) the names of the person or persons suspected to be responsible for the abuse are not disclosed unless such person or persons have been arrested as a result of the investigation.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_488a__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The person who made such report is legally mandated to make such report,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_488a__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the information is not otherwise privileged or confidential under state or federal law,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_488a__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the names of the witnesses or other persons interviewed are kept confidential, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_488a__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the names of the person or persons suspected to be responsible for the abuse are not disclosed unless such person or persons have been arrested as a result of the investigation.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_488a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services shall maintain a state-wide registry of the number of reports received under this section, the allegations contained in such reports and the outcomes of the investigations resulting from such reports.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_488a__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The patient's file, including, but not limited to, the original report and the investigation report shall not be deemed a public record or subject to the provisions of section1-210. The commissioner may disclose such file, in whole or in part, to an individual, agency, corporation or organization only with the written authorization of the patient, the patient's legal representative or as otherwise authorized under this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_488a__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_488a__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, the commissioner shall not disclose the name of a person who reported suspected abuse, except with such person's written permission or to a law enforcement official pursuant to a court order that specifically requires such disclosure.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_488a__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The patient or such patient's legal representative or attorney shall have the right of access to records made, maintained or kept on file by the department, in accordance with all applicable state and federal law, when such records pertain to or contain information or material concerning the patient, including, but not limited to, records concerning investigations, reports or medical, psychological or psychiatric examinations of the patient, except:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_488a__subsec_e__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If protected health information was obtained by the department from someone other than a health care provider under the promise of confidentiality and the access requested would, with reasonable likelihood, reveal the source of the information;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_488a__subsec_e__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>information identifying the individual who reported the abuse of the person shall not be released unless, upon application made to the Superior Court by the patient or such patient's legal representative or attorney and served on the Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services, a judge determines, after in camera inspection of relevant records and a hearing, that there is reasonable cause to believe the individual knowingly made a false report or that other interests of justice require such release;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_488a__subsec_e__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>if it is determined by a licensed health care provider that the access requested is reasonably likely to endanger the life or physical safety of the patient or another person;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_488a__subsec_e__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>if the protected health information makes reference to another person, other than a health care provider, and the access requested would reveal protected health information about such other person; or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_488a__subsec_e__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the request for access is made by the patient's legal representative, and a licensed health care provider has determined, in the exercise of professional judgment, that the provision of access to such legal representative is reasonably likely to cause harm to the patient or another person.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>