<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-500"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-500"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-500"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-500/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-500/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-500/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-500/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_500">
          <num>17a-500</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-180). Maintenance and confidentiality of records of cases of persons with psychiatric disabilities. Exchange of information concerning commitment or admission status of firearm permit or certificate applicants and holders</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_500__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each court of probate shall keep a record of the cases relating to persons with psychiatric disabilities coming before it under sections17a-75to17a-83, inclusive,17a-450to17a-483, inclusive,17a-495to17a-528, inclusive,17a-540to17a-550, inclusive,17a-560to17a-575, inclusive, and17a-615to17a-618, inclusive, and the disposition of them. It shall also keep on file the original application and certificate of physicians required by said sections, or a microfilm duplicate of such records in accordance with regulations issued by the Probate Court Administrator. All records maintained in the courts of probate under the provisions of said sections shall be sealed and available only to the respondent or his or her counsel unless the Court of Probate, after hearing held with notice to the respondent, determines such records should be disclosed for cause shown.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_500__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services shall, notwithstanding the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_500__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, maintain information, in accordance with section17a-499, on commitment orders by a probate court, section17a-506a, on voluntary admissions, and section17a-502, on commitment under an emergency certificate, and shall provide such information to the Commissioner of Emergency Services and Public Protection in fulfillment of the commissioner's obligations under sections29-28to29-38, inclusive, and section53-202d, in such a manner as to report identifying information on the commitment or voluntary admission status, including, but not limited to, name, address, sex, date of birth and date of commitment or admission, for a person who applies for or holds a permit or certificate under said sections29-28to29-38, inclusive, and section53-202d. The Commissioner of Emergency Services and Public Protection shall maintain as confidential any such information provided to the commissioner and shall use such information only for purposes of fulfilling the commissioner's obligations under sections29-28to29-38, inclusive, and section53-202d, except that nothing in this section shall prohibit said commissioner from entering such information into evidence at a hearing held in accordance with section29-32b.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_500__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <paragraph eId="17a_500__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services shall obtain from the Commissioner of Emergency Services and Public Protection the status of any firearm application, permit or certificate under sections29-28to29-38, inclusive, and section53-202d, of each person who is the subject of an order of commitment as provided in section17a-499or is the subject of a voluntary admission as provided in section17a-506a, in such a manner so as to only receive a report on the firearm application, permit or certificate status of the person with respect to whom the inquiry is made.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_500__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services shall report to the Commissioner of Emergency Services and Public Protection any commitment or voluntary admission status and identifying information for any person who is an applicant for or holder of any permit or certificate under said sections29-28to29-38, inclusive, and section53-202d.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_500__subsec_c__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services shall advise the hospital for psychiatric disabilities to which a person has been committed or voluntarily admitted of the status of a firearm application, permit or certificate of such person under sections29-28to29-38, inclusive, and section53-202d, as reported by the Commissioner of Emergency Services and Public Protection for consideration by such hospital in any psychiatric treatment procedures.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_500__subsec_c__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services and a hospital for psychiatric disabilities shall maintain as confidential any information provided to said commissioner or such hospital concerning the status of a firearm application, permit or certificate under sections29-28to29-38, inclusive, and section53-202d, of any person.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>