<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-566"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-566"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-566"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-566/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-566/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-566/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-566/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_566">
          <num>17a-566</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-244). Certain convicted persons to be examined. Report and recommendation</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_566__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as provided in section17a-574, any court prior to sentencing a person convicted of an offense for which the penalty may be imprisonment in any correctional institution of this state, or of a sex offense involving</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_566__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>physical force or violence,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_566__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>disparity of age between an adult and a minor, or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_566__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a sexual act of a compulsive or repetitive nature, may, if it appears to the court that such person has psychiatric disabilities and is dangerous to himself or others, upon its own motion or upon request of any of the persons enumerated in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_566__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section and a subsequent finding that such request is justified, order the commissioner to conduct an examination of the convicted defendant by qualified personnel of the hospital. Upon completion of such examination the examiner shall report in writing to the court. Such report shall indicate whether the convicted defendant should be committed to the diagnostic unit of the hospital for additional examination or should be sentenced in accordance with the conviction. Such examination shall be conducted and the report made to the court not later than fifteen days after the order for the examination. Such examination may be conducted at a correctional facility if the defendant is confined or it may be conducted on an outpatient basis at the hospital or other appropriate location. If the report recommends additional examination at the diagnostic unit, the court may, after a hearing, order the convicted defendant committed to the diagnostic unit of the hospital for a period not to exceed sixty days, except as provided in section17a-567provided the hearing may be waived by the defendant. Such commitment shall not be effective until the director certifies to the court that space is available at the diagnostic unit. While confined in said diagnostic unit, the defendant shall be given a complete physical and psychiatric examination by the staff of the unit and may receive medication and treatment without his consent. The director shall have authority to procure all court records, institutional records and probation or other reports which provide information about the defendant.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_566__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The request for such examination may be made by the state's attorney or assistant state's attorney who prosecuted the defendant for an offense specified in this section, or by the defendant or his attorney in his behalf. If the court orders such examination, a copy of the examination order shall be served upon the defendant to be examined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_566__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon completion of the physical and psychiatric examination of the defendant, but not later than sixty days after admission to the diagnostic unit, a written report of the results thereof shall be filed in quadruplicate with the clerk of the court before which he was convicted, and such clerk shall cause copies to be delivered to the state's attorney, to counsel for the defendant and to the Court Support Services Division.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_566__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such report shall include the following:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_566__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A description of the nature of the examination;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_566__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a diagnosis of the mental condition of the defendant;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_566__subsec_d__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>an opinion as to whether the diagnosis and prognosis demonstrate clearly that the defendant is actually dangerous to himself or others and requires custody, care and treatment at the hospital; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_566__subsec_d__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a recommendation as to whether the defendant should be sentenced in accordance with the conviction, sentenced in accordance with the conviction and confined in the hospital for custody, care and treatment, placed on probation by the court or placed on probation by the court with the requirement, as a condition to probation, that he receive outpatient psychiatric treatment.
See Sec. 53-22 re court-ordered psychiatric examinations.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>