<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-453h"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-453h"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-453h"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-453h/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-453h/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-453h/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-453h/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_453h">
          <num>17a-453h</num>
          <heading>*(See end of section for amended version of subdivision (1) of subsection (c) and effective date.) Mental health first aid training program</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_453h__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and effective date.) Mental health first aid training program.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_453h__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services, in consultation with the Commissioner of Education, shall administer a mental health first aid training program. Said program shall:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453h__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Help persons attending the training program recognize the signs of mental disorders in children and young adults; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453h__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>connect children and young adults who show signs of having a mental disorder with a professional who offers the appropriate services.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_453h__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Said commissioners may seek federal and state funding and may accept private donations for the administration of, and providing for persons to participate in, the mental health first aid training program.
*</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_453h__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453h__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For the school year commencing July 1, 2014, the Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services shall provide mental health first aid training to any person appointed to serve as the district safe school climate coordinator, pursuant to section10-222k. Each such district safe school climate coordinator shall successfully complete such mental health first aid training.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453h__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For the school year commencing July 1, 2015, the Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services shall provide mental health and first aid training to any person appointed to serve as the district safe school climate coordinator for such school year and who did not serve as the district safe school climate coordinator for the prior school year or did not otherwise successfully complete such training. Each such district safe school climate coordinator shall successfully complete such mental health first aid training.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453h__subsec_c__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>No district safe school climate coordinator shall be required to successfully complete such mental health first aid training more than once.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_453h__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each local and regional board of education may require teachers, school nurses, counselors and other school employees to participate in mental health first aid training.
*Note:On and after July 1, 2025, subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453h__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_453h__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, as amended by section 70 of public act 23-167, is to read as follows:
“</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_453h__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <paragraph eId="17a_453h__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For the school year commencing July 1, 2025, the Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services shall provide mental health first aid training to any person appointed to serve as the school climate coordinator, as described in section 10-222dd. Each such school climate coordinator shall successfully complete such mental health first aid training.”
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>