<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-450a"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-450a"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-450a"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-450a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-450a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-450a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-450a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_450a">
          <num>17a-450a</num>
          <heading>Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services. Successor to the Department of Mental Health and to the addiction services component of the former Department of Public Health and Addiction Services</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_450a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services shall constitute a successor department to the Department of Mental Health. Whenever the words “Commissioner of Mental Health” are used or referred to in the following general statutes, the words “Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services” shall be substituted in lieu thereof and whenever the words “Department of Mental Health” are used or referred to in the following general statutes, the words “Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services” shall be substituted in lieu thereof:4-5,4-38c,4-77a,4a-12,4a-16,5-142,8-206d,10-19,10-71,10-76d,17a-14,17a-26,17a-31,17a-33,17a-218,17a-246,17a-450,17a-451,17a-453,17a-454,17a-455,17a-456,17a-457,17a-458,17a-459,17a-464,17a-465,17a-466,17a-467,17a-468,17a-470,17a-471,17a-472,17a-473,17a-474,17a-476,17a-478,17a-479,17a-480,17a-481,17a-482,17a-483,17a-498,17a-499,17a-502,17a-506,17a-510,17a-511,17a-512,17a-513,17a-519,17a-528,17a-560,17a-561,17a-562,17a-565,17a-581,17a-582,17a-675,17-836a,17b-28,17b-59a,17b-222,17b-223,17b-225,17b-359,17b-694,19a-82,19a-495,19a-498,19a-507a,19a-576,19a-583,20-14i,20-14j,21a-240,21a-301,27-122a,31-222,38a-514,51-51o,52-146hand54-56d.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_450a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services shall constitute a successor department to the addiction services component of the Department of Public Health and Addiction Services. Whenever the words “Commissioner of Public Health and Addiction Services” are used or referred to in the following general statutes, the words “Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services” shall be substituted in lieu thereof and whenever the words “Department of Public Health and Addiction Services” are used or referred to in the following general statutes, the words “Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services” shall be substituted in lieu thereof:4a-12,17a-670to17a-676, inclusive,17a-678to17a-682, inclusive,17a-684to17a-687, inclusive,17a-691,17a-694,17a-710,17a-712,17a-713,19a-89c,20-74o,20-74p,20-74q,21a-274a,54-36iand54-56g.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_450a__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any order or regulation of the Department of Mental Health or the addiction services component of the Department of Public Health and Addiction Services that is in force on July 1, 1995, shall continue in force and effect as an order or regulation of the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services until amended, repealed or superseded pursuant to law. Where any order or regulation of the departments conflict, the Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services may implement policies and procedures consistent with the provisions of public act 95-257* while in the process of adopting the policy or procedure in regulation form, provided notice of intention to adopt the regulations is printed in the Connecticut Law Journal within twenty days of implementation. The policy or procedure shall be valid until the time final regulations are effective.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>