<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-278n"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-278n"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-278n"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-278n/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-278n/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-278n/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-278n/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319v">
        <num>319v</num>
        <heading>Temporary Assistance for Needy Families</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_278n">
          <num>17b-278n</num>
          <heading>Medicaid coverage of rapid whole genome sequencing for critically ill infants. Data use restrictions. Medical necessity criteria</heading>
          <subsection eId="17b_278n__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section,</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_278n__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“rapid whole genome sequencing” means a test designed to diagnose genetic disorders in time to inform or change acute medical or surgical management of a critically ill infant, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_278n__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“infant” means a child from birth to age twelve months. The Commissioner of Social Services shall, within available appropriations, provide medically necessary Medicaid coverage for rapid whole genome sequencing of a critically ill infant enrolled in the Medicaid program who is being treated in a neonatal intensive care or pediatric intensive care unit.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_278n__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall require that any health care provider receiving reimbursement for such test certify, in writing, that any genetic data resulting from such test is</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_278n__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>used only to assist in diagnosing and treating the infant,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_278n__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>protected in accordance with the federal Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, P.L. 104-191, as amended from time to time, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_278n__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>not used in scientific research unless a parent or legal guardian of the infant expressly consents to such use.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_278n__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall take actions necessary to implement the provisions of this section, including, but not limited to,</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_278n__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>promulgating regulations in accordance with chapter 54 to provide payment for such rapid whole genome sequencing, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_278n__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>submitting to the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services any new waiver application, amendment to an existing waiver or Medicaid state plan amendment necessary to ensure federal financial participation for Medicaid coverage of such rapid whole genome sequencing.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_278n__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In developing regulations pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_278n__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, the commissioner shall establish evidence-based medical necessity criteria for such rapid whole genome sequencing coverage that shall include, but need not be limited to:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_278n__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The infant has symptoms that suggest a broad differential diagnosis that would require an evaluation by multiple genetic tests if rapid whole genome sequencing is not performed,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_278n__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the infant's treating health care provider has provided a written determination that rapid whole genome sequencing is necessary to guide clinical decision making, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_278n__subsec_c__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the infant has complex or acute illness of unknown etiology, which may include (A) congenital anomalies involving at least two organ systems or complex or multiple congenital anomalies in one organ system, (B) specific organ malformations highly suggestive of a genetic etiology, or (C) abnormal laboratory tests or abnormal chemistry profiles suggesting the presence of a genetic disease.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_278n__subsec_c__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>congenital anomalies involving at least two organ systems or complex or multiple congenital anomalies in one organ system,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_278n__subsec_c__subsec_3__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>specific organ malformations highly suggestive of a genetic etiology, or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_278n__subsec_c__subsec_3__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>abnormal laboratory tests or abnormal chemistry profiles suggesting the presence of a genetic disease.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>