<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-265d"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-265d"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-265d"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-265d/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-265d/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-265d/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-265d/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319v">
        <num>319v</num>
        <heading>Temporary Assistance for Needy Families</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_265d">
          <num>17b-265d</num>
          <heading>Definition of full benefit dually eligible Medicare Part D beneficiary. Prescription drug coverage under Medicare Part D. Copayment coverage. Enrollment in benchmark plan. Commissioner's enrollment authority</heading>
          <subsection eId="17b_265d__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, “full benefit dually eligible Medicare Part D beneficiary” means a person who has coverage for Medicare Part D drugs and is eligible for full medical assistance benefits pursuant to section17b-261, under any category of eligibility.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_265d__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On and after the effective date of the Medicare Part D program established pursuant to Public Law 108-173, the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, no Medicaid prescription drug coverage shall be provided to a Medicaid recipient eligible for Medicare Part D for Medicare Part D drugs, as defined in said act. Medicaid coverage shall be provided to a full benefit dually eligible Medicare Part D beneficiary for prescription drugs that are not Medicare Part D drugs, as defined in said act.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_265d__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A full benefit dually eligible Medicare Part D beneficiary shall be responsible for any Medicare Part D prescription drug copayments imposed pursuant to Public Law 108-173, the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 in an amount not to exceed seventeen dollars per month in the aggregate. The Department of Social Services shall be responsible for payment, on behalf of such beneficiary, of any portion of such Medicare Part D prescription drug copayment which exceeds seventeen dollars in the aggregate in any month.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_265d__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each full benefit dually eligible Medicare Part D beneficiary shall enroll in a Medicare Part D benchmark plan. To the extent permitted under federal law, the Commissioner of Social Services may be the authorized representative of a full benefit dually eligible Medicare Part D beneficiary for the purpose of enrolling the beneficiary in a Medicare Part D benchmark plan.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>