<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-225"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-225"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-225"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-225/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-225/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-225/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-225/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319v">
        <num>319v</num>
        <heading>Temporary Assistance for Needy Families</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_225">
          <num>17b-225</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-295c). Availability of patient information to certain agencies</heading>
          <subsection eId="17b_225__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Emergency Services and Public Protection, the Department of Social Services and the United States Department of Health and Human Services shall be entitled to receive only such information concerning patients in institutions, hospitals and facilities of the Departments of Public Health, Developmental Services and Mental Health and Addiction Services as is required to obtain support and payments for the care of such patients, including submissions of such information to probate courts, agencies and corporations dispensing benefits, or only such information concerning such patients as is required for the purpose of claiming federal reimbursement, or only such information concerning such patients as is required for the review and audit of federally funded programs. Any such information received by said Department of Emergency Services and Public Protection, Department of Social Services and United States Department of Health and Human Services shall be confidential and shall be used for the purposes of obtaining support and payments for the care of said patients or for the purpose of claiming federal reimbursement or for the review and audit of federally funded programs.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_225__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Administrative Services shall be entitled to receive only such information concerning patients in institutions, hospitals and facilities of the Departments of Public Health, Mental Health and Addiction Services and Developmental Services, and state humane institutions, as defined in section17b-222, as is required to obtain support and payments for the care of such patients, including submissions of such information to probate courts, agencies and corporations dispensing benefits. Any such information received by said Department of Administrative Services shall be confidential and shall be used only for the purposes specified in this subsection.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>