<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-277d"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-277d"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-277d"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-277d/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-277d/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-277d/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-277d/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319v">
        <num>319v</num>
        <heading>Temporary Assistance for Needy Families</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_277d">
          <num>17b-277d</num>
          <heading>Medicaid payment for maternity services. Regulations</heading>
          <subsection eId="17b_277d__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To the extent permissible under federal law and within available appropriations, as the single state Medicaid agency designated under sections17b-2and17b-260, the Commissioner of Social Services may implement a bundled payment for maternity services and associated alternative payment methodology for maternity services that the commissioner determines are designed to improve health quality, equity, member experience, cost containment and coordination of care. Such bundled payment may include payment to physicians and other qualified licensed practitioners for the services of doulas and other nonlicensed practitioners. Such bundled payment shall be designed to reduce unnecessary utilization and avoidable costs, ensure access to necessary services, improve outcomes and improve coordination of care. In designing such bundled payment, and prior to implementation, the commissioner shall first consult with health care providers, advocates for consumers of health care and other stakeholders as set forth in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_277d__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_277d__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Consultation shall begin on or after July 1, 2023, and shall include solicitation of input and advice from health care providers, advocates for consumers of health care and other stakeholders covering at least the following topics:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_277d__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The quality measures used to assess the performance of participating practices;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_277d__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>reimbursement and financing methods and amounts; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_277d__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>safeguards designed to ensure access and network adequacy. Consultation shall include at least two live, online meeting opportunities for public input noticed at least ten days in advance on the department's Internet web site.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_277d__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall adopt regulations in accordance with the provisions of chapter 54 to implement the provisions of this section. The commissioner may implement policies and procedures while in the process of adopting such regulations, provided the commissioner publishes notice of intent to adopt regulations on the eRegulations System not later than twenty days after the date of implementation of such policies and procedures. Any policies and procedures implemented pursuant to this section shall be valid until the time final regulations are adopted.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>