<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-239c"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-239c"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-239c"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-239c/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-239c/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-239c/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-239c/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319v">
        <num>319v</num>
        <heading>Temporary Assistance for Needy Families</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_239c">
          <num>17b-239c</num>
          <heading>Interim disproportionate share payments to short-term general hospitals</heading>
          <subsection eId="17b_239c__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any provision of the general statutes, on and after July 1, 2011, the Department of Social Services may, within available appropriations, make interim quarterly medical assistance disproportionate share payments to short-term general hospitals. The total amount of interim payments made to such hospitals individually and in the aggregate shall maximize federal matching payments under the medical assistance program as determined by the Department of Social Services, in consultation with the Office of Policy and Management. No payments shall be made under this section to</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_239c__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>any hospital which, on July 1, 2011, is within the class of hospitals licensed by the Department of Public Health as a children's general hospital, or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_239c__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a short-term acute hospital operated exclusively by the state other than a short-term acute hospital operated by the state as a receiver pursuant to chapter 920. The quarterly interim payment amount for each hospital shall be determined by the Commissioner of Social Services based upon the information submitted by the hospital pursuant to Section 1001</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_239c__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of Public Law 108-173, the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_239c__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Effective July 1, 2011, interim payments made to hospitals pursuant to this section for the succeeding twenty-seven months shall be based on 2009 federal fiscal year data and may be adjusted at the commissioner's discretion for accuracy. Effective October 1, 2013, interim payments shall be based on the most recent independent, certified disproportionate share hospital audit of federal fiscal year data. For federal fiscal year 2011 and succeeding federal fiscal years, final disproportionate share payment amounts shall be recalculated and reallocated in accordance with Section 1001</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_239c__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of Public Law 108-173, the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003. The commissioner shall prescribe uniform annual hospital data reporting forms. Payments made pursuant to this section shall be in addition to inpatient hospital rates determined pursuant to section17b-239. The commissioner may withhold payment to a hospital to offset money owed by the hospital to the state.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>