<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-285"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-285"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-285"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-285/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-285/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-285/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-285/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319v">
        <num>319v</num>
        <heading>Temporary Assistance for Needy Families</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_285">
          <num>17b-285</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-134gg). Assignment of spousal support of an institutionalized person or person in need of institutional care</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 17b-285. (Formerly Sec. 17-134gg). Assignment of spousal support of an institutionalized person or person in need of institutional care.Notwithstanding any provision of the general statutes, an institutionalized person or person in need of institutional care who applies for Medicaid may assign to the Commissioner of Social Services the right of support derived from the assets of the community spouse of such person but only if (1) the assets of the institutionalized person or person in need of institutional care do not exceed the Medicaid program asset limit; and (2) the institutionalized person or person in need of institutional care cannot locate the community spouse; or the community spouse is unable to provide information regarding his or her own assets. If such assignment is made or if the institutionalized person or person in need of institutional care lacks the ability to execute such an assignment due to physical or mental impairment, the commissioner may seek recovery of any medical assistance paid on behalf of the institutionalized person or person in need of institutional care up to the amount of the community spouse's assets that are in excess of the community spouse protected amount as of the initial month of Medicaid eligibility.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>