<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-282a"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-282a"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-282a"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-282a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-282a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-282a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-282a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319v">
        <num>319v</num>
        <heading>Temporary Assistance for Needy Families</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_282a">
          <num>17b-282a</num>
          <heading>Coverage for in-patient dental services in certain instances involving children and developmentally disabled persons</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 17b-282a. Coverage for in-patient dental services in certain instances involving children and developmentally disabled persons.The Commissioner of Social Services, to the extent permitted by federal law, shall amend the Medicaid state plan to provide coverage for general anesthesia, nursing and related hospital services provided in conjunction with dental services, provided such anesthesia, nursing and related hospital services are provided in conjunction with in-patient dental services if the following conditions are met:
(1) The anesthesia, nursing and related hospital services are deemed medically necessary by the treating dentist or oral surgeon and the patient's primary care physician in accordance with the department's requirements for prior authorization of services, if required; and
(2) The patient is either (A) a child under the age of four who is determined by a licensed dentist, in conjunction with a licensed physician who specializes in primary care, to have a dental condition of significant dental complexity that it requires certain dental procedures to be performed in a hospital, or (B) a person who has a developmental disability, as determined by a licensed physician who specializes in primary care, that places the person at serious risk. The expense of such anesthesia, nursing and related hospital services shall be deemed a medical expense under such health insurance policy and shall not be subject to any limits on dental benefits under such policy.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>