<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-251"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-251"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-251"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-251/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-251/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-251/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-251/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_210">
        <num>210</num>
        <heading>Corporations: Miscellaneous Tax Provisions</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_251">
          <num>12-251</num>
          <heading>Basis. Rate. Deductions</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_251__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_251__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Such tax shall be based on the amount of gross earnings from all sources from operations in this state as determined by one-half of a railroad's revenues generated by its shipments from all origins in this state and to all destinations in this state or as follows: (A) In case of a corporation operating a railroad which is entirely within the limits of this state, the amount of gross earnings from all sources from operations; (B) in case of a corporation operating a railroad when only part of such railroad lies in this state, such portion of the amount of gross earnings from all sources from operations as is represented by the ratio of the number of miles of tracks, including yard tracks, sidings, branches and spurs, operated in this state during the year ended said thirty-first day of December, to the number of miles of such tracks, including yard tracks, sidings, branches and spurs, operated by it during such year.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_251__subsec_a__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In case of a corporation operating a railroad which is entirely within the limits of this state, the amount of gross earnings from all sources from operations;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_251__subsec_a__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>in case of a corporation operating a railroad when only part of such railroad lies in this state, such portion of the amount of gross earnings from all sources from operations as is represented by the ratio of the number of miles of tracks, including yard tracks, sidings, branches and spurs, operated in this state during the year ended said thirty-first day of December, to the number of miles of such tracks, including yard tracks, sidings, branches and spurs, operated by it during such year.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_251__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The net railway operating income for the purpose of computing the rate of tax shall constitute: (A) In the case of a corporation operating a railroad which is entirely within the limits of this state, the entire net railway operating income; (B) in the case of a corporation operating a railroad, only a part of which railroad is in this state, such portion of the net railway operating income as is represented by the ratio of the number of miles of tracks, including yard tracks, sidings, branches and spurs, operated in this state during the year ended said December thirty-first, to the number of miles of such tracks, including yard tracks, sidings, branches and spurs, operated by it during such year.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_251__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In the case of a corporation operating a railroad which is entirely within the limits of this state, the entire net railway operating income;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_251__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>in the case of a corporation operating a railroad, only a part of which railroad is in this state, such portion of the net railway operating income as is represented by the ratio of the number of miles of tracks, including yard tracks, sidings, branches and spurs, operated in this state during the year ended said December thirty-first, to the number of miles of such tracks, including yard tracks, sidings, branches and spurs, operated by it during such year.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_251__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The rate of tax on gross earnings of railroads shall be fixed as follows:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_251__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When there is no net railway operating income, or the net railway operating income does not exceed eight per cent of the gross earnings, two per cent of the gross earnings;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_251__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>when the net railway operating income exceeds eight per cent of the gross earnings, but does not exceed ten per cent, two and one quarter per cent;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_251__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>when the net railway operating income exceeds ten per cent of the gross earnings, but does not exceed twelve per cent, two and one-half per cent;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_251__subsec_b__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>when the net railway operating income exceeds twelve per cent of the gross earnings, but does not exceed fourteen per cent, two and three-quarters per cent;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_251__subsec_b__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>when the net railway operating income exceeds fourteen per cent of the gross earnings, but does not exceed sixteen per cent, three per cent;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_251__subsec_b__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>when the net railway operating income exceeds sixteen per cent of the gross earnings, but does not exceed eighteen per cent, three and one-quarter per cent;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_251__subsec_b__subsec_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>when the net railway operating income exceeds eighteen per cent of the gross earnings, three and one-half per cent, provided with respect to the tax under subdivisions</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_251__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>to</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_251__subsec_b__subsec_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>, inclusive, when there has been filed with the Governor by the Commissioner of Transportation the annual certificate of eligibility for exemption required by section13b-232with respect to the year ended said thirty-first day of December, there shall be no tax on gross earnings but a fee of twenty dollars shall be paid to the Commissioner of Revenue Services with the statement required by section12-250. The amount of taxes paid during the year ended said thirty-first day of December, in any town in this state, on the real estate not used exclusively in the business of such corporation, or of any corporation all of whose property is operated by such corporation, shall be deducted from the amount of the tax upon such gross earnings.
See Secs. 13b-226 to 13b-233, inclusive, re standards of service required to maintain exemption.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>