<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-94a"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-94a"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-94a"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-94a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-94a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-94a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-94a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_94a">
          <num>12-94a</num>
          <heading>State reimbursement in lieu of tax revenue from totally disabled persons</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-94a. State reimbursement in lieu of tax revenue from totally disabled persons.On or before July first, annually, the assessor of each municipality shall certify to the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management, on a form furnished by said secretary, the amount of tax revenue which such municipality, except for the provisions of subdivision (55) of section12-81, would have received, together with such supporting information as said secretary may require, except that for the assessment year commencing October 1, 2003, such certification shall be made to the secretary on or before August 1, 2004. Any municipality which neglects to transmit to said secretary such claim and supporting documentation as required by this section shall forfeit two hundred fifty dollars to the state, provided said secretary may waive such forfeiture in accordance with procedures and standards adopted by regulation in accordance with chapter 54. Said secretary shall review each such claim as provided in section12-120b. Any claimant aggrieved by the results of the secretary's review shall have the rights of appeal as set forth in section12-120b. The secretary shall, on or before December fifteenth, annually, certify to the Comptroller the amount due each municipality under the provisions of this section, including any modification of such claim made prior to December fifteenth, and the Comptroller shall draw an order on the Treasurer on the fifth business day following and the Treasurer shall pay the amount thereof to such municipality on or before the thirty-first day of December following. If any modification is made as the result of the provisions of this section on or after the December fifteenth following the date on which the assessor has provided the amount of tax revenue in question, any adjustments to the amount due to any municipality for the period for which such modification was made shall be made in the next payment the Treasurer shall make to such municipality pursuant to this section. For the purposes of this section, “municipality” means a town, city, borough, consolidated town and city or consolidated town and borough. The provisions of this section shall not apply to the assessment year commencing on October 1, 2002. In the fiscal year commencing July 1, 2004, and in each fiscal year thereafter, the amount of the grant payable to each municipality in accordance with this section shall be reduced proportionately in the event that the total amount of the grants payable to all municipalities exceeds the amount appropriated.
See Sec. 12-81i re additional exemption for totally disabled persons.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>