<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-40a"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-40a"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-40a"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-40a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-40a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-40a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-40a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_40a">
          <num>12-40a</num>
          <heading>Committee for training, examination and certification of assessment personnel. Fees. Certification by Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_40a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>There shall be a committee for the purpose of establishing a program and procedures for the training, examination and certification of assessment personnel, appointed by the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management and consisting of seven members, six of whom shall serve without pay and shall be appointed initially as follows: Two members for two-year terms; two members for four-year terms; and two members for six-year terms. No less than one member shall be from a municipality with a population over fifty thousand, and no less than one member shall be from a municipality with a population under five thousand. The seventh member shall be an employee of the Office of Policy and Management, who shall have demonstrated competence in Connecticut assessment practices. The Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management shall thereafter appoint two members every two years for six-year terms. Each member of the committee, other than the representative from the Office of Policy and Management, shall, on and after July 1, 1984, be a person certified pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_40a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section and shall have demonstrated competence in Connecticut assessment practices. Each member of the committee, other than the representative from the Office of Policy and Management, appointed on or after July 1, 1984, shall be employed by a municipality in the state in a position relating to the assessment of property for the purposes of the property tax. Any member of the committee who ceases to be an employee of the Office of Policy and Management, or to be certified pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_40a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, as the case may be, shall cease to be a member of the committee and the secretary shall appoint a replacement to fill the remainder of the term. Said committee shall</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_40a__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>elect its own chairman,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_40a__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>adopt regulations, in accordance with the provisions of chapter 54, for the training, fees and examination of assessment personnel, including, but not limited to, standards for the certification and recertification of assessors, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_40a__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>on or after May 27, 2022, amend such regulations to ensure that such training and examination is readily available online or at various locations throughout this state. Such regulations may include requirements for any type of training or experience, or combination thereof, the committee deems appropriate.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_40a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <heading>Any person may participate in training on assessment practices prescribed by said committee</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Upon completion of the requirements provided for in regulations adopted under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_40a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section and successful completion of any examination prescribed by said committee, any person shall be recommended to the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management as a candidate for certification as a certified Connecticut municipal assessor. The Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management shall certify any qualified candidate recommended by said committee as a certified Connecticut municipal assessor and may rescind such certification for sufficient cause as said secretary may determine. Such certification shall be valid for five years from the date of issuance. Said secretary may certify a candidate who has not completed such training provided such candidate has experience in Connecticut assessment practices to such extent, determined by said secretary, as to make it unnecessary to complete such training; provided, such candidate shall be required to successfully complete any examination prescribed by said committee.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>