<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-100"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-100"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-100"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_100">
          <num>12-100</num>
          <heading>Material cut for domestic use exempted from yield tax</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-100. Material cut for domestic use exempted from yield tax.All products of cuttings on classified land shall be taxed with a yield tax as provided in sections12-97and12-98, except material cut for domestic use, which shall be limited to fuel and the construction of fences, buildings or other improvements which tend to develop the property of the owner and increase its taxable value, when such material is used by the owner of such land, or by a tenant with the permission of such owner, upon property belonging to such owner which is taxable in the same town as the timber land from which such material was removed. If such material is sold or otherwise disposed of or transferred to the ownership of other persons, it shall be subject to a yield tax as provided in sections12-97and12-98. Whenever a cutting is made, other than as excepted above, the owner of the land shall file a sworn statement with the assessors and the State Forester of the quantity and stumpage value of all timber cut, before any of it is removed from the land. If the assessors deem the quantity or value to be incorrectly stated, they may themselves determine the quantity cut and stumpage value of the same. If the owner is unwilling to accept their valuation, the matter shall be referred to a special board consisting of the first selectman of the town in which the land is located and the State Forester, and the decision of said board with regard to quantity and value shall be final. Upon the valuation thus determined, a yield tax as provided in sections12-97and12-98shall be paid by the owner of the land. If it is necessary to remove any products of a cutting before the operation is completed, the owner of the land shall deposit with the tax collector a sufficient sum to cover the estimated yield tax. When the cutting is completed, such tax shall be levied as herein provided and the balance of such deposit, if any, returned. If the products of a cutting have been unlawfully removed, the owner of the land and the owner of the timber shall be jointly liable to the town for the full value of both land and timber.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>