<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-66c"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-66c"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-66c"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-66c/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-66c/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-66c/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-66c/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_66c">
          <num>12-66c</num>
          <heading>Taxation of residential real property intended for student learning</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-66c. Taxation of residential real property intended for student learning.Notwithstanding any provision of this chapter or chapter 201 or 204 or any special act, except subdivision (8) of section12-81, which provides an exemption from taxation of real or personal property held by or on behalf of a private nonprofit institution of higher learning, as defined in section12-20a, any residential real property intended for use or used as student housing, except a dormitory, that is held by or on behalf of such entity, shall be taxable by a municipality in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and chapters 201 and 204. For purposes of this subsection: (1) “Residential real property” means any house or building, or portion thereof, which is rented, leased or hired out to be occupied as a home or residence of one or more students, and (2) “dormitory” means a building containing living or sleeping facilities consisting of twenty or more beds intended for use or used as student housing and maintained by a private nonprofit institution of higher learning, as defined in section12-20a.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>