<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-93"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-93"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-93"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-93/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-93/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-93/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-93/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_93">
          <num>12-93</num>
          <heading>Veterans' exemptions; proof of claim</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-93. Veterans' exemptions; proof of claim.Any person who claims an exemption from taxation under the provisions of section12-81or12-82by reason of service in the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Coast Guard, Air Force or Space Force of the United States shall give notice to the town clerk of the town in which he resides that he is entitled to such exemption. Any person who has performed such service may establish his right to such exemption by exhibiting to the town clerk an honorable discharge, or a certified copy thereof, from such service or, in the absence of such discharge or copy, by appearing before the assessors for an examination under oath, supported by two affidavits of disinterested persons, showing that the claimant is a veteran, as defined in section27-103, or is serving or, if he is unable to appear by reason of such service, he may establish such right, until such time as he appears personally and exhibits his discharge or copy, by forwarding to the town clerk annually a written statement, signed by the commanding officer of his unit, ship or station or by some other appropriate officer, or where such claimant is currently serving in an active theater of war or hostilities, by the presentation of a notarized statement of a parent, guardian, spouse or legal representative of such claimant, stating that he is personally serving and is unable to appear in person by reason of such service, which statement shall be received before the assessment day of the town wherein the exemption is claimed. The assessors shall report to the town clerk all claims so established. Any person claiming exemption by reason of the service of a relative as a soldier, sailor, marine or member of the Coast Guard, Air Force or Space Force may establish his right thereto by at least two affidavits of disinterested persons showing the service of such relative, his honorable discharge or death in service, and the relationship of the claimant to him; and the assessors may further require such person to be examined by them under oath concerning such facts. The town clerk of the town where the honorable discharge or certified copy thereof and each affidavit is originally presented for record shall record such discharge or certified copy or affidavits thereof in full and shall list the names of such claimants and such service shall be performed by the town clerk without remuneration therefor. Thereafter if any person entitled to such exemption changes his legal residence, the town clerk in the town of former residence and in which such honorable discharge or certified copy thereof or any such affidavit in respect to such person was originally presented for record shall, upon request and payment of a fee by such person to said town of former residence in an amount determined by the town treasurer as necessary to cover the cost of such procedure, prepare and mail to the town in which such person resides, a copy of the record of such discharge or certified copy thereof or affidavits, or he may establish his right to such exemption in the town in which he resides by exhibiting to the town clerk thereof the original discharge or a certified copy thereof or such affidavits. Said clerk shall take therefrom sufficient data to satisfy the exemption requirements of the general statutes and shall record the same and shall note the town where the original complete recording of discharge papers was made. No board of assessors or board of assessment appeals or other official shall allow any such claim for exemption unless evidence as herein specified has been filed in the office of the town clerk, provided, if any claim for exemption has been allowed by any board of assessors or board of assessment appeals prior to July 1, 1923, the provisions of this section shall not apply to such claim. Each claim granted prior to July 1, 1923, shall be recorded with those presented subsequent thereto, and a list of such names, alphabetically arranged, shall be furnished the assessors by the town clerk.
See Sec. 12-127 re abatement or refund of taxes upon proof of exempt status.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>