<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-65d"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-65d"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-65d"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-65d/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-65d/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-65d/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-65d/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_65d">
          <num>12-65d</num>
          <heading>Designation of rehabilitation area. Criteria for deferral of assessment increase</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_65d__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The legislative body of any municipality may, in accordance with the provisions of sections12-65cto12-65f, inclusive, adopt a resolution designating such municipality, or any part thereof, as a rehabilitation area and establishing criteria for eligibility of real property within the area so designated for deferral, as provided in section12-65e, of any increased assessment attributable to rehabilitation or new construction. Such criteria shall include the initial condition of the property, the extent and nature of improvements compatible with the plan of development of the municipality and subdivision and zoning regulations, if any, and in compliance with such state building and health codes and local housing code requirements, as may apply, and acceptable uses for such property. Such criteria shall be determined with the advice of the local building official and housing code enforcement officer or other authority designated by the municipality to enforce the provisions of sections19a-355,47a-14ato47a-14g, inclusive,47a-51,47a-53,47a-54,47a-54a,47a-55,47a-56,47a-56a,47a-56dto47a-56j, inclusive, and47a-57to47a-61, inclusive.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_65d__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No such resolution or criteria shall be adopted</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_65d__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>until after a public hearing, notice of the time, place and purpose of which shall be given by publication in a newspaper having a general circulation in the municipality at least twice, at intervals of not less than two days, the first not more than fifteen days nor less than ten days and the last not less than two days prior to the date of such hearing; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_65d__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>following such hearing, in any municipality having a planning commission or combined planning and zoning commission, such proposal has been referred to such commission for a report in accordance with the provisions of section8-24, and in the event such commission disapproves the proposal, the vote on adoption by the municipality shall be in accordance with the provisions of said section8-24.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_65d__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notice of the adoption of the resolution and criteria shall be published by the legislative body, in a newspaper having a general circulation in the municipality, not later than fifteen days after its adoption. A copy of such resolution and criteria shall be filed in the office of the town clerk of such municipality.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>