<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-64"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-64"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-64"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-64/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-64/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-64/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-64/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_64">
          <num>12-64</num>
          <heading>Real estate liable to taxation. Easements in air space. Separate assessment of the interest of a lessee. Conditions under which lessee of state-owned property is subject to tax</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_64__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All the following mentioned property, not exempted, shall be set in the list of the town where it is situated and, except as otherwise provided by law, shall be liable to taxation at a uniform percentage of its present true and actual valuation, not exceeding one hundred per cent of such valuation, to be determined by the assessors: Dwelling houses, garages, barns, sheds, stores, shops, mills, buildings used for business, commercial, financial, manufacturing, mercantile and trading purposes, ice houses, warehouses, silos, all other buildings and structures, house lots, all other building lots and improvements thereon and thereto, including improvements that are partially completed or under construction, agricultural lands, shellfish lands, all other lands and improvements thereon and thereto, quarries, mines, ore beds, fisheries, property in fish pounds, machinery and easements to use air space whether or not contiguous to the surface of the ground. An easement to use air space shall be an interest in real estate and may be assessed separately from the surface of the ground below it. Any interest in real estate shall be set by the assessors in the list of the person in whose name the title to such interest stands on the land records. If the interest in real estate consists of an easement to use air space, whether or not contiguous to the surface of the ground, which easement is in the form of a lease for a period of not less than fifty years, which lease is recorded in the land records of the town and provides that the lessee shall pay all taxes, said interest shall be deemed to be a separate parcel and shall be separately assessed in the name of the lessee. If the interest in real estate consists of a lease of land used for residential purposes which allows the lessee to remove any or all of the structures, buildings or other improvements on said land erected or owned by the lessee, which lease is recorded in the land records of the town and provides that the lesse</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_64__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as provided in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_64__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, any land, buildings or easement to use air rights belonging to or held in trust for the state, not used for purposes attributable to functions of the state government or any other governmental purpose but leased to a person or organization for use unrelated to any such purpose, exclusive of any such lease with respect to which a binding agreement is in effect on June 25, 1985, shall be separately assessed in the name of the lessee and subject to local taxation annually in the name of the lessee having immediate right to occupancy of such land or building, by the town wherein situated as of the assessment day next following the date of leasing pursuant to section4b-38. If such property or any portion thereof is leased to any organization which, if the property were owned by or held in trust for such organization, would not be liable for taxes with respect to such property under any of the subdivisions of section12-81, such organization shall be entitled to exemption from property taxes as the lessee under such lease, provided such property is used exclusively for the purposes of such organization as stated in the applicable subdivision of section12-81and the portion of such property so leased to such exempt organization shall be eligible for a grant in lieu of taxes pursuant to section12-18b. Whenever the lessee of such property is required to pay property taxes to the town in which such property is situated as provided in this subsection, the assessed valuation of such property subject to the interest of the lessee shall not be included in the annual list of assessed values of state-owned real property in such town as prepared for purposes of state grants in accordance with section12-18band the amount of grant to such town under section12-18bshall be determined without consideration of such assessed value.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_64__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_64__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section shall not be applicable to</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_64__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>any land, building or easement belonging to or held in trust for the state of Connecticut or the Connecticut Airport Authority at Bradley International Airport or any general aviation airport or other airport, as such terms are defined in section15-120aa, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_64__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>any restaurant, gasoline station or other service facility or public convenience as may be deemed appropriate by the Commissioner of Transportation for state highway, mass transit, marine or aviation purposes. In the event a lessee of property, belonging to or held in trust for the state or a constituent unit of the state system of higher education, who is subject to taxation pursuant to the provisions of this subsection or pursuant to subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_64__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section4b-38is delinquent in the payment of such tax, a municipal tax collector may enforce the collection of said tax by all legal means available, except for the filing of a lien on such property.
See Sec. 7-33 re lists of transfers of taxable property.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>