<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-63a"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-63a"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-63a"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-63a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-63a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-63a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-63a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_63a">
          <num>12-63a</num>
          <heading>Taxation of mobile manufactured homes and mobile manufactured home parks</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_63a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, unless the context otherwise requires: “Mobile manufactured home” means a detached residential unit having three-dimensional components which are intrinsically mobile with or without a wheel chassis or a detached residential unit built on or after June 15, 1976, in accordance with federal manufactured home construction and safety standards, and, in either case, containing sleeping accommodations, a flush toilet, tub or shower bath, kitchen facilities and plumbing and electrical connections for attachment to outside systems, and designed for long-term occupancy and to be placed on rigid supports at the site where it is to be occupied as a residence, complete and ready for occupancy, except for minor and incidental unpacking and assembly operations and connection to utilities systems. “Mobile manufactured home park” or “park” means a plot of ground upon which two or more mobile manufactured homes occupied for residential purposes are located.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_63a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In determining the value of a mobile manufactured home park for the purpose of real property taxation, assessors shall consider the cost of the original unimproved land and all improvements thereon, including, but not limited to, leveling, drainage, filling, paving of streets and walkways, lighting, installation of water, sewer and electrical systems, facilities for sanitation, laundering and recreation, erection of structures and landscaping.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_63a__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In determining the value of a mobile manufactured home for the purpose of property taxation, beginning with the assessment year commencing October 1, 1986, each assessor shall assess mobile manufactured homes connected to utilities and used as a residence in the same manner as residential real property, except that in the case of a mobile manufactured home located on leased land the sum of the assessed value of the mobile manufactured home and the assessed value of the land apportionable to the lot on which the mobile manufactured home sits shall not exceed the sum of the assessed value of the mobile manufactured home and the lot if the lot had been owned by the lessee. Any assessor who first assesses any such mobile manufactured home as residential real property on or after October 1, 1986, and which assessment would result in an increase in taxation for said assessment year of over twenty-five per cent shall phase in said increase in assessment over a five-year period, twenty per cent of the increased assessment being phased in on the list of October 1, 1986, and twenty per cent in each of the four assessment years next succeeding the list of October 1, 1986. The assessment for a mobile manufactured home shall be in the name of the owner of the mobile manufactured home and shall not alter in any way the assessment of the ground upon which the mobile manufactured home is situated, except that a mobile manufactured home situated upon land owned by the owner of the mobile manufactured home shall be assessed in the same manner as any dwelling house. In determining the value of a mobile manufactured home which is not used as a residence for the purpose of property taxation, assessors may consult authoritative handbooks listing current common prices of used mobile manufactured homes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_63a__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_63a__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of this section or of any other section of the general statutes or any special act to the contrary, a municipality may, by ordinance, elect to assess a mobile manufactured home, on or after October 1, 1986, but not later than the first sale of such mobile manufactured home, in the same manner in which mobile manufactured homes were assessed by such municipality for the assessment year commencing October 1, 1985. On the first assessment date immediately following the first sale of such mobile manufactured home after October 1, 1986, such mobile manufactured home shall be assessed and subject to property tax pursuant to subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_63a__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_63a__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>As used in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_63a__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, “first sale” means any sale or conveyance by an owner of any mobile manufactured home on or after October 1, 1986, except a sale or conveyance to (A) an owner's spouse; (B) an owner's brother or sister who actually resides in the mobile manufactured home unit being sold or conveyed; or (C) any other person if the owner makes such sale to such other person for the purpose of using the proceeds of such sale to purchase a substitute mobile manufactured home to be located on the leasehold site being occupied by such owner's existing mobile manufactured home. In the case of a sale as defined in subparagraph (C) of this subdivision, the owner's substitute mobile manufactured home subsequently located on the owner's leasehold site shall be assessed in the same manner as his original mobile manufactured home until a first sale. The original mobile manufactured home removed from the owner's leasehold site shall be assessed as provided in subsection</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_63a__subsec_c__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>an owner's spouse;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_63a__subsec_c__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>an owner's brother or sister who actually resides in the mobile manufactured home unit being sold or conveyed; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_63a__subsec_c__subsec_1__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>any other person if the owner makes such sale to such other person for the purpose of using the proceeds of such sale to purchase a substitute mobile manufactured home to be located on the leasehold site being occupied by such owner's existing mobile manufactured home. In the case of a sale as defined in subparagraph</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_63a__subsec_c__subsec_1__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of this subdivision, the owner's substitute mobile manufactured home subsequently located on the owner's leasehold site shall be assessed in the same manner as his original mobile manufactured home until a first sale. The original mobile manufactured home removed from the owner's leasehold site shall be assessed as provided in subsection</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_63a__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, unless the new owner of such original mobile manufactured home can independently qualify to be assessed as such homes were assessed in the assessment year commencing October 1, 1985, under subparagraph (C) of this subdivision. Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, a mobile manufactured home which is treated by a municipality as personal property in accordance with the provisions of this subsection shall continue to be treated as real property pursuant to sections12-412cand21-67a.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>