<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-80a"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-80a"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-80a"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-80a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-80a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-80a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-80a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_80a">
          <num>12-80a</num>
          <heading>Personal property used in rendering telecommunications service. Exceptions</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_80a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_80a__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>taxpayer which, prior to January 1, 1990, was subject to tax under chapter 211 with respect to the rendering of telecommunications service and which, on or after January 1, 1990, is subject to tax under chapter 219 for rendering telecommunications service, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_80a__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>other taxpayer that is subject to tax under chapter 219 for rendering telecommunications service and which has elected in the manner specified in this section to have personal property taxed as provided in this section, shall be required to submit to the Commissioner of Revenue Services and the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management, not later than the thirtieth day of November of each year during which it is subject to tax under chapter 219, a list of all personal property on a town-by-town basis that is owned by such taxpayer in this state on the first day of October of such year and that is used solely and exclusively for rendering telecommunications service, as defined in said chapter 219, including the location of each item of such property and the fair market value thereof, recognizing depreciation of such property to the maximum extent allowed for purposes of the corporation business tax in this state, as certified by the Commissioner of Revenue Services. Each such taxpayer shall also submit such list to each municipality in which such taxpayer owns property, provided the list submitted to a municipality shall contain only the personal property owned by such taxpayer that is located in, or allocated pursuant to this subsection to, such municipality. If the records of a taxpayer subject to the requirements of this subsection do not contain the data necessary to develop the list as required without undue cost, the taxpayer may, for purposes of requirements under this subsection, petition the Commissioner of Revenue Services for approval of an alternate method of determining the value of the plant used solely and exclusively to render telecommunications services, but not including central office or switching equipment of that taxpayer, located in each town in the state. If the commissioner finds that the alternative method proposed results in a reasonable approximation of the value of the property of the taxpayer located in each town and used solely an</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_80a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_80a__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Not later than the first day of February immediately following the end of such tax year, the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management shall determine, with respect to such company, a value for personal property equivalent to seventy per cent of the value of personal property included in the list of such property prepared and certified in accordance with subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_80a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section. The amount of tax applicable with respect to such personal property of any taxpayer subject to the tax imposed under this section shall be determined by multiplying the value of personal property of such company, as determined under this subsection, by a mill rate of forty-seven mills. Said secretary shall, not later than the first day of March immediately following the end of such tax year, submit a tax bill to each company stating the amount of tax payable to each town in relation to the personal property of such taxpayer located in such town. Such tax shall be due and payable to the town in which such personal property is located not later than the first day of April immediately following. Any city or borough not consolidated with the town in which it is located and any town containing such a city or borough shall receive a portion of the tax due and payable to such town on the basis of the following ratio: The total taxes levied in the previous fiscal year by such town, city or borough shall be the numerator of the fraction. The total taxes levied by the town and all cities or boroughs located within such town shall be added together, and the sum shall be the denominator of the fraction. Any such city or borough may, by vote of its legislative body, direct the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management to reallocate all or a portion of the share of such city or borough to the town in which it is located.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_80a__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The person responsible for the collection of taxes for each town, city or borough owed taxes under this subsection may, at such time as such tax becomes delinquent as provided in sections12-146and12-169, subject such tax to interest at the rate of one and one-half per cent of such tax for each month or fraction thereof which elapses from the time when such tax becomes due and payable until the same is paid.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_80a__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>With respect to tangible personal property included in the list of such property submitted to the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management as provided in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_80a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, any taxpayer subject to the tax imposed under this section for any tax year shall not be subject to property tax in any town applicable to such personal property for the assessment year in such town commencing on the first day of October immediately preceding the date on which the tax determined with respect to such property in accordance with this section becomes due and payable.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_80a__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any taxpayer that, on or after January 1, 1990, is subject to tax under chapter 219 for rendering telecommunications service but that, prior to January 1, 1990, was not subject to tax under chapter 211 for rendering telecommunications service may elect to have personal property taxed in the manner specified in this section. Such election shall be made in writing and filed with the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management and a copy thereof shall be filed with the assessor of each town in which personal property affected by such election is located. Except as provided in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_80a__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, such election, once filed with the secretary, shall be irrevocable and shall, if filed on or before the date that is two months prior to the start of the assessment year, be effective for such assessment year and for all succeeding assessment years, otherwise to be effective for the next succeeding assessment year and all succeeding assessment years.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_80a__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For assessment years commencing on or after October 1, 1997, the provisions of this section, including informational reporting requirements imposed on owners, shall also apply, to the extent provided in section12-80b, to property that is used both to render telecommunications service subject to tax under chapter 219 and to render community antenna television service subject to tax under chapter 219 and that is required, under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_80a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-80b, to be taxed as provided in this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_80a__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any municipality may examine the Office of Policy and Management's or the Department of Revenue Services' audit of a taxpayer's submission pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_80a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_80a__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_80a__subsec_g__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any election for taxation made under subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_80a__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section on or before August 1, 2009, by a taxpayer that provides mobile telecommunications service, as defined in section12-407a, is null and void. For the assessment year commencing October 1, 2010, and for each assessment year thereafter, such taxpayer shall not be subject to taxation for personal property under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_80a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, but shall be subject to personal property taxation as otherwise provided in this chapter, subject to the provisions of subdivisions</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_80a__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_80a__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection. No taxpayer that provides mobile telecommunications service shall be eligible to make an election as provided in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_80a__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section after August 1, 2009.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_80a__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The personal property of any taxpayer whose election for taxation becomes null and void pursuant to this subsection that, on or before the October 1, 2009, grand list, has not been depreciated to the maximum extent allowed for purposes of the corporation business tax in this state, shall be subject to taxation by the town in which it is located as of the assessment year beginning October 1, 2010, under the provisions of this chapter that are applicable to all other taxpayers.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_80a__subsec_d__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The personal property of any taxpayer whose election for taxation becomes null and void pursuant to this subsection that, on or before the October 1, 2009, grand list, has been depreciated to the maximum extent allowed for purposes of the corporation business tax in this state, shall be subject to taxation for assessment years commencing on and after October 1, 2010, as follows: (A) In the assessment year beginning October 1, 2010, such taxpayer shall file a declaration, as required by section12-41, in which twenty-five per cent of the total value of such taxpayer's fully depreciated personal property shall be reported for purposes of assessment; (B) in the assessment year beginning October 1, 2011, such taxpayer shall file a declaration as required by section12-41, in which fifty per cent of the total value of such taxpayer's fully depreciated personal property shall be reported for purposes of assessment; (C) in the assessment year beginning October 1, 2012, such taxpayer shall file a declaration as required by section12-41, in which seventy-five per cent of the total value of such taxpayer's fully depreciated personal property shall be reported for purposes of assessment; and (D) in the assessment year beginning October 1, 2013, and each assessment year thereafter, such taxpayer shall file a declaration as required by section12-41, in which one hundred per cent of the total value of such taxpayer's fully depreciated personal property shall be reported for purposes of assessment.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_80a__subsec_d__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In the assessment year beginning October 1, 2010, such taxpayer shall file a declaration, as required by section12-41, in which twenty-five per cent of the total value of such taxpayer's fully depreciated personal property shall be reported for purposes of assessment;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_80a__subsec_d__subsec_3__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>in the assessment year beginning October 1, 2011, such taxpayer shall file a declaration as required by section12-41, in which fifty per cent of the total value of such taxpayer's fully depreciated personal property shall be reported for purposes of assessment;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_80a__subsec_d__subsec_3__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>in the assessment year beginning October 1, 2012, such taxpayer shall file a declaration as required by section12-41, in which seventy-five per cent of the total value of such taxpayer's fully depreciated personal property shall be reported for purposes of assessment; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_80a__subsec_d__subsec_3__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>in the assessment year beginning October 1, 2013, and each assessment year thereafter, such taxpayer shall file a declaration as required by section12-41, in which one hundred per cent of the total value of such taxpayer's fully depreciated personal property shall be reported for purposes of assessment.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>