<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-120b"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-120b"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-120b"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-120b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-120b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-120b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-120b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_120b">
          <num>12-120b</num>
          <heading>Uniform administrative review procedures for certain state-reimbursed property tax exemptions and credits</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_120b__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Claimant” means a person, company, limited liability company, firm, association, corporation or other business entity having received approval for financial assistance from a town's assessor or a municipal official;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Financial assistance” means a property tax exemption, property tax credit or rental rebate for which the state of Connecticut provides direct or indirect reimbursement; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Program” means (A) property tax exemptions under section12-81gor subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_120b__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>property tax exemptions under section12-81gor subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_a__subsec_55">
              <num>(55)</num>
              <content>
                <p>,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_a__subsec_59">
              <num>(59)</num>
              <content>
                <p>,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_a__subsec_60">
              <num>(60)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_a__subsec_70">
              <num>(70)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of section12-81, (B) tax relief pursuant to section12-129dor12-170aa, and (C) grants under section12-170d.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_120b__subsec_a__subsec_70__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>tax relief pursuant to section12-129dor12-170aa, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_120b__subsec_a__subsec_70__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>grants under section12-170d.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_120b__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A claimant negatively affected by a decision of the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management with respect to any program may appeal such decision in the manner set forth in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_120b__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section. Any notice the secretary issues pursuant to this section shall be sent by first class United States mail to a claimant at the address entered on the application for financial assistance as filed unless, subsequent to the date of said filing, the claimant sends the secretary a written request that any correspondence regarding said financial assistance be sent to another name or address. The date of any notice sent by the secretary pursuant to this section shall be deemed to be the date the notice is delivered to the claimant.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_120b__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The secretary may review any application for financial assistance submitted by a claimant in conjunction with a program. The secretary may exclude from reimbursement any property included in an application that, in the secretary's judgment, does not qualify for financial assistance or may modify the amount of any financial assistance approved by an assessor or municipal official in the event the secretary finds it to be mathematically incorrect, not supported by the application, not in conformance with law or if the secretary believes that additional information is needed to justify its approval.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_120b__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the secretary modifies the amount of financial assistance approved by an assessor or municipal official under a program, or makes a preliminary determination that the claimant who filed written application for such financial assistance is ineligible therefor, the secretary shall send a written notice of preliminary modification or denial to said claimant and shall concurrently forward a copy to the office of the assessor or municipal official who approved said financial assistance. The notice shall include plain language setting forth the reason for the preliminary modification or denial, the name and telephone number of a member of the secretary's staff to whom questions regarding the notice may be addressed, a request for any additional information or documentation that the secretary believes is needed in order to justify the approval of such financial assistance, the manner by which the claimant may request reconsideration of the secretary's preliminary determination and the time frame for doing so. Not later than ninety days after the date an assessor receives a copy of such preliminary notice, the assessor shall determine whether an increase to the taxable grand list of the town is required to be made as a result of such modification or denial, unless, in the interim, the assessor has received written notification from the secretary that a request for a hearing with respect to such financial assistance has been approved pursuant to subparagraph (B) of subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_120b__subsec_d__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection. If an assessment increase is warranted, the assessor shall promptly issue a certificate of correction adding the value of such property to the taxable grand list for the appropriate assessment year and shall forward a copy thereof to the tax collector, who shall, not later than thirty days following, issue a bill for the amount of the additional tax due as a result of such increase. Such additional tax shall become due and payable not later than thirty days from the date such bill is sent and shall be subject to interest for delinquent taxes as provided in section12-146. With respect to the preliminary modification or denial of financial assistance for which a hearing is held, the assessor shall not issue a certificate of correction until the assessor receives written notice of the secretary's final determination following such hearing.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>(A) Any claimant aggrieved by the secretary's notice of preliminary modification or denial of financial assistance under a program may, not later than thirty business days after receiving said notice, request a reconsideration of the secretary's decision for any factual reason, provided the claimant states the reason for the reconsideration request in writing and concurrently provides any additional information or documentation that the secretary may have requested in the preliminary notice of modification or denial. The secretary may grant an extension of the date by which a claimant's additional information or documentation must be submitted, upon receipt of proof that the claimant has requested such data from another governmental agency or if the secretary determines there is good cause for doing so.
(B) Not later than thirty business days after receiving a claimant's request for reconsideration and any additional information or documentation the claimant has provided, the secretary shall reconsider the preliminary decision to modify or deny said financial assistance and shall send the claimant a written notice of the secretary's determination regarding such reconsideration. If aggrieved by the secretary's notice of determination with respect to the reconsideration of said financial assistance, the claimant may, not later than thirty business days after receiving said notice, make application for a hearing before said secretary, or the secretary's designee. Such application shall be in writing and shall set forth the reason why the financial assistance in question should not be modified or denied. Not later than thirty business days after receiving an application for a hearing, the secretary shall grant or deny such hearing request by written notice to the claimant. If the secretary denies the claimant's request for a hearing, such notice shall state the reason for said denial. If the secretary grants the claimant's request for a hearing, the secretary shall send</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_120b__subsec_d__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Any claimant aggrieved by the secretary's notice of preliminary modification or denial of financial assistance under a program may, not later than thirty business days after receiving said notice, request a reconsideration of the secretary's decision for any factual reason, provided the claimant states the reason for the reconsideration request in writing and concurrently provides any additional information or documentation that the secretary may have requested in the preliminary notice of modification or denial. The secretary may grant an extension of the date by which a claimant's additional information or documentation must be submitted, upon receipt of proof that the claimant has requested such data from another governmental agency or if the secretary determines there is good cause for doing so.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_120b__subsec_d__subsec_2__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Not later than thirty business days after receiving a claimant's request for reconsideration and any additional information or documentation the claimant has provided, the secretary shall reconsider the preliminary decision to modify or deny said financial assistance and shall send the claimant a written notice of the secretary's determination regarding such reconsideration. If aggrieved by the secretary's notice of determination with respect to the reconsideration of said financial assistance, the claimant may, not later than thirty business days after receiving said notice, make application for a hearing before said secretary, or the secretary's designee. Such application shall be in writing and shall set forth the reason why the financial assistance in question should not be modified or denied. Not later than thirty business days after receiving an application for a hearing, the secretary shall grant or deny such hearing request by written notice to the claimant. If the secretary de</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_d__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If any claimant is aggrieved by the secretary's determination concerning the hearing regarding the claimant's financial assistance or the secretary's decision not to hold a hearing, such claimant may, not later than thirty business days after receiving the secretary's notice related thereto, appeal to the superior court of the judicial district in which the claimant resides or in which the claimant's property that is the subject of the appeal is located. Such appeal shall be accompanied by a citation to the secretary to appear before said court, and shall be served and returned in the same manner as is required in the case of a summons in a civil action. The pendency of such appeal shall not suspend any action by a municipality to collect property taxes from the applicant on the property that is the subject of the appeal. The authority issuing the citation shall take from the applicant a bond or recognizance to the state of Connecticut, with surety, to prosecute the application in effect and to comply with the orders and decrees of the court in the premises. Such applications shall be preferred cases, to be heard, unless cause appears to the contrary, at the first session, by the court or by a committee appointed by the court. Said court may grant such relief as may be equitable and, if the application is without probable cause, may tax double or triple costs, as the case demands; and, upon all applications which are denied, costs may be taxed against the applicant at the discretion of the court, but no costs shall be taxed against the state.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_d__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The secretary shall notify each claimant of the final modification or denial of financial assistance as claimed, in accordance with the procedure set forth in this subsection. A copy of the notice of final modification or denial shall be sent concurrently to the assessor or municipal official who approved such financial assistance. With respect to property tax exemptions under section12-81gor subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_d__subsec_55">
              <num>(55)</num>
              <content>
                <p>,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_d__subsec_59">
              <num>(59)</num>
              <content>
                <p>,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_d__subsec_60">
              <num>(60)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_120b__subsec_d__subsec_70">
              <num>(70)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of section12-81, and tax relief pursuant to section12-129dor12-170aa, the notice pursuant to this subdivision shall be sent not later than one year after the date claims for financial assistance for each such program are filed with the secretary. For grants under section12-170d, such notice shall be sent not later than the date by which the secretary certifies the amounts of payment to the Comptroller.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>