<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-107e"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-107e"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-107e"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-107e/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-107e/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-107e/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-107e/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_107e">
          <num>12-107e</num>
          <heading>Classification of land as open space land</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_107e__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The planning commission of any municipality, in preparing a plan of conservation and development for such municipality, may designate upon such plan areas which it recommends for preservation as areas of open space land, provided such designation is approved by a majority vote of the legislative body of such municipality. Land, or a portion thereof, including any terrestrial recreational trail corridor that meets the criteria for designation as a greenway pursuant to chapter 454, included in any area so designated upon such plan as finally adopted may be classified as open space land for purposes of property taxation or payments in lieu thereof if there has been no change in the use of such area which has adversely affected its essential character as an area of open space land between the date of the adoption of such plan and the date of such classification.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_107e__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An owner of land included in any area designated as open space land upon any plan as finally adopted may apply for its classification as open space land on any grand list of a municipality by filing a written application for such classification with the assessor thereof not earlier than thirty days before or later than thirty days after the assessment date, provided in a year in which a revaluation of all real property in accordance with section12-62becomes effective such application may be filed not later than ninety days after such assessment date. The assessor shall determine whether there has been any change in the area designated as an area of open space land upon the plan of development which adversely affects its essential character as an area of open space land and, if the assessor determines that there has been no such change, said assessor shall classify such land as open space land and include it as such on the grand list. An application for classification of land as open space land shall be made upon a form prescribed by the Commissioner of Agriculture and shall set forth a description of the land, a general description of the use to which it is being put, a statement of the potential liability for tax under the provisions of section12-504ato12-504f, inclusive, and such other information as the assessor may require to aid in determining whether such land qualifies for such classification. Any advisory opinion issued by the Commissioner of Agriculture pursuant to section22-4c, stating that such land constitutes open space land, shall be prima facie evidence that such land is classified as open space land for purposes of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_107e__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Failure to file an application for classification of land as open space land within the time limit prescribed in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_107e__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section and in the manner and form prescribed in said subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_107e__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>shall be considered a waiver of the right to such classification on such assessment list.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_107e__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person aggrieved by the denial by an assessor of any application for the classification of land as open space land shall have the same rights and remedies for appeal and relief as are provided in the general statutes for taxpayers claiming to be aggrieved by the doings of assessors or boards of assessment appeals.
See Sec. 12-63 re rule of valuation.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>