<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-428"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-428"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-428"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-428/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-428/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-428/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-428/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_219">
        <num>219</num>
        <heading>Motor Vehicle Fuels Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_428">
          <num>12-428</num>
          <heading>Wilful violations and corresponding penalties</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-428. Wilful violations and corresponding penalties.(1)Wilful failure to file return.Any person required under this chapter to pay any tax, or required under this chapter or by regulations thereunder to make a return, keep any record or supply any information, who wilfully fails to pay such tax, make such return, keep such records or supply such information, at the time required by law, shall, in addition to any other penalty provided by law, be fined not more than one thousand dollars or imprisoned not more than one year or both. Notwithstanding the provisions of section54-193, no person shall be prosecuted for a violation of the provisions of this subsection committed on or after July 1, 1997, except within three years next after such violation has been committed. As used in this section, “person” includes any officer or employee of a corporation, or a member or employee of a partnership under a duty to pay such tax, make such return, keep such records or supply such information.
(2)Wilful delivery of false return or document.Any person who wilfully delivers or discloses to the commissioner or his authorized agent any list, return, account, statement or other document, known by him to be fraudulent or false in any material matter, shall, in addition to any other penalty provided by law, be guilty of a class D felony. No person shall be charged with an offense under both subsections (1) and (2) of this section in relation to the same tax period but such person may be charged and prosecuted for both such offenses upon the same information.
(3)Penalties for certain violations.Any person who knowingly violates any provision of this chapter for which no other penalty is provided, shall be fined not more than one thousand dollars or imprisoned not more than one year or both for each offense.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>