<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-420a"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-420a"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-420a"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-420a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-420a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-420a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-420a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_219">
        <num>219</num>
        <heading>Motor Vehicle Fuels Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_420a">
          <num>12-420a</num>
          <heading>Managed compliance and audit agreements: Definitions</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-420a. Managed compliance and audit agreements: Definitions.For purposes of this section and sections12-420band12-420c:
(1) “Eligible taxpayer” means any person who is required to file any return or to pay or remit any tax under this chapter and who in the opinion of the commissioner has demonstrated a willingness and ability to comply with the tax laws of this state and has maintained an acceptable system of business records;
(2) “Managed compliance agreement” means an agreement between the commissioner and an eligible taxpayer that provides for an agreed upon method for calculating and remitting use tax on that taxpayer's purchases;
(3) “Managed audit agreement” means an agreement between the commissioner and an eligible taxpayer consisting of an audit plan developed by the commissioner and the eligible taxpayer wherein the eligible taxpayer agrees to review selected sales and purchase records and to calculate and determine its liability for sales and use taxes;
(4) “Commissioner” means the Commissioner of Revenue Services; and
(5) “Effective use tax rate” means the rate of use tax to be applied against a predetermined base of purchases for the purpose of computing the eligible taxpayer's use tax liability for a defined period.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>