<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-431"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-431"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-431"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-431/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-431/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-431/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-431/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_219">
        <num>219</num>
        <heading>Motor Vehicle Fuels Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_431">
          <num>12-431</num>
          <heading>Tax on casual sales of motor vehicles, vessels, snowmobiles and aircraft</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_431__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_431__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Except as otherwise provided in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_431__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_431__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, in case of the purchase of any motor vehicle, snowmobile, vessel or aircraft other than from a licensed motor vehicle dealer or licensed motor vehicle lessor, a snowmobile dealer, a licensed marine dealer or a retailer of aircraft, respectively, the receipts therefrom shall not be included in the measure of the sales tax, but the purchaser thereof shall pay a use tax on the total purchase price thereof to the Commissioner of Revenue Services, as provided in section 12411, in the case of tangible personal property purchased from a retailer, and, in the case of motor vehicles, vessels and snowmobiles, before obtaining an original or transferal registration, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Commissioner of Revenue Services and on forms approved by the Commissioner of Revenue Services and the Commissioner of Motor Vehicles, and, in the case of aircraft, before obtaining an original or transferal registration, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Commissioner of Revenue Services and on forms approved by the Commissioner of Revenue Services and the Commissioner of Transportation.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_431__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>No use tax shall be payable in cases of purchase (A) when the purchaser is the spouse, mother, father, brother, sister or child of the seller, (B) when a motor vehicle or vessel is sold in connection with the organization, reorganization or liquidation of an incorporated business, provided the last taxable sale or use of the motor vehicle or vessel was subjected to a tax imposed by this chapter and the purchaser is the incorporated business or a stockholder thereof, (C) when a motor vehicle is sold in connection with the organization or termination of a partnership or limited liability company, provided the last taxable sale or use of the motor vehicle was subjected to a tax imposed by this chapter and the purchaser is the partnership or limited liability company, as the case may be, or a partner or member thereof as the case may be, or (D) when a motor vehicle which has been declared a total loss pursuant to the provisions of section 1416c is rebuilt for sale or use, provided the purchaser was subjected to the tax imposed by this chapter for the last taxable sale of said vehicle.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_431__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>when the purchaser is the spouse, mother, father, brother, sister or child of the seller,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_431__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>when a motor vehicle or vessel is sold in connection with the organization, reorganization or liquidation of an incorporated business, provided the last taxable sale or use of the motor vehicle or vessel was subjected to a tax imposed by this chapter and the purchaser is the incorporated business or a stockholder thereof,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_431__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>when a motor vehicle is sold in connection with the organization or termination of a partnership or limited liability company, provided the last taxable sale or use of the motor vehicle was subjected to a tax imposed by this chapter and the purchaser is the partnership or limited liability company, as the case may be, or a partner or member thereof as the case may be, or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_431__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>when a motor vehicle which has been declared a total loss pursuant to the provisions of section 1416c is rebuilt for sale or use, provided the purchaser was subjected to the tax imposed by this chapter for the last taxable sale of said vehicle.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_431__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When a motor vehicle in which special equipment has previously been installed exclusively for the use of a person with physical disabilities is sold for use by a person with physical disabilities, the purchaser shall pay a use tax on the total purchase price of the vehicle, less the portion of such price attributable to such special equipment. Unless established otherwise, the portion of the purchase price attributable to the motor vehicle shall be deemed to be the value determined pursuant to subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_431__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_431__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In order to determine the total purchase price of a motor vehicle for the purposes of this section, the commissioner shall, by regulation, adopt by reference a book of valuations, for various purposes, of motor vehicles published by a nationally recognized organization. The commissioner shall, by regulation, determine which of the various valuations of motor vehicles contained in any such book is appropriate for the purposes of this section and such value shall, regardless of the value placed on the motor vehicle at the time of the purchase by the parties to such transaction, be presumed to be the total purchase price of such motor vehicle for the purposes of this section unless the purchaser can prove to the satisfaction of the commissioner that such value is incorrect.
See Sec. 14-379 for definition of “snowmobile”.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>