<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-409"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-409"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-409"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-409/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-409/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-409/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-409/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_219">
        <num>219</num>
        <heading>Motor Vehicle Fuels Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_409">
          <num>12-409</num>
          <heading>Permits</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_409__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <heading>Permit required</heading>
            <content>
              <p>No person shall engage in or transact business as a seller within this state, unless a permit or permits have been issued to such person as prescribed in this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_409__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <heading>Application for permit</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Every person desiring to engage in or conduct business as a seller within this state shall file with the commissioner an application for a permit for each place of business. Every application for a permit shall be made upon a form prescribed by the commissioner and shall set forth the name under which the applicant transacts or intends to transact business, the location of the applicant's place or places of business and such other information as the commissioner requires. The application shall be signed by the owner if a natural person; in the case of an association or partnership, by a member or partner; in the case of a corporation, by an executive officer or some person specifically authorized by the corporation to sign the application.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_409__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <heading>Permit fee</heading>
            <content>
              <p>At the time of making an initial application for a permit, the applicant shall pay to the Commissioner of Revenue Services a permit fee of one hundred dollars for each permit. Any permit issued on or after October 1, 2003, but prior to October 1, 2017, shall expire on the fifth anniversary date of the issuance of such permit unless renewed in accordance with such procedure and application form as prescribed by the commissioner. Any permit issued on or after October 1, 2017, shall expire biennially on the anniversary date of the issuance of such permit unless renewed in accordance with such procedure and application form as prescribed by the commissioner.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_409__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <heading>Issuance of permit</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Permit requirements.After compliance with subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_409__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>,</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_409__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_409__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section by the applicant, the commissioner shall grant and issue to such applicant a separate permit for each place of business within the state. A permit is not assignable and is valid only for the person in whose name it is issued and for the transaction of business at the place designated therein. It shall at all times be conspicuously displayed at the place for which issued. Only a person actively engaging in or conducting business as a seller may hold a permit. Any person not so engaged shall surrender the permit to the commissioner for cancellation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_409__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <heading>Reissuance of permit</heading>
            <content>
              <p>A seller whose permit has been suspended or revoked shall pay to the Commissioner of Revenue Services a fee of one hundred dollars for the reissuance of a permit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_409__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <heading>Revocation or suspension of permit</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Whenever any person fails to comply with any provision of this chapter relating to the sales tax or any regulation of the commissioner relating to the sales tax prescribed and adopted under this chapter, the commissioner, upon hearing, after giving such person ten days' notice in writing specifying the time and place of hearing and requiring such person to show cause why such person's permit or permits should not be revoked, may revoke or suspend any one or more of the permits held by the person. The notice may be served personally or by registered or certified mail. The commissioner shall not issue a new permit after the revocation of a permit unless the commissioner is satisfied that the former holder of the permit will comply with the provisions of this chapter relating to the sales tax and the regulations of the commissioner.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_409__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <heading>Cancellation of permit</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Whenever any seller files returns for four successive monthly or quarterly periods, or for two successive annual periods, as the case may be, showing no sales, the commissioner, upon hearing, after giving such seller thirty days' notice, in writing, specifying the time and place of hearing and requiring such seller to show cause why such seller's permit or permits should not be cancelled, may cancel one or more of the permits held by such seller. The notice may be served personally or by mail. The commissioner shall not issue a new permit after the cancellation of a permit unless the commissioner is satisfied that the former holder of the permit will make sales subject to the provisions of this chapter relating to the sales tax and the regulations of the commissioner.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_409__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <heading>Unlawful acts</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Penalty.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_409__subsec_h__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any person who knowingly violates any provision of this section shall be fined not more than five hundred dollars or imprisoned not more than three months or both for each offense.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_409__subsec_h__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any person who fails to secure or renew a permit as provided in this section shall be subject to a civil penalty of two hundred fifty dollars for the first day such person engages in or transacts business without a permit and one hundred dollars for each subsequent day such person engages in or transacts business without such permit. Subject to the provisions of section12-3a, the commissioner may waive all or any part of the civil penalty provided in this subdivision if it is proven to the commissioner's satisfaction that the failure to secure or renew such permit was due to reasonable cause and was not intentional or due to neglect.
See Sec. 12-39o re issuance or renewal of license when taxes are owed.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>