<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-344a"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-344a"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-344a"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-344a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-344a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-344a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-344a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_216">
        <num>216</num>
        <heading>Sales and Use Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_344a">
          <num>12-344a</num>
          <heading>Additional amount added to tax</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_344a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To the tax imposed by the provisions of this chapter, there shall be added an amount equal to thirty per cent of the tax so imposed and computed under said provisions. Said added amount so computed shall, upon its addition as aforesaid, constitute a part of the tax imposed and to be computed and assessed, become due and be paid, collected and enforced as provided in this chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_344a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>With respect to the estate of any person whose death occurs on or after July 1, 1983, there shall be added to the tax imposed by the provisions of this chapter, including the amount of tax added in accordance with subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_344a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, and subject to the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_344a__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, an amount determined as ten per cent of the tax so imposed and computed under said provisions. The additional amount of tax determined in accordance with this subsection shall constitute a part of the tax imposed by the provisions of this chapter and shall be computed and assessed, become due and be paid, collected and enforced as provided in this chapter. The estate of any person whose death occurs prior to July 1, 1983, shall be subject to the provisions of this chapter applicable to such estate at the time of such person's death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_344a__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The additional amount of tax imposed in accordance with subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_344a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section shall not be applicable with respect to any real property in the estate of the decedent passing to any natural or adopted descendant of the decedent, which real property is classified as farm land in accordance with section12-107cat the time of the decedent's death.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>