<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-371"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-371"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-371"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-371/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-371/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-371/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-371/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_216">
        <num>216</num>
        <heading>Sales and Use Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_371">
          <num>12-371</num>
          <heading>Estates of nonresident decedents; cooperation with other states</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-371. Estates of nonresident decedents; cooperation with other states.“Death taxes”, as used in this section, shall include inheritance, succession, transfer or estate taxes or any taxes levied against the estate of a decedent upon the occasion of his death. When the Commissioner of Revenue Services is notified by a probate court of the issuance of original letters testamentary or of administration in the case of the estate of a decedent not domiciled in this state, he shall immediately notify the proper taxing authorities of the state in which such decedent was domiciled of the filing of a petition therefor and of the nature and value of the decedent's property, so far as such information has come into the hands of said commissioner. No executor of the will or administrator of the estate of such a decedent to whom original letters have been issued shall be entitled to a final account or discharge unless he has filed with the probate court proof that all death taxes, together with interest or penalties thereon, due the state of domicile of such decedent, or any political subdivision thereof, have been paid or secured, or a consent by the proper taxing authorities of the state of domicile to such final accounting or discharge. The Commissioner of Revenue Services shall cooperate with the domiciliary taxing authorities and furnish them with such information as may be requested with respect to any such estate. The official or body of the domiciliary state charged with the administration of the statutes relating to death taxes shall be deemed a party interested in such estate to the extent that he or it may petition for an accounting therein if the death taxes, with interest and penalties, due such domiciliary state, or a political subdivision thereof, are not paid or secured and, upon such petition, the probate court may decree such accounting and may decree the remission to a fiduciary appointed by the domiciliary probate court of so much of the personal property of such estate as is necessary to insure the payment to the state of domicile, or political subdivision thereof, of the amount of death taxes, interest and penalties due such state or political subdivision. The provisions of this section shall apply to the estate of a decedent not domiciled in this state only if the laws of the state of his domicile contain a provision whereby this state is given reasonable assurance of the collection of its death taxes, interest and penalties from the estates of decedents who died domiciled in this state in cases in which such estates are being administered by the probate court of such other state by virtue of original letters testamentary or of administration, or if the state in which such decedent was domiciled does not grant letters testamentary or of administration in the case of estates of nonresidents until after letters have been issued by the state of domicile. The provisions of this section shall be liberally construed in order to insure that the state of domicile of a decedent shall receive any death taxes, with interest and penalties thereon, due it from such decedent's estate. For the purpose of this section “state” shall include any territory of the United States, the District of Columbia and the Dominion of Canada or any province thereof.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>