<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-169b"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-169b"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-169b"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-169b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-169b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-169b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-169b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_204">
        <num>204</num>
        <heading>Local Levy and Collection of Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_169b">
          <num>12-169b</num>
          <heading>Addition of municipal expenses to property taxes for real estate violating health, safety or housing codes</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-169b. Addition of municipal expenses to property taxes for real estate violating health, safety or housing codes.If a municipality does not file a lien under any provisions of the general statutes to recover costs for the inspection, repair, demolition, removal or other disposition of any real estate in order to secure such real estate or to make it safe and sanitary, pursuant to any provision of the general statutes or municipal building, health, housing or safety codes or regulations, then such municipality may assess the amount of such costs against the real estate upon which such cost was incurred. Upon certification by the municipal agency incurring such cost of the assessment amount due and owing reasonably related to the municipality's actual cost, the tax collector shall add the amount of such assessment to the extent unpaid to the taxes due on such real estate and such amount shall become a part of the taxes to be collected at the same time and shall bear interest at such rates and in such manner as provided for delinquent taxes in accordance with section12-146. Any amount added to the assessment under this section shall constitute a lien upon the real estate against for which the amount was imposed from the date such amount was due. Each such lien may be continued, recorded and released in the manner provided by the general statutes for continuing, recording and releasing property tax liens. Each such lien may be enforced in the same manner as property tax liens. Any agency of a municipality that incurs costs that have been assessed against real estate under this section shall maintain a current record of all real estate with respect to which such costs remain unpaid in the office of such municipal agency. Such record shall be available for inspection by the public.
See Sec. 7-148ff re special assessment on blighted housing.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>