<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129c"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129c"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-129c"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129c/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129c/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129c/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129c/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_204">
        <num>204</num>
        <heading>Local Levy and Collection of Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_129c">
          <num>12-129c</num>
          <heading>Application for real property tax relief for certain persons sixty-five years of age or over. Biennial requirements. Penalty for false affidavit or false statement</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_129c__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No claim shall be accepted under section12-129bunless the taxpayer or authorized agent of such taxpayer files an application with the assessor of the municipality in which the property is located, in affidavit form as provided by the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management, during the period from February first to and including May fifteenth of any year in which benefits are first claimed, including such information as is necessary to substantiate said claim in accordance with requirements in such application. A taxpayer may make application to the secretary prior to August fifteenth of the claim year for an extension of the application period. The secretary may grant such extension in the case of extenuating circumstance due to illness or incapacitation as evidenced by a certificate signed by a physician, a physician assistant or an advanced practice registered nurse to that extent, or if the secretary determines there is good cause for doing so. The taxpayer shall present to the assessor a copy of such taxpayer's federal income tax return and the federal income tax return of such taxpayer's spouse, if filed separately, for such taxpayer's taxable year ending immediately prior to the submission of the taxpayer's application, or if not required to file a federal income tax return, such other evidence of qualifying income in respect to such taxable year as the assessor may require. Each such application, together with the federal income tax return and any other information submitted in relation thereto, shall be examined by the assessor and if the application is approved by the assessor, it shall be forwarded to the secretary on or before July first of the year in which such application is approved, except that in the case of a taxpayer who received a filing date extension from the secretary, such application shall be forwarded to the secretary not later than ten business days after the date it is filed with the assessor. After a taxpayer's claim for the fir</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_129c__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person knowingly making a false affidavit for the purpose of claiming property tax relief under section12-129band this section shall be fined not more than five hundred dollars. Any person who fails to disclose all matters relating thereto or with intent to defraud makes a false statement shall refund to the state or to the municipality, as the case may be, all tax relief improperly taken.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>