<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129n"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129n"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-129n"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129n/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129n/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129n/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129n/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_204">
        <num>204</num>
        <heading>Local Levy and Collection of Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_129n">
          <num>12-129n</num>
          <heading>Optional municipal property tax relief program for certain homeowners age sixty-five or over or permanently and totally disabled</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_129n__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any municipality may, by vote of its legislative body on recommendation of its board of finance or equivalent body, provide property tax relief to residents of such municipality, with respect to real property owned and occupied by such residents as their principal residence, or held in trust for and occupied by such residents as their principal residence, who are</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_129n__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>sixty-five years of age and over, or whose spouses, living with them, are sixty-five years of age or over or sixty years of age or over and the surviving spouse of a taxpayer qualified in such municipality under this section at the time of his or her death or with respect to real property on which such residents or their spouses are liable for taxes under section12-48, or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_129n__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>under age sixty-five and eligible in accordance with applicable federal regulations to receive permanent total disability benefits under Social Security, or have not been engaged in employment covered by Social Security and accordingly have not qualified for benefits thereunder, but have become qualified for permanent total disability benefits under any federal, state or local government retirement or disability plan, including the Railroad Retirement Act and any government-related teacher's retirement plan, in which requirements with respect to qualifications for such permanent total disability benefits are comparable to such requirements under Social Security, provided such residents or their spouses under subdivisions</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_129n__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_129n__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>above have been taxpayers of such municipality for one year immediately preceding their receipt of tax benefits under this section, and meet the requirements which may be established by such municipality with respect to maximum income allowable during the calendar year preceding the year in which application is made for the tax relief provided in this section. No such property tax relief, together with any relief received by any such resident under the provisions of sections12-129bto12-129d, inclusive, and12-170aashall exceed, in the aggregate the total amount of the tax which would, except for said sections12-129bto12-129d, inclusive,12-170aaand this section, be laid against the taxpayer.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_129n__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Prior to initial approval by the legislative body of such municipality of the plan of property tax relief to be provided pursuant to the provisions of this section, the executive authority of such municipality shall appoint a committee consisting of not less than five resident taxpayers of such municipality, which shall undertake and complete within a period not in excess of sixty days following such appointment, a study and investigation with respect to such property tax relief and, on the basis thereof, prepare a report to be presented to the board of finance or equivalent body of such municipality, which report shall include the following:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_129n__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The fiscal effect of such property tax relief on property tax revenue for such municipality;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_129n__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>recommendations with respect to the form and extent of such property tax relief. After the initial approval of such property tax relief by the legislative body of such municipality, such plan may be amended from time to time by vote of its legislative body on recommendation of its board of finance or equivalent body without compliance with the requirements of this subsection applicable to such initial approval.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_129n__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The total abatement of property tax revenue, based on an estimate in any tax year by the board of finance or equivalent body of such municipality, which may be granted in such tax year by such municipality pursuant to the provisions of this section shall not exceed an amount equal to ten per cent of the total real property tax assessed in such municipality in the preceding tax year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_129n__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any such property tax relief granted to any such resident in accordance with the provisions of this section shall not disqualify such resident with respect to any benefits for which such resident shall be eligible under the provisions of sections12-129bto12-129d, inclusive, and12-170aa, and any such property tax relief provided under this section shall be in addition to any such benefits for which such resident shall be eligible under said sections.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_129n__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Reimbursement of such municipality under the provisions of sections12-129bto12-129d, inclusive, and12-170aashall be limited to such amount as the municipality would be entitled to receive for revenues lost because of tax relief provided under the provisions of said sections. The property tax relief provided for in this section may, in any case where title to real property is recorded in the name of the taxpayer or his or her spouse and any other person or persons, be prorated to reflect the fractional share of such taxpayer or spouse or, if such property is a multiple-family dwelling, such relief may be prorated to reflect the fractional portion of such property occupied by the taxpayer.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_129n__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any municipality providing property tax relief under this section may establish a lien on such property in the amount of the relief granted, provided if the total amount of such property tax relief with respect to any such taxpayer, when combined with any such tax relief for which such taxpayer may be eligible in accordance with sections12-129bto12-129d, inclusive, or12-170aa, exceeds in the aggregate seventy-five per cent of the property tax for which such taxpayer would be liable but for the benefits under this section and any of the sections mentioned above in this subsection, such municipality shall be required to establish a lien on such property in the amount that such tax relief exceeds seventy-five per cent of such property tax liability, plus interest applicable to the total of such unpaid taxes at a rate to be determined by such municipality. Any such lien shall have a priority in the settlement of such person's estate.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_129n__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_129n__subsec_g__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any municipality establishing a program of property tax relief under this section shall make persons eligible for such relief if they qualify in accordance with age and income pursuant to subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_129n__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section and are unit owners of a cooperative.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_129n__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The amount of annual property tax relief in accordance with this subsection to any such person shall be determined in relation to an assumed amount of property tax liability applicable to the assessed value for the dwelling unit which such person owns and occupies, as determined by the assessor in the municipality in which the cooperative is situated. For purposes of this section the assessor shall determine the assumed amount of property tax liability applicable to the assessed value for the dwelling unit of each such person who is otherwise eligible under this subsection, but such determination shall not constitute a tax bill for purposes of property taxation of such cooperative or any individual dwelling unit thereof. Annually, not later than the first day of June, the assessor in such municipality, upon receipt of an application for such relief, shall determine, with respect to the assessment list in such municipality for the assessment year commencing October first immediately preceding, the portion of the assessed value of the entire cooperative, as included in such assessment list, attributable to the dwelling unit occupied by such person. The assumed property tax liability for purposes of determining the amount of the relief shall be the product of such assessed value and the mill rate in such municipality as determined for purposes of property tax imposed on said assessment list for the assessment year commencing October first immediately preceding. The amount of relief to which such person shall be entitled for such assessment year shall be equivalent to the amount of tax reduction for which such person would qualify, considering such assumed property tax liability to be the actual property tax applicable to such person's dwelling unit and such person as liable for the payment of such tax.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>