<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129d"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129d"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-129d"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129d/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129d/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129d/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129d/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_204">
        <num>204</num>
        <heading>Local Levy and Collection of Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_129d">
          <num>12-129d</num>
          <heading>State payment in lieu of tax revenue</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_129d__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On or before January first, annually, the tax collector of each municipality shall certify to the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management, on a form furnished by the secretary, the amount of tax revenue which such municipality, except for the provisions of section12-129b, would have received, together with such supporting information as said secretary may require. On or after December 1, 1989, any municipality which neglects to transmit the claim and supporting information as required by this section shall forfeit two hundred fifty dollars to the state, provided said secretary may waive such forfeiture in accordance with procedures and standards adopted by regulation in accordance with chapter 54. Said secretary shall review each such claim in accordance with the procedure set forth in section12-120b. Any claimant aggrieved by the results of the secretary's review shall have the rights of appeal as set forth in section12-120b.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_129d__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management shall, on or before September first, annually, certify to the Comptroller the amount due each municipality under the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_129d__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, including any modification of such claim made prior to September first, and the Comptroller shall draw an order on the Treasurer on or before the fifth business day following September first and the Treasurer shall pay the amount thereof to such municipality on or before the fifteenth day of September following. If any modification is made as the result of the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_129d__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section on or after the August fifteenth following the date on which the tax collector has provided the amount of tax revenue in question, any adjustments to the amount due to any municipality for the period for which such modification was made shall be made in the next payment the Treasurer shall make to such municipality pursuant to this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_129d__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The amount of state payment to each municipality as reimbursement for the revenue loss related to the tax relief given to individuals pursuant to12-129bshall be reduced proportionately in the event that the total amount payable to all municipalities for this program exceeds the amount appropriated.
See Sec. 12-120b re uniform administrative procedure for appeals related to state-reimbursed property tax exemptions, credits and rebates.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>