<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-126"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-126"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-126"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-126/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-126/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-126/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-126/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_204">
        <num>204</num>
        <heading>Local Levy and Collection of Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_126">
          <num>12-126</num>
          <heading>Abatement or refund of tax on tangible personal property assessed in more than one municipality</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-126. Abatement or refund of tax on tangible personal property assessed in more than one municipality.If any tangible personal property is assessed in more than one municipality in any assessment year, upon payment of the tax in the municipality in which such property is subject to property tax for such assessment year in accordance with sections12-43,12-59or12-71, the tax in the other municipality or municipalities shall be removed from the rate book by means of a certificate of error issued by the assessor or board of assessors. If such tax has been paid to a municipality in which such property is not subject to property tax for such assessment year in accordance with said sections12-43,12-59or12-71, the amount thereof shall be refunded to the taxpayer upon written application therefor to the tax collector. Such application shall contain a recital of the facts, and the collector shall, after examination thereof, refer the same, with his recommendation thereon, to the board of selectmen in the case of a town or to the corresponding authority in any other municipality, and shall certify to the amount of refund to which the applicant is entitled. Upon receipt of such application and certification, the selectmen or other duly constituted authority shall draw an order upon the treasurer in favor of such applicant for such amount without interest.
See Sec. 12-57 re issuance of certificate of correction when property improperly included on list.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>