<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-28j"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-28j"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-28j"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-28j/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-28j/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-28j/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-28j/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319o">
        <num>319o</num>
        <heading>Personal Care Assistance</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_28j">
          <num>17b-28j</num>
          <heading>Amendment to Medicaid state plan re community violence prevention services</heading>
          <subsection eId="17b_28j__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Community violence” means intentional acts of interpersonal violence committed in public areas by individuals who are not family members or intimate partners of the victim;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Community violence prevention services” means evidence-based, trauma-informed, supportive and nonpsychotherapeutic services provided by a certified violence prevention professional, within or outside of a clinical setting, for the purpose of promoting improved health outcomes and positive behavioral change, preventing injury recidivism and reducing the likelihood that individuals who are victims of community violence will commit or promote violence themselves. “Community violence prevention services” may include the provision of peer support and counseling, mentorship, conflict mediation, crisis intervention, targeted case management, referrals to certified or licensed health care professionals or social services providers, patient education or screening services to victims of community violence;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Interpersonal violence” means the intentional use of physical force or power against other persons by an individual or small group of individuals;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Prevention professional” has the same meaning as described by the National Uniform Claim Committee (NUCC), or its successor, under NUCC Code Number 405300000X; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_a__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Certified violence prevention professional” means a prevention professional who meets all of the conditions specified in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_28j__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_28j__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>On or before July 1, 2022, the Commissioner of Social Services, shall amend the Medicaid state plan to make community violence prevention services available, to the extent permitted by federal law, to any Medicaid beneficiary who has: (A) Received medical treatment for an injury sustained as a result of an act of community violence, and (B) been referred by a certified or licensed health care provider or social services provider to receive community violence prevention services from a certified violence prevention professional, after such provider determines such beneficiary to be at elevated risk of a violent injury or retaliation resulting from another act of community violence.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Received medical treatment for an injury sustained as a result of an act of community violence, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>been referred by a certified or licensed health care provider or social services provider to receive community violence prevention services from a certified violence prevention professional, after such provider determines such beneficiary to be at elevated risk of a violent injury or retaliation resulting from another act of community violence.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Commissioner of Social Services shall seek any federal approvals necessary to implement this section, including, but not limited to, any state plan amendments or federal waivers by the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services. This subsection shall be implemented only to the extent that federal financial participation is available, and any necessary federal approvals have been obtained.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The provisions of this subsection shall be implemented only to the extent permitted by federal law.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_28j__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any prevention professional seeking certification as a certified violence prevention professional shall complete an accredited training and certification program for certified violence prevention professionals, approved in accordance with subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_28j__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section and maintain such certification.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_28j__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On or before January 1, 2022, the Department of Public Health shall approve at least one accredited training and certification program for certified violence prevention professionals. Such program shall include:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>At least thirty-five hours of initial training, collectively addressing all of the following:
(A) The profound effects of trauma and violence and the basics of trauma-informed care;
(B) Community violence prevention strategies, including, but not limited to, conflict mediation and retaliation prevention related to community violence;
(C) Case management and advocacy practices; and
(D) Patient privacy and the federal Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, P.L. 104-191, as amended from time to time, (HIPAA); and</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_d__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The profound effects of trauma and violence and the basics of trauma-informed care;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_d__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Community violence prevention strategies, including, but not limited to, conflict mediation and retaliation prevention related to community violence;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_d__subsec_1__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Case management and advocacy practices; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_d__subsec_1__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Patient privacy and the federal Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, P.L. 104-191, as amended from time to time, (HIPAA); and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>At least six hours of continuing education every two years.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_28j__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any entity that employs or contracts with a certified violence prevention professional to provide community violence prevention services shall:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_e__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Maintain documentation that the certified violence prevention professional has met all of the conditions described in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_28j__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section; and</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28j__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Ensure that the certified violence prevention professional is providing community violence prevention services in compliance with any applicable standards of care, rules, regulations and governing law of the state or federal government.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_28j__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No person, unless certified as a violence prevention professional pursuant to this section, may use the title “certified violence prevention professional” or make use of any title, words, letters, abbreviations or insignia indicating or implying that he or she is a certified violence prevention professional.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_28j__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <heading>Nothing in this section shall alter the scope of practice for any health care professional</heading>
            <content>
              <p>(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>