<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-10c"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-10c"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-10c"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-10c/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-10c/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-10c/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-10c/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319o">
        <num>319o</num>
        <heading>Personal Care Assistance</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_10c">
          <num>17b-10c</num>
          <heading>Uniform Policy Manual revision to regulation format. Committee review. Posting on eRegulations System</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 17b-10c. Uniform Policy Manual revision to regulation format. Committee review. Posting on eRegulations System.The Department of Social Services shall make technical and structural changes to the Uniform Policy Manual to conform to the numbering system, organization, form and style of the regulations of Connecticut state agencies. Notwithstanding the provisions of chapter 54, the department may make such changes without complying with the provisions of said chapter concerning regulation-making proceedings. The department shall submit such changes to the standing legislative regulations review committee for review in accordance with this section. Any review of such changes by said committee shall be limited to confirming that such changes are technical and structural in nature in accordance with this section. If the committee does not act in response to the department's submission not later than forty-five days after such submission, such changes shall be deemed approved. Upon approval, the department shall transmit a certified electronic copy of such changes to the Secretary of the State for the Secretary to post on the eRegulations System. At the time that the Secretary posts such changes on the eRegulations System, the corresponding sections of the Uniform Policy Manual shall be deemed superseded.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>