<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-423"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-423"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-423"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-423/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-423/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-423/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-423/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319h">
        <num>319h</num>
        <heading>Energy Assistance</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_423">
          <num>17a-423</num>
          <heading>Long-term care policy, regulation, task force membership requirements. Duties of state agencies, Ombudsman, Commission on Women, Children, Seniors, Equity and Opportunity</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_423__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Not later than three days after a state agency submits a legislative proposal to the General Assembly or posts a notice of intent on the eRegulations System proposing a new or revised regulation concerning living and care conditions at long-term care facilities, such agency shall inform the State Ombudsman, appointed pursuant to section17a-870, and the executive director of the Commission on Women, Children, Seniors, Equity and Opportunity, established pursuant to section2-127. The State Ombudsman and the executive director shall seek testimony from the Statewide Coalition of Presidents of Residents Councils and from family councils concerning such legislative proposal or proposed regulation. For regulations other than those proposed pursuant to subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_423__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_423__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section4-168, the State Ombudsman and the executive director shall immediately inform the members of the coalition and family councils that the agency will be required to hold a public hearing upon the request of fifteen or more persons not later than fourteen days after the date such notice of intent is posted on the eRegulations System. Such agency or legislative committee of cognizance shall accept testimony in a manner and format that provides for the greatest input from members of residents councils and family councils including, but not limited to, when permissible under the rules of such agency or committee and when practicable, remote testimony by such members via technology with audio or audio and video capabilities.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_423__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any state task force appointed by the General Assembly or by a state agency that is studying issues concerning living or care conditions at long-term care facilities shall include among members</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_423__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>representatives of residents councils,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_423__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>representatives of family councils, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_423__subsec_c__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the chairpersons and ranking members of the joint standing committee of the General Assembly having cognizance of matters relating to aging, or their designees. The chairpersons of such task force shall schedule meetings in a manner and format that provides for the greatest input from members of residents councils and family councils, including, but not limited to, when practicable, remote testimony by such members via technology with audio or video capabilities.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>