<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-557b"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-557b"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-557b"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-557b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-557b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-557b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-557b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_226">
        <num>226</num>
        <heading>Prepared Food and Beverage Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_557b">
          <num>12-557b</num>
          <heading>Definitions</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-557b. Definitions.As used in this chapter, sections12-578ato12-578e, inclusive,12-579and12-580, chapter 226b, and section53-278g, unless the context otherwise requires:
(1) “Commissioner” means the Commissioner of Consumer Protection;
(2) “Department” means the Department of Consumer Protection;
(3) “Business organization” means a partnership, incorporated or unincorporated association, firm, corporation, trust or other form of business or legal entity, other than a financial institution regulated by a state or federal agency which is not exercising control over an association licensee, but does not mean a governmental or sovereign entity;
(4) “Control” means the power to exercise authority over or direct the management and policies of a person or business organization;
(5) “Casino gaming facility” means any casino gaming facility authorized by any provision of the general statutes or a public or special act to conduct authorized games on its premises, but does not include any casino gaming facility located on Indian lands pursuant to the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act, P.L. 100-497, 25 USC 2701 et seq.;
(6) “Authorized game” means any game of chance specifically authorized to be conducted at a casino gaming facility by any provision of the general statutes or a public or special act; and
(7) “Gross gaming revenue” means the total of all sums actually received by a casino gaming facility from gaming operations less the total of all sums paid as winnings to patrons of the casino gaming facility, provided the total of all sums paid as winnings to such patrons shall not include the cash equivalent value of any merchandise or thing of value included in a jackpot or payout, and provided further the issuance to or wagering by such patrons of any promotional gaming credit shall not be included in the total of all sums actually received by a casino gaming facility for the purposes of determining gross gaming revenue.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>