<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-571"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-571"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-571"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-571/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-571/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-571/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-571/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_226">
        <num>226</num>
        <heading>Prepared Food and Beverage Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_571">
          <num>12-571</num>
          <heading>Sale of off-track betting systems. Regulation of off-track betting systems</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_571__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Consumer Protection shall enter into negotiations with a person or business organization for the award of a contract of sale of the off-track betting system including, but not limited to, the assets and liabilities of the system and the right to operate the system. Such contract of sale shall authorize the purchaser of the system to establish and conduct a system of off-track betting on races held within or without the state pursuant to the provisions of this chapter. All proceeds derived from such sale shall be deposited as provided in section 39 of public act 93-332*. Until the effective date of transfer of ownership of the off-track betting system, the commissioner shall establish and conduct systems of off-track betting on races held within or without the state pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_571__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is hereby declared that off-track betting on races conducted under the administration or regulatory authority of the department in the manner and subject to the conditions of this chapter shall be lawful notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, general, special or municipal, including any law prohibiting or restricting lotteries, bookmaking or any other kind of gambling, it being the purpose of this chapter to derive from such betting, as authorized by this chapter, a reasonable revenue for the support of state government and to prevent and curb unlawful bookmaking and illegal betting on races.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_571__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Until the effective date of transfer of ownership of the off-track betting system, the commissioner shall adopt rules and regulations, consistent with this chapter, establishing and governing the permitted method or methods of operation of the system of off-track betting.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_571__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of this section, the effective date of transfer of ownership of the off-track betting system was June 30, 1993.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>