<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-592"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-592"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-592"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-592/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-592/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-592/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-592/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_227">
        <num>227</num>
        <heading>Rental Surcharge on Leasing Companies</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_592">
          <num>12-592</num>
          <heading>Inquiries, investigations or hearings related to the tax</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-592. Inquiries, investigations or hearings related to the tax.The Commissioner of Revenue Services or any agent of said commissioner authorized to conduct any inquiry, investigation or hearing related to the tax imposed under section12-587may administer oaths and take testimony under oath relative to such matter of inquiry or investigation. At any such hearing ordered by said commissioner, the commissioner or such agent authorized to conduct such hearing may subpoena witnesses and require the production of books, papers and documents pertinent to such inquiry. No witness under subpoena as aforesaid shall be excused from testifying or from producing books or papers on the ground that such testimony or the production of such books or other documentary evidence would tend to incriminate such witness, provided such evidence or books or papers so produced shall not be used in any criminal proceeding against such witness. If any person disobeys such process or, having appeared in obedience thereto, refuses to answer any pertinent question by said commissioner or such authorized agent, or to produce any books and papers pursuant thereto, said commissioner or such agent may apply to the superior court for the judicial district wherein such person resides or wherein the business under investigation has been conducted, or to any judge of said court if the same is not in session, setting forth such disobedience to process or refusal to answer, and said court or such judge shall cite such person to appear before said court or such judge to answer such question or to produce such books and papers and upon his refusal so to do shall commit such person to a community correctional center until he testifies, but not for a period longer than sixty days. Notwithstanding the serving of the term of such commitment by any person, said commissioner may proceed in all respects with such inquiry and examination as if the witness had not previously been called upon to testify. Officers who serve subpoenas issued by said commissioner or under said commissioner's authority and witnesses attending hearings conducted by said commissioner in accordance with this section shall receive fees and compensation at the same rates as officers and witnesses in the courts of this state, to be paid on vouchers of said commissioner on order of the Comptroller from the proper appropriation for the administration of this section.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>