<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-587a"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-587a"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-587a"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-587a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-587a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-587a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-587a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_227">
        <num>227</num>
        <heading>Rental Surcharge on Leasing Companies</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_587a">
          <num>12-587a</num>
          <heading>Tax credit for company liable for tax on sale of petroleum products to purchaser who sells the products outside the state. Purchaser reimbursed by company for tax in purchase price of such products</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_587a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_587a__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any company, as such term is used in section12-587, liable for the tax imposed under subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_587a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-587on gross earnings from the first sale of petroleum products within this state, which products the purchaser thereof subsequently sells for exportation and sale or use outside this state, shall be allowed a credit against any tax for which such company is liable in accordance with subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_587a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-587, in the amount of tax paid to the state with respect to the sale of such products, provided (A) such purchaser has submitted certification to such company, in such form as prescribed by the Commissioner of Revenue Services, that such products were sold or used outside this state, (B) such certification and any additional information related to such sale or use by such purchaser, which said commissioner may request, have been submitted to said commissioner, and (C) such company makes a payment to such purchaser, related to such products sold or used outside this state, in the amount equal to the tax imposed under section12-587on gross earnings from the first sale to such purchaser within the state.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_587a__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The credit allowed pursuant to subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_587a__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection may also be claimed, in the same manner as provided in said subdivision, by any such company when the petroleum products sold in a first sale within this state by such company are incorporated by the purchaser thereof into a material that is included in U.S. industry group 3255 in the North American Industrial Classification System United States Manual, United States Office of Management and Budget, 2007 edition, and such products are subsequently exported for sale or use outside this state. Such company shall be allowed such credit in the amount of tax paid to the state with respect to the sale of such products.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_587a__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In addition, such company shall be allowed such credit when there has been any sale of such products subsequent to the sale by such company but prior to sale or use outside this state, provided (A) each purchaser receives payment, related to such products sold or used outside this state, equal to the tax imposed under section12-587, on gross earnings from the first sale of such products within this state, and (B) the purchaser selling or using such products outside this state complies with the requirements in this section related to a purchaser of such products from the company liable for such tax.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_587a__subsec_b__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>each purchaser receives payment, related to such products sold or used outside this state, equal to the tax imposed under section12-587, on gross earnings from the first sale of such products within this state, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_587a__subsec_b__subsec_3__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the purchaser selling or using such products outside this state complies with the requirements in this section related to a purchaser of such products from the company liable for such tax.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_587a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_587a__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any company liable for the tax imposed under subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_587a__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-587on the consideration given or contracted to be given for petroleum products which it imports or causes to be imported into this state for sale, use or consumption in this state, shall be allowed a credit against tax under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_587a__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-587if the company subsequently exports such petroleum products for sale or use outside this state, in the amount of tax paid to the state with respect to the sale, use or consumption in this state of such products.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_587a__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The credit allowed pursuant to subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_587a__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection may also be claimed, in the same manner as provided in said subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_587a__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>, by any such company when the petroleum products which such company imports or causes to be imported into this state are incorporated by such company into a material that is included in U.S. industry group 3255 in the North American Industrial Classification System United States Manual, United States Office of Management and Budget, 2007 edition, and such company subsequently exports such products for sale or use outside this state. Such company shall be allowed said credit in the amount of tax paid to the state with respect to the sale, use or consumption in this state of such products.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>