<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-170aa"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-170aa"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-170aa"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-170aa/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-170aa/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-170aa/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-170aa/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_204a">
        <num>204a</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Relief for Elderly Homeowners and Renters and Persons with Permanent Total Disability</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_170aa">
          <num>12-170aa</num>
          <heading>Tax relief for certain elderly or totally disabled homeowners. Reductions in real property taxes</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <heading>Revision effective for assessment year commencing October 1, 1985, and thereafter</heading>
            <content>
              <p>There is established, for the assessment year commencing October 1, 1985, and each assessment year thereafter, a revised state program of property tax relief for certain elderly homeowners as determined in accordance with subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, and additionally for the assessment year commencing October 1, 1986, and each assessment year thereafter, the property tax relief benefits of such program are made available to certain homeowners who are permanently and totally disabled as determined in accordance with subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <heading>Eligibility for benefits</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Age and income requirements. Determination of income.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The program established by this section shall provide for a reduction in property tax, except in the case of benefits payable as a grant under certain circumstances in accordance with provisions in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_j">
            <num>(j)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, applicable to the assessed value of certain real property, determined in accordance with subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, for any (A) owner of real property, including any owner of real property held in trust for such owner, provided such owner or such owner and such owner's spouse are the grantor and beneficiary of such trust, (B) tenant for life or tenant for a term of years liable for property tax under section12-48, or (C) resident of a multiple-dwelling complex under certain contractual conditions as provided in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_j">
            <num>(j)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, who</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>at the close of the preceding calendar year has attained age sixty-five or over, or whose spouse domiciled with such homeowner, has attained age sixty-five or over at the close of the preceding calendar year, or is fifty years of age or over and the surviving spouse of a homeowner who at the time of such homeowner's death had qualified and was entitled to tax relief under this section, provided such spouse was domiciled with such homeowner at the time of such homeowner's death, or (ii) at the close of the preceding calendar year has not attained age sixty-five and is eligible in accordance with applicable federal regulations to receive permanent total disability benefits under Social Security, or has not been engaged in employment covered by Social Security and accordingly has not qualified for benefits thereunder but who has become qualified for permanent total disability benefits under any federal, state or local government retirement or disability plan, including the Railroad Retirement Act and any government-related teacher's retirement plan, determined by the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management to contain requirements in respect to qualification for such permanent total disability benefits that are comparable to such requirements under Social Security; and in addition to qualification under clause</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or (ii) of this subdivision, whose taxable and nontaxable income, the total of which shall hereinafter be called “qualifying income”, in the tax year of such homeowner ending immediately preceding the date of application for benefits under the program in this section, was not in excess of sixteen thousand two hundred dollars, if unmarried, or twenty thousand dollars, jointly with spouse if married, subject to adjustments in accordance with subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_i__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, evidence of which income shall be required in the form of a signed affidavit to be submitted to the assessor in the municipality in which application for benefits under this section is filed. Such affidavit may be filed electronically, in a manner prescribed by the assessor. The amount of any Medicaid payments made on behalf of such homeowner or the spouse of such homeowner shall not constitute income. The amount of tax reduction provided under this section, determined in accordance with and subject to the variable factors in the schedule of amounts of tax reduction in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, shall be allowed only with respect to a residential dwelling owned by such qualified homeowner and used as such homeowner's primary place of residence. If title to real property or a tenancy interest liable for real property taxes is recorded in the name of such qualified homeowner or his spouse making a claim and qualifying under this section and any other person or persons, the claimant hereunder shall be entitled to pay his fractional share of the tax on such property calculated in accordance with the provisions of this section, and such other person or persons shall pay his or their fractional share of the tax without regard for the provisions of this section, unless also qualified hereunder. For the purposes of this section, a “mobile manufactured home”, as defined in section12-63a, or a dwelling on leased land, including but not limited to a modular home, shall be deemed to be real property and the word “taxes” shall not include special assessments, interest and lien fees.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The amounts of qualifying income as provided in this section shall be adjusted annually in a uniform manner to reflect the annual inflation adjustment in Social Security income, with each such adjustment of qualifying income determined to the nearest one hundred dollars. Each such adjustment of qualifying income shall be prepared by the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management in relation to the annual inflation adjustment in Social Security, if any, becoming effective at any time during the twelve-month period immediately preceding the first day of October each year and the amount of such adjustment shall be distributed to the assessors in each municipality not later than the thirty-first day of December next following.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_c__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For purposes of determining qualifying income under subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection with respect to a married homeowner who submits an application for tax reduction in accordance with this section, the Social Security income of the spouse of such homeowner shall not be included in the qualifying income of such homeowner, for purposes of determining eligibility for benefits under this section, if such spouse is a resident of a health care or nursing home facility in this state receiving payment related to such spouse under the Title XIX Medicaid program. An applicant who is legally separated pursuant to the provisions of section46b-40, as of the thirty-first day of December preceding the date on which such person files an application for a grant in accordance with subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, may apply as an unmarried person and shall be regarded as such for purposes of determining qualifying income under said subsection.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <heading>Schedule of qualifying income and corresponding tax deductions</heading>
            <content>
              <p>The amount of reduction in property tax provided under this section shall, subject to the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, be determined in accordance with the following schedule:
Qualifying IncomeTax ReductionAs PercentageOf Property TaxTax ReductionFor Any YearOverNot ExceedingMarried HomeownersMaximumMinimum$         0$11,70050%$1,250$40011,70015,900401,00035015,90019,7003075025019,70023,6002050015023,60028,9001025015028,900NoneUnmarried Homeowners$         0$11,70040%$1,000$35011,70015,9003075025015,90019,7002050015019,70023,6001025015023,600None</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <heading>Maximum amount of tax reduction</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Any homeowner qualified for tax reduction in accordance with subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section in an amount to be determined under the schedule of such tax reduction in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, shall in no event receive less in tax reduction than the minimum amount of such reduction applicable to the qualifying income of such homeowner according to the schedule in said subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <heading>Initial claim for tax reductions</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Biennial requirements. Penalty.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_e__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any claim for tax reduction under this section shall be submitted for approval, on the application form prepared for such purpose by the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management, in the first year claim for such tax relief is filed and biennially thereafter. Such application form may be submitted by mail or electronic mail, in a manner prescribed by the secretary. The amount of tax reduction approved shall be applied to the real property tax payable by the homeowner for the assessment year in which such application is submitted and approved. If any such homeowner has qualified for tax reduction under this section, the tax reduction determined shall, when possible, be applied and prorated uniformly over the number of installments in which the real property tax is due and payable to the municipality in which such homeowner resides. In the case of any homeowner who is eligible for tax reduction under this section as a result of increases in qualifying income, under the schedule of qualifying income and tax reduction in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, exclusive of any such increases related to Social Security adjustments in accordance with subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, the total amount of tax reduction to which such homeowner is entitled shall be credited and uniformly prorated against property tax installment payments applicable to such homeowner's residence that become due after such homeowner's application for tax reduction under this section is accepted. In the event that a homeowner has paid in full the amount of property tax applicable to such homeowner's residence, regardless of whether the municipality requires the payment of property taxes in one or more installments, such municipality shall make payment to such homeowner in the amount of the tax reduction allowed. The municipality shall be reimbursed for the amount of such payment in accordance with subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_g__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In respect to such application required biennially after the filing and approval for the first year, the tax assessor in each municipality shall notify each such homeowner concerning application requirements by mail or, at such homeowner's option, electronic mail, not later than February first, annually enclosing a copy of the required application form. Such homeowner may submit such application to the assessor by mail or electronic mail, in a manner prescribed by the assessor, provided it is received by the assessor not later than April fifteenth in the assessment year with respect to which such tax reduction is claimed. Not later than April thirtieth of such year the assessor shall notify, by mail evidenced by a certificate of mailing, any such homeowner for whom such application was not received by said April fifteenth concerning application requirements and such homeowner shall be required not later than May fifteenth to submit such application personally or by electronic mail, in a manner prescribed by the assessor, or, for reasonable cause, by a person acting on behalf of such taxpayer as approved by the assessor. In the year immediately following any year in which such homeowner has submitted application and qualified for tax reduction in accordance with this section, such homeowner shall be presumed, without filing application therefor, to be qualified for tax reduction in accordance with the schedule in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section in the same percentage of property tax as allowed in the year immediately preceding.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_c__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If any homeowner has qualified and received tax reduction under this section and subsequently in any calendar year has qualifying income in excess of the maximum described in this section, such homeowner shall notify the tax assessor by mail or electronic mail, in a manner prescribed by the assessor, on or before the next filing date and shall be denied tax reduction under this section for the assessment year and any subsequent year or until such homeowner has reapplied and again qualified for benefits under this section. Any such person who fails to so notify the tax assessor of his disqualification shall refund all amounts of tax reduction improperly taken and be fined not more than five hundred dollars.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <heading>Proof of claim requirements</heading>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_f__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any homeowner, believing such homeowner is entitled to tax reduction benefits under this section for any assessment year, shall make application as required in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, to the assessor of the municipality in which the homeowner resides, for such tax reduction at any time from February first to and including May fifteenth of the year in which tax reduction is claimed. A homeowner may make application to the secretary prior to August fifteenth of the claim year for an extension of the application period. The secretary may grant such extension in the case of extenuating circumstance due to illness or incapacitation as evidenced by a certificate signed by a physician, physician assistant or an advanced practice registered nurse to that extent, or if the secretary determines there is good cause for doing so. Such application for tax reduction benefits shall be submitted on a form prescribed and furnished by the secretary to the assessor. In making application the homeowner shall present to such assessor, in substantiation of such homeowner's application, a copy of such homeowner's federal income tax return, including a copy of the Social Security statement of earnings for such homeowner, and that of such homeowner's spouse, if filed separately, for such homeowner's taxable year ending immediately prior to the submission of such application, or if not required to file a return, such other evidence of qualifying income in respect to such taxable year as may be required by the assessor.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_e__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the assessor is satisfied that the applying homeowner is entitled to tax reduction in accordance with this section, such assessor shall issue a certificate of credit, in such form as the secretary may prescribe and supply showing the amount of tax reduction allowed. A duplicate of such certificate shall be delivered to the applicant and the tax collector of the municipality and the assessor shall keep the fourth copy of such certificate and a copy of the application. Any homeowner who, for the purpose of obtaining a tax reduction under this section, wilfully fails to disclose all matters related thereto or with intent to defraud makes false statement shall refund all property tax credits improperly taken and shall be fined not more than five hundred dollars.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_e__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Applications filed under this section shall not be open for public inspection.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <heading>State reimbursement for loss of property tax</heading>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_g__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>On or before July first, annually, each municipality shall submit to the secretary a claim for the tax reductions approved under this section in relation to the assessment list of October first immediately preceding. On or after December first, annually, any municipality that neglects to transmit to the secretary the claim as required by this section shall forfeit two hundred fifty dollars to the state, except that the secretary may waive such forfeiture in accordance with procedures and standards established by regulations adopted in accordance with chapter 54.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_g__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Subject to procedures for review and approval of such data pursuant to section12-120b, said secretary shall, on or before December fifteenth next following, certify to the Comptroller the amount due each municipality as reimbursement for loss of property tax revenue related to the tax reductions allowed under this section, except that the secretary may reduce the amount due as reimbursement under this section by up to one hundred per cent for any municipality that is not eligible for a grant under section32-9s. The Comptroller shall draw an order on the Treasurer on or before the fifth business day following December fifteenth and the Treasurer shall pay the amount due each municipality not later than the thirty-first day of December.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_g__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any claimant aggrieved by the results of the secretary's review shall have the rights of appeal as set forth in section12-120b. The amount of the grant payable to each municipality in any year in accordance with this section shall be reduced proportionately in the event that the total of such grants in such year exceeds the amount appropriated for the purposes of this section with respect to such year.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <heading>Residential dwelling on leased land</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Property taxes paid by the owner of the dwelling.Any person who is the owner of a residential dwelling on leased land, including any such person who is a sublessee under terms of the lease agreement applicable to such land, shall be entitled to claim tax relief under the provisions of this section, subject to all requirements therein except as provided in this subsection, with respect to property taxes paid by such person on the assessed value of such dwelling, provided</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_h__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the dwelling is such person's principal place of residence,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_h__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>such lease or sublease requires that such person as the lessee or sublessee, whichever is applicable, pay all property taxes related to the dwelling, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_h__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>such lease or sublease is recorded in the land records of the town.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <heading>Pro rata tax reduction for assessment year in which property is transferred</heading>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_i__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If any person with respect to whom a claim for tax reduction in accordance with this section has been approved for any assessment year transfers, assigns, grants or otherwise conveys on or after the first day of October but prior to the first day of August in such assessment year the interest in real property to which such claim for tax credit is related, regardless of whether such transfer, assignment, grant or conveyance is voluntary or involuntary, the amount of such tax credit shall be a pro rata portion of the amount otherwise applicable in such assessment year to be determined by a fraction the numerator of which shall be the number of full months from the first day of October in such assessment year to the date of such conveyance and the denominator of which shall be twelve. If such conveyance occurs in the month of October the grantor shall be disqualified for tax credit in such assessment year. The grantee shall be required within a period not exceeding ten days immediately following the date of such conveyance to notify the assessor thereof by mail or electronic mail, in a manner prescribed by the assessor, or in the absence of such notice, upon determination by the assessor that such transfer, assignment, grant or conveyance has occurred, the assessor shall (A) determine the amount of tax reduction to which the grantor is entitled for such assessment year with respect to the interest in real property conveyed and notify the tax collector of the reduced amount of tax reduction applicable to such interest, and (B) notify the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management on or before the October first immediately following the end of the assessment year in which such conveyance occurs of the reduction in such tax reduction for purposes of a corresponding adjustment in the amount of state payment to the municipality next following as reimbursement for the revenue loss related to such tax reductions. On or after December first, annually, any municipality th</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_i__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>determine the amount of tax reduction to which the grantor is entitled for such assessment year with respect to the interest in real property conveyed and notify the tax collector of the reduced amount of tax reduction applicable to such interest, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_i__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>notify the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management on or before the October first immediately following the end of the assessment year in which such conveyance occurs of the reduction in such tax reduction for purposes of a corresponding adjustment in the amount of state payment to the municipality next following as reimbursement for the revenue loss related to such tax reductions. On or after December first, annually, any municipality that neglects to transmit to the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management the claim as required by this section shall forfeit two hundred fifty dollars to the state except that the secretary may waive such forfeiture in accordance with procedures and standards established by regulations adopted in accordance with chapter 54.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_i__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Upon receipt of such notice from the assessor, the tax collector shall, if such notice is received after the tax due date in the municipality, not later than thirty days after such receipt, mail, hand or deliver by electronic mail, at the grantee's option, a bill to the grantee stating the additional amount of tax due as determined by the assessor. Such tax shall be due and payable and collectible as other property taxes and subject to the same liens and processes of collection, provided such tax shall be due and payable in an initial or single installment not sooner than thirty days after the date such bill is mailed or handed to the grantee and in equal amounts in any remaining, regular installments as the same are due and payable.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_j">
            <num>(j)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Benefits for persons without ownership or leasehold interest in real property who reside in multiple-dwelling complex.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_j__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding the intent in subsections</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, inclusive, of this section to provide for benefits in the form of property tax reduction applicable to persons liable for payment of such property tax and qualified in accordance with requirements related to age and income as provided in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, a certain annual benefit, determined in amount under the provisions of subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section but payable in a manner as prescribed in this subsection, shall be provided with respect to any person who (A) is qualified in accordance with said requirements related to age and income as provided in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, including provisions concerning such person's spouse, and (B) is a resident of a dwelling unit within a multiple-dwelling complex containing dwelling units for occupancy by certain elderly persons under terms of a contract between such resident and the owner of such complex, in accordance with which contract such resident occupies a certain dwelling unit subject to the express provision that such resident has no legal title, interest or leasehold estate in the real or personal property of such complex, and under the terms of which contract such resident agrees to pay the owner of the complex a fee, as a condition precedent to occupancy and a monthly or other such periodic fee thereafter as a condition of continued occupancy. In no event shall any such resident be qualified for benefits payable in accordance with this subsection if, as determined by the assessor in the municipality in which such complex is situated, such resident's contract with the owner of such complex, or occupancy by such resident</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>confers upon such resident any ownership interest in the dwelling unit occupied or in such complex, or (ii) establishes a contract of lease of any type for the dwelling unit occupied by such resident.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_i__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The amount of annual benefit payable in accordance with this subsection to any such resident, qualified as provided in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_i__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, shall be determined in relation to an assumed amount of property tax liability applicable to the assessed value for the dwelling unit which such resident occupies, as determined by the assessor in the municipality in which such complex is situated. Annually, not later than the first day of June, the assessor in such municipality, upon receipt of an application for such benefit submitted in accordance with this subsection by mail or electronic mail, in a manner prescribed by the assessor, by any such resident, shall determine, with respect to the assessment list in such municipality for the assessment year commencing October first immediately preceding, the portion of the assessed value of the entire complex, as included in such assessment list, attributable to the dwelling unit occupied by such resident. The assumed property tax liability for purposes of this subsection shall be the product of such assessed value and the mill rate in such municipality as determined for purposes of property tax imposed on said assessment list for the assessment year commencing October first immediately preceding. The amount of benefit to which such resident shall be entitled for such assessment year shall be equivalent to the amount of tax reduction for which such resident would qualify, considering such assumed property tax liability to be the actual property tax applicable to such resident's dwelling unit and such resident as liable for the payment of such tax, in accordance with the schedule of qualifying income and tax reduction as provided in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, subject to provisions concerning maximum allowable benefit for any assessment year under subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section. The amount of benefit as determined for such resident in respect to any assessment year shall be payable by the state as a grant to such resident equivalent to the amount of property tax reduction to which such resident would be entitled under subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, inclusive, of this section if such resident were the owner of such dwelling unit and qualified for tax reduction benefits under said subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, inclusive.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_i__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any such resident entitled to a grant as provided in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_i__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection shall be required to submit an application to the assessor in the municipality in which such resident resides for such grant by mail or electronic mail, in a manner prescribed by the assessor, at any time from February first to and including the fifteenth day of May in the year in which such grant is claimed, on a form prescribed and furnished for such purpose by the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management. Any such resident submitting an application for such grant shall be required to present to the assessor, in substantiation of such application, a copy of such resident's federal income tax return, and if not required to file a federal income tax return, such other evidence of qualifying income, receipts for money received or cancelled checks, or copies thereof, and any other evidence the assessor may require. Not later than the first day of July in such year, the assessor shall submit to the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management (A) a copy of the application prepared by such resident, together with such resident's federal income tax return, if required to file such a return, and any other information submitted in relation thereto, (B) determinations of the assessor concerning the assessed value of the dwelling unit in such complex occupied by such resident, and (C) the amount of such grant approved by the assessor. Said secretary, upon approving such grant, shall certify the amount thereof and not later than the fifteenth day of September immediately following submit approval for payment of such grant to the State Comptroller. Not later than five business days immediately following receipt of such approval for payment, the State Comptroller shall draw an order on the State Treasurer and the Treasurer shall pay the amount of the grant to such resident not later than the first day of October immediately following.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_i__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a copy of the application prepared by such resident, together with such resident's federal income tax return, if required to file such a return, and any other information submitted in relation thereto,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_i__subsec_2__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>determinations of the assessor concerning the assessed value of the dwelling unit in such complex occupied by such resident, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_170aa__subsec_i__subsec_2__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the amount of such grant approved by the assessor. Said secretary, upon approving such grant, shall certify the amount thereof and not later than the fifteenth day of September immediately following submit approval for payment of such grant to the State Comptroller. Not later than five business days immediately following receipt of such approval for payment, the State Comptroller shall draw an order on the State Treasurer and the Treasurer shall pay the amount of the grant to such resident not later than the first day of October immediately following.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_170aa__subsec_k">
            <num>(k)</num>
            <heading>Adjustments</heading>
            <content>
              <p>If the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management makes any adjustments to the grants for tax reductions or assumed amounts of property tax liability claimed under this section subsequent to the State Comptroller's order of payment of grants in any year, the amount of such adjustment shall be reflected in the next payment the Treasurer shall make to such municipality pursuant to this section.
See Sec. 12-120b re uniform administrative procedure for appeals related to state-reimbursed property tax exemptions, credits and rebates.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>