<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-574"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-574"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-574"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-574/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-574/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-574/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-574/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_226">
        <num>226</num>
        <heading>Prepared Food and Beverage Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_574">
          <num>12-574</num>
          <heading>Licensing</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <heading>Association licensees</heading>
            <content>
              <p>No person or business organization may conduct a meeting at which racing or the exhibition of jai alai is permitted for any stake, purse or reward or operate the off-track betting system unless such person or business organization is licensed as an association licensee by the commissioner. Any such licensee authorized to conduct a meeting or operate the off-track betting system shall indemnify and save harmless the state of Connecticut against any and all actions, claims, and demands of whatever kind or nature which the state may sustain or incur by reason or in consequence of issuing such license.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <heading>Concessionaire licensees</heading>
            <content>
              <p>No person or business organization may operate any concession at any meeting at which racing or the exhibition of jai alai is permitted or any concession which is allied to an off-track betting facility unless such person or business organization is licensed as a concessionaire licensee by the commissioner.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <heading>Vendor licensees</heading>
            <content>
              <p>No person or business organization awarded the primary contract by an association licensee to provide facilities, components, goods or services which are necessary for the operation of the activities authorized by the provisions of section12-572may do so unless such person or business organization is licensed as a vendor licensee by the commissioner.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <heading>Totalizator licensees</heading>
            <content>
              <p>No person or business organization may provide totalizator equipment and services to any association licensee for the operation of a pari-mutuel system unless such person or business organization is licensed as a totalizator licensee by the commissioner.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <heading>Affiliate licensees</heading>
            <content>
              <p>No business organization, other than a shareholder in a publicly traded corporation, may exercise control in or over an association, a concessionaire, a vendor or a totalizator licensee unless such business organization is licensed as an affiliate licensee by the commissioner. The commissioner shall issue affiliate licenses to qualified business organizations.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <heading>Occupational licensees</heading>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_f__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>No person may participate in this state in any activity permitted under this chapter as an employee of an association, concessionaire, vendor, totalizator or affiliate licensee unless such person is licensed as an occupational licensee by the commissioner under subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_f__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-578. Whether located in or out of this state, no officer, director, partner, trustee or owner of a business organization which obtains a license in accordance with this section may continue in such capacity unless such officer, director, partner, trustee or owner is licensed as an occupational licensee by the commissioner as an owner under subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-578. An occupational license shall also be obtained by any shareholder, key executive, agent or other person connected with any association, concessionaire, vendor, totalizator or affiliate licensee, who in the judgment of the commissioner will exercise control in or over any such licensee. Such person shall apply for a license not later than thirty days after the commissioner requests such person, in writing, to do so as a pari-mutuel employee under subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-578. The commissioner shall complete his investigation of an applicant for an occupational license and notify such applicant of his decision to approve or deny the application within one year after its receipt, or, if the commissioner determines good cause exists for extending such period of investigation and gives the applicant a reasonable opportunity for a hearing, by the date prescribed by the commissioner.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Upon petition by the holder of an association, vendor, totalizator or affiliate license, the commissioner may authorize an applicant for an occupational license under subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-578to provisionally perform the work permitted under the occupational license applied for, if:
(A) The applicant has filed a completed application for such occupational license in the form and manner required by the commissioner, and
(B) Such association, vendor, totalizator or affiliate licensee attests that the provisional authorization is necessary to continue the efficient operation of pari-mutuel wagering, and is based on circumstances that are extraordinary and not designed to circumvent the otherwise applicable licensing procedures.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commissioner may issue a provisional authorization to an applicant for an occupational license under subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-578in advance of issuance or denial of such occupational license for such applicant for a period not to exceed six months. Provisional authorization shall permit such applicant to perform the functions and require the applicant to comply with the requirements of the occupational license applied for as set forth in the provisions of this chapter and regulations adopted pursuant to this chapter. Provisional authorization shall not constitute approval for an occupational license under subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-578. During the period of time that any provisional authorization is in effect, the applicant granted such authorization shall be subject to and comply with all applicable statutes and regulations. Any provisional authorization issued by the commissioner shall expire immediately upon the earlier of: (A) The date of issuance of written notice from the commissioner that the occupational license has been approved or denied, or (B) six months after the date the provisional authorization was issued.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An individual whose occupational license application is denied after a period of provisional authorization shall not reapply for an occupational license under subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-578for a period of one year from the date of the denial.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_a__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An individual whose provisional authorization expires pursuant to subparagraph (B) of subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_574__subsec_a__subsec_5__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection may apply for an additional provisional authorization. The commissioner may issue such additional provisional authorization upon a determination that the conditions of subparagraph (B) of subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_574__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection exist.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <heading>Information required for licensing</heading>
            <content>
              <p>In determining whether to grant a license, the commissioner may require the applicant to submit information as to: Financial standing and credit; moral character; criminal record, if any; previous employment; corporate, partnership or association affiliations; ownership of personal assets; and such other information as it or he deems pertinent to the issuance of such license.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <heading>Licensing and regulation of licensees by commissioner</heading>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner may reject for good cause an application for a license. Any license granted under the provisions of this chapter is a revocable privilege and no licensee shall be deemed to have acquired any vested rights based on the issuance of such license. The commissioner, the deputy commissioner, the executive assistant, any unit head or any assistant unit head authorized by the commissioner may suspend or revoke for good cause any license issued by the commissioner after a hearing held in accordance with chapter 54. If any affiliate licensee fails to comply with the provisions of this chapter, the commissioner, after a hearing held in accordance with chapter 54, may revoke or suspend the license of any one or more of the following related licensees: Concessionaire, vendor or totalizator, and may fine any one or more of such licensees in an amount not to exceed two thousand five hundred dollars. In addition, if any affiliate licensee fails to comply with the provisions of this chapter, the commissioner, after a hearing held in accordance with chapter 54, may revoke or suspend the license of the related association licensee and may fine the related association licensee in an amount not to exceed seventy-five thousand dollars or both. If any license is suspended or revoked, the commissioner shall state the reasons for such suspension or revocation and cause an entry of such reasons to be made on the record books of the department. Any licensee whose license is suspended or revoked, or any applicant aggrieved by the action of the commissioner concerning an application for a license, may appeal pursuant to section4-183.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <heading>Regulations governing licensee's operation</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Penalties, hearings and appeals.The commissioner shall adopt regulations governing the operation of the off-track betting system and facilities, tracks, stables and frontons, including the regulation of betting in connection therewith, to ensure the integrity and security of the conduct of meetings and the broadcast of racing events held pursuant to this chapter. Such regulations shall include provision for the imposition of fines and suspension of licenses for violations thereof. The commissioner shall have the authority to impose a fine of up to</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_i__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>seventy-five thousand dollars for any violation of such regulations by a licensee authorized to conduct a meeting or operate the off-track betting system under this section;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_i__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>five thousand dollars for any violation of such regulations by a business organization licensed as an affiliate licensee authorized to exercise control over an association; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_574__subsec_i__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>two thousand five hundred dollars for any such violation by any other licensee licensed by the commissioner. The stewards or judges of a meeting acting in accordance with such regulations shall have the authority to impose a fine of up to five hundred dollars for any such violation by such licensee, and the players' manager of a jai alai exhibition acting in accordance with such regulations shall have the authority to recommend to the judges that a fine should be considered for a player who may have violated such regulations. The commissioner may delegate to the stewards and judges of a meeting the power to suspend the license of any occupational licensee employed in this state by an association licensee for a period not to exceed sixty days for any violation of such regulations. If any license is suspended, such stewards and judges of a meeting shall state the reasons therefor in writing. All fines imposed pursuant to this section shall be paid over to the General Fund upon receipt by the department. Any person or business organization fined or suspended pursuant to this section shall have a right of appeal to the commissioner for a hearing that shall be conducted pursuant to chapter 54. Any person or business organization aggrieved by a decision of the commissioner following such a hearing shall have a right of appeal pursuant to section4-183.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_j">
            <num>(j)</num>
            <heading>Preparation, maintenance and inspection of books and records</heading>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner may require that the books and records of any licensee, other than an occupational licensee, be maintained in any manner which the commissioner may deem best, and that any financial or other statements based on such books and records be prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles in such form as the commissioner shall prescribe. The commissioner or the commissioner's designee shall also be authorized to visit, to investigate and to place expert accountants and such other persons as the commissioner may deem necessary, in the offices, tracks, frontons, off-track betting facilities or places of business of any such licensee, for the purpose of satisfying the commissioner or such designee that the department's regulations are strictly complied with.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_k">
            <num>(k)</num>
            <heading>Removal of employee or official of licensee</heading>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner may at any time for good cause require the removal of any employee or official employed by any licensee under this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_l">
            <num>(l)</num>
            <heading>Licensing exemptions</heading>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner may, on the commissioner's own motion or upon application, exempt any person or business organization from the licensing requirements of this chapter or some or all of the disclosure requirements of chapter 226b, provided the applicant does not exercise control in or over an integral part of any activity which is authorized under this chapter. The burden of proving that an exemption should be granted rests solely with the applicant. The commissioner may limit or condition the terms of an exemption and such determination shall be final.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_m">
            <num>(m)</num>
            <heading>Penalty for aiding operation of off-track betting system or meeting without license</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Any person aiding or abetting in the operation of an off-track betting system or the conduct of any meeting within this state at which racing or the exhibition of the game of jai alai shall be permitted for any stake, purse or reward, except in accordance with a license duly issued and unsuspended or unrevoked by the commissioner, shall be guilty of a class A misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_n">
            <num>(n)</num>
            <heading>Residency requirement</heading>
            <content>
              <p>The majority of the membership of the board of directors of any corporation licensed to operate the off-track betting system or to hold or conduct any meeting within the state of Connecticut at which racing or the exhibition of the game of jai alai shall be permitted for any stake, purse or reward, shall be residents of the state of Connecticut.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_o">
            <num>(o)</num>
            <heading>License application and renewal</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Any license granted under this section, other than an association license authorizing the licensee to conduct a meeting or operate the off-track betting system, as described in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, or an affiliate license authorizing the licensee to exercise control in or over an association licensee, as described in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_574__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, shall be effective for not more than one year from the date of issuance. Initial application for and renewal of any license shall be in such form and manner as the commissioner shall prescribe by regulation.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>