<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-112h"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-112h"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-112h"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-112h/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-112h/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-112h/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-112h/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319s">
        <num>319s</num>
        <heading>Connecticut Partnership for Long-Term Care</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_112h">
          <num>17b-112h</num>
          <heading>Disbursement of federal funds received from Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Emergency Contingency Fund</heading>
          <subsection eId="17b_112h__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the fiscal year ending June 30, 2010, and each fiscal year thereafter, the Commissioner of Social Services shall disburse all federal funds received by the Department of Social Services for benefits or services previously provided that qualify for reimbursement under the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Emergency Contingency Fund provision of Section 403 of the Social Security Act as follows:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_112h__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Commissioner of Social Services shall deposit any funds received for reimbursement for expenditures not originally funded from the General Fund in the General Fund. Such funds shall be credited to a nonlapsing account in the Department of Social Services. Eighty per cent of the first two hundred fifty thousand dollars of such funds provided as reimbursement for benefits or services previously provided by a service provider using funding sources other than the General Fund shall be paid to each provider of such benefits or services for the purpose of providing additional benefits or services under the temporary assistance for needy families program, as approved by the department. The remaining twenty per cent of such reimbursed funds shall be deposited into the General Fund as revenue. Any such reimbursement in excess of two hundred fifty thousand dollars per service provider shall be shared equally between the service provider and the state. The service provider's share shall be used to provide additional benefits or services under the state's temporary assistance for needy families program, as approved by the department. The state's share of any such reimbursement shall be deposited into the General Fund as revenue and shall be used for any purpose permitted under the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Program pursuant to Section 403</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_112h__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the Social Security Act.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_112h__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Commissioner of Social Services shall deposit any funds received for reimbursement for expenditures originally funded from the General Fund through a contract with a human service provider in the General Fund. Such funds shall be credited to a nonlapsing account in the Department of Social Services. Thirty per cent of such funds provided as reimbursement for benefits or services previously provided shall be paid to each provider of such benefits or services for the purpose of providing additional benefits or services under the temporary assistance for needy families program, as approved by the department. The remaining seventy per cent of such reimbursement shall be deposited into the General Fund as revenue and shall be used for any purpose permitted under the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Program pursuant to Section 403</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_112h__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the Social Security Act.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_112h__subsec_c__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivisions</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_112h__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_112h__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, the Commissioner of Social Services shall deposit any funds for reimbursement received by the Department of Social Services for prior expenditures for subsidized employment services provided under the Jobs First program, in the General Fund. Such funds shall be credited to a nonlapsing account in the Department of Social Services. The commissioner shall use such funds to fund additional subsidized employment services under the temporary assistance for needy families program.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_112h__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the fiscal year ending June 30, 2010, and each fiscal year thereafter, the Commissioner of Social Services shall deposit all federal funds received by the Department of Social Services as an advance payment of the eighty per cent federal share for benefits and services to be provided under the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Emergency Contingency Fund provision of Section 403 of the Social Security Act for expenditures not funded from the General Fund in the General Fund. Such funds shall be credited to a nonlapsing account in the Department of Social Services. Such funds shall be used to pay for benefits or services under the temporary assistance for needy families program, for programs operated by service providers that qualify under the provisions of Section 403 of the Social Security Act, as approved by the department, and for which the service provider provides the twenty per cent nonfederal share of such program's cost. Any advance payment of the eighty per cent federal share for benefits and services to be provided under the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Emergency Contingency Fund provision of Section 403 of the Social Security Act for expenditures to be funded from the General Fund shall be deposited in the General Fund as revenue and shall be used for any purpose permitted under the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Program pursuant to Section 403</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_112h__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the Social Security Act.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_112h__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Social Services shall designate and contract with a fiscal intermediary to administer the distribution of funds to service providers under this section. The commissioner shall pay the costs associated with such contract from</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_112h__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the federal Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Emergency Contingency Fund advance payments and the service provider's twenty per cent nonfederal share of the program's cost on a proportionate basis,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_112h__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the federal Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Emergency Contingency Fund reimbursement revenue, notwithstanding the provisions of subdivisions</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_112h__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_112h__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_112h__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, or</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_112h__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>funding sources available to the Department of Social Services other than the General Fund.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>