<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-81"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-81"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-81"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-81/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-81/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-81/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-81/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319s">
        <num>319s</num>
        <heading>Connecticut Partnership for Long-Term Care</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_81">
          <num>17b-81</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-82e). Investigations of legally liable relatives by commissioner</heading>
          <subsection eId="17b_81__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall investigate the financial condition of each legally liable relative, as defined in section4a-12, and shall make a determination as to the financial ability of each such relative in accordance with the uniform contribution scale established by the Commissioner of Administrative Services in accordance with said section4a-12, and shall notify in writing each such relative of the amount each is found able to contribute toward such support, and each such relative shall be liable in said amount from the date of such notice, retroactive to the date of granting of assistance, unless and until such support responsibility shall be otherwise fixed by a court of competent jurisdiction. When any finding or written agreement to support, or any modification thereof is made with the commissioner by the liable relative and is filed with the clerk of the superior court for the judicial district in which the applicant, recipient, beneficiary or liable relative resides, or the assistant clerk of the Family Support Magistrate Division in the judicial district where the applicant resides, such agreement shall have the same force and effect as an order of support by said court, and shall be enforceable in the same manner as orders of support issued by said court or a family support magistrate, provided any court of competent jurisdiction, or a family support magistrate, called upon to enforce such agreement, including a finding consented to by the relative, after notice to all parties, shall fully review such determination as to financial ability and shall insure that such determination is reasonable in light of the relative's ability to pay and may modify such finding prospectively, retroactively or both. Such determination shall not be affected by appeal but shall continue in effect, until the appeal is denied, or unless changed by order of the court or family support magistrate. The commissioner shall periodically reinvestigate the financial condition of such rel</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_81__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Social Services shall continue to independently determine parental support obligations under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_81__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section17b-179, notwithstanding the uniform contribution scale developed pursuant to section4a-12. The commissioner shall promulgate support guidelines for such cases.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_81__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Social Services shall determine a legally liable relative contribution for the spouse of an institutionalized recipient of Medicaid only when such spouse has income in excess of</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_81__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the minimum monthly needs allowance or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_81__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the monthly needs allowance for such spouse as determined by the commissioner, through a fair hearing or court proceeding. The amount of such contribution shall not cause the income of such spouse to fall below said minimum monthly needs allowance or said monthly needs allowance for such spouse as determined by the commissioner, through a fair hearing or court proceeding. The spouse of an institutionalized individual, for whom a legally liable relative contribution is determined, may request a fair hearing regarding the amount of the contribution.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>