<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-131"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-131"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-131"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-131/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-131/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-131/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-131/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319s">
        <num>319s</num>
        <heading>Connecticut Partnership for Long-Term Care</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_131">
          <num>17b-131</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-286). Funeral and burial allowance for indigent persons or beneficiaries under the state-administered general assistance program. Reductions. Disclosure of information regarding liquid assets</heading>
          <subsection eId="17b_131__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When a person in any town, or sent from such town to any licensed institution or state humane institution, dies or is found dead therein and does not leave sufficient estate and has no legally liable relative able to pay the cost of a proper funeral and burial, or upon the death of any beneficiary under the state-administered general assistance program, the Commissioner of Social Services shall give to such person a proper funeral and burial, and shall pay a sum not exceeding one thousand eight hundred dollars as an allowance toward the funeral expenses of such decedent. Said sum shall be paid, upon submission of a proper bill, to the funeral director, cemetery or crematory, as the case may be. Such payment for funeral and burial expenses shall be reduced by</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_131__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the amount in any revocable or irrevocable funeral fund,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_131__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>any prepaid funeral contract,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_131__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the face value of any life insurance policy owned by the decedent that names a funeral home, cemetery or crematory as a beneficiary,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_131__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the net value of all liquid assets in the decedent's estate, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_131__subsec_a__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>contributions in excess of three thousand four hundred dollars toward such funeral and burial expenses from all other sources including friends, relatives and all other persons, organizations, agencies, veterans' programs and other benefit programs. Notwithstanding the provisions of section17b-90, whenever payment for funeral, burial or cremation expenses is reduced due to liquid assets in the decedent's estate, the commissioner may disclose information concerning such liquid assets to the funeral director, cemetery or crematory providing funeral, burial or cremation services for the decedent.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_131__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_131__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section and section17b-84, the Commissioner of Social Services shall, upon submission of a proper bill, pay the maximum amount authorized under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_131__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section to a funeral director, cemetery or crematory if the Chief Medical Examiner, or the Chief Medical Examiner's designee, certifies that, after an investigation, the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner was unable to locate any person with a connection to the decedent, including a relative or friend, who was willing to take possession of the decedent's remains, and that the decedent's remains were therefore transferred to such funeral director, cemetery or crematory for disposition.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_131__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Social Services may adopt regulations, in accordance with chapter 54, to implement the provisions of this section.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>