<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-177"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-177"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-177"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-177/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-177/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-177/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-177/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_205">
        <num>205</num>
        <heading>Tax Liens</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_177">
          <num>12-177</num>
          <heading>Certificates continuing tax liens; ordinances in certain large municipalities</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-177. Certificates continuing tax liens; ordinances in certain large municipalities.Any town having a population of more than one hundred thousand as shown by the last United States census and any municipality coterminous with or within any such town may enact an ordinance, specifying the manner by which certificates continuing tax liens shall, without copying and after binding, be incorporated into the land records of such town, provided, directly after each certificate of continuance of a tax lien, a vacant space shall be left for the release, in due course, of such tax lien. Such ordinance may specify the forms of certificates of continuance and of release of tax liens, the number of such certificates of continuance and of release to appear on each page and the form, method and time of binding of such pages into one or more tax lien books for the land records of such town. Any action so taken may be amended, rescinded or otherwise altered at any time by the enactment of a supplementary ordinance. Each such ordinance shall be a matter of public record and shall not be applicable until thirty days from the date of its enactment. The tax collector or other agency authorized by law of any town or municipality proceeding under this section shall continue tax liens by certificate in the manner and form prescribed by the latest applicable ordinance and shall within the time limited by law, file such certificates with the proper town clerk. The town clerk shall forthwith index such certificates in the index records of his office and shall, if such original certificates are not already bound, bind them into one or more volumes, which shall constitute a part of the land records in his office. While such certificates are being so bound, the reference to any such tax lien in the index records of the office of the town clerk shall constitute a sufficient notice to all parties as to the existence and priority of such lien. Such tax collector or other agency authorized by law shall make out a certificate releasing any such tax lien when the total amount represented by such lien has been paid or otherwise legally disposed of. Each such certificate of release shall be filed with the town clerk, who shall record such release in the space provided therefor directly after the applicable certificate of continuance. All such certificates of release shall be preserved by the town clerk. Except as provided in this section, all provisions of the statutes and of relevant special acts relating to tax liens shall continue to apply to all towns and municipalities.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>