<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217ii"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217ii"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-217ii"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217ii/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217ii/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217ii/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217ii/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_208">
        <num>208</num>
        <heading>Estate Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_217ii">
          <num>12-217ii</num>
          <heading>Jobs creation tax credit program. No eligibility certificates issued on or after January 1, 2012</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_217ii__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of Economic and Community Development;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Income year” means, with respect to entities subject to the insurance premiums tax under chapter 207, the corporation business tax under this chapter or the utility companies tax under chapter 212, the income year as determined under each of said chapters, as the case may be;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Taxpayer” means a person subject to tax under chapter 207, this chapter or chapter 212;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“New job” means a full-time job which (A) did not exist in this state prior to a taxpayer's application to the commissioner for an eligibility certificate under this section for a job creation credit, and (B) is filled by a new employee;</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_a__subsec_4__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>did not exist in this state prior to a taxpayer's application to the commissioner for an eligibility certificate under this section for a job creation credit, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_a__subsec_4__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>is filled by a new employee;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_a__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“New employee” means a person hired by the taxpayer to fill a new full-time job. A new employee does not include a person who was employed in Connecticut by a related person with respect to the taxpayer during the prior twelve months;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_a__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Full-time job” means a job in which an employee is required to work at least thirty-five or more hours per week. A full-time job does not include a temporary or seasonal job;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_a__subsec_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Related person” means (A) a corporation, limited liability company, partnership, association or trust controlled by the taxpayer, (B) an individual, corporation, limited liability company, partnership, association or trust that is in control of the taxpayer, (C) a corporation, limited liability company, partnership, association or trust controlled by an individual, corporation, limited liability company, partnership, association or trust that is in control of the taxpayer, or (D) a member of the same controlled group as the taxpayer; and</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_a__subsec_7__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a corporation, limited liability company, partnership, association or trust controlled by the taxpayer,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_a__subsec_7__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>an individual, corporation, limited liability company, partnership, association or trust that is in control of the taxpayer,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_a__subsec_7__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a corporation, limited liability company, partnership, association or trust controlled by an individual, corporation, limited liability company, partnership, association or trust that is in control of the taxpayer, or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_a__subsec_7__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a member of the same controlled group as the taxpayer; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_a__subsec_8">
              <num>(8)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Control”, with respect to a corporation, means ownership, directly or indirectly, of stock possessing fifty per cent or more of the total combined voting power of all classes of the stock of such corporation entitled to vote. “Control”, with respect to a trust, means ownership, directly or indirectly, of fifty per cent or more of the beneficial interest in the principal or income of such trust. The ownership of stock in a corporation, of a capital or profits interest in a partnership, limited liability company or association or of a beneficial interest in a trust shall be determined in accordance with the rules for constructive ownership of stock provided in Section 267</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217ii__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or any subsequent corresponding internal revenue code of the United States, as from time to time amended, other than paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_c__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of said Section 267</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217ii__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217ii__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>There is established a jobs creation tax credit program whereby a taxpayer who creates at least ten new jobs in Connecticut may be allowed a credit against the tax imposed under chapter 207, this chapter or chapter 212, in an amount up to sixty per cent of the income tax deducted and withheld from the wages of new employees and paid over to the state pursuant to chapter 229.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For each new employee, credits may be granted for five successive years.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The credit shall be claimed in the income year in which it is earned. Any credits not used in a tax year shall expire.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217ii__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any taxpayer planning to claim a credit under the provisions of this section shall apply to the commissioner in accordance with the provisions of this section. The application shall be on a form provided by the commissioner, and shall contain sufficient information concerning the number of new jobs to be created, feasibility studies or business plans for the increased number of jobs, projected state and local revenue that might derive as a result of the job growth and other information necessary to demonstrate that there will be net benefits to the economy of the municipality and the state. The commissioner shall impose a fee for such application as the commissioner deems appropriate.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217ii__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall determine whether</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the taxpayer making the application is eligible for the tax credit, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the proposed job growth (A) is economically viable only with use of the tax credit, (B) would provide a net benefit to economic development and employment opportunities in the state, and (C) conforms to the state plan of conservation and development prepared pursuant to part I of chapter 297. The commissioner may require the applicant to submit such additional information as may be necessary to evaluate the application.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_d__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>is economically viable only with use of the tax credit,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_d__subsec_2__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>would provide a net benefit to economic development and employment opportunities in the state, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_d__subsec_2__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>conforms to the state plan of conservation and development prepared pursuant to part I of chapter 297. The commissioner may require the applicant to submit such additional information as may be necessary to evaluate the application.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217ii__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_e__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commissioner, upon consideration of the application and any additional information the commissioner requires, may approve the credit application, in whole or in part, if the commissioner concludes that the increase in the number of jobs is economically viable only with the use of the tax credit and that the revenue generated due to economic development and employment opportunities created in the state exceeds the credit and any other credits to be taken. If the commissioner disapproves an application, the commissioner shall specifically identify the defects in the application and specifically explain the reasons for the disapproval. The commissioner shall render a decision on an application not later than ninety days after the date of its receipt by the commissioner.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_e__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The total amount of credits granted to all taxpayers under this section and sections12-217nn,12-217ooand12-217ppshall not exceed twenty million dollars in any one fiscal year.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_e__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>(A) A credit under this section may be granted to a taxpayer for not more than five successive income years. No credit under this section shall be granted to a taxpayer more than five income years after the date the commissioner issues an eligibility certificate to the taxpayer under subsection</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_e__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A credit under this section may be granted to a taxpayer for not more than five successive income years. No credit under this section shall be granted to a taxpayer more than five income years after the date the commissioner issues an eligibility certificate to the taxpayer under subsection</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217ii__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.
(B) The commissioner shall not issue any eligibility certificates under this section on or after January 1, 2012.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_f__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commissioner may combine approval of a credit application with the exercise of any of the commissioner's other powers, including, but not limited to, the provision of other forms of financial assistance.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217ii__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon approving a taxpayer's credit application, the commissioner shall issue a credit allocation notice certifying that the credits will be available to be claimed by the taxpayer if the taxpayer otherwise meets the requirements of this section. No later than thirty days after the close of the taxpayer's income year, the taxpayer shall provide information to the commissioner regarding the number of new jobs created for the year and the income tax deducted and withheld from the wages of such new employees and paid over to the state for such year. The commissioner shall issue an eligibility certificate that includes the taxpayer's name, the number of new jobs created, and the amount of the credit certified for the year. The certificate shall be issued by the commissioner not later than sixty days after the close of the taxpayer's income year or not later than thirty days after the information is provided, whichever comes first.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217ii__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall, upon request, provide a copy of the eligibility certificate issued under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217ii__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section to the Commissioner of Revenue Services.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217ii__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_h__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If (A) the number of new employees on account of which a taxpayer claimed the credit allowed by this section decreases to less than the number for which the commissioner issued an eligibility certificate during any of the four years succeeding the first full income year following the issuance of an eligibility certificate, and (B) those employees are not replaced by other employees who have not been shifted from an existing location of the taxpayer or a related person in this state, the taxpayer shall be required to recapture a percentage of the credit allowed under this section on its tax return, as determined under the provisions of subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_h__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the number of new employees on account of which a taxpayer claimed the credit allowed by this section decreases to less than the number for which the commissioner issued an eligibility certificate during any of the four years succeeding the first full income year following the issuance of an eligibility certificate, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_h__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>those employees are not replaced by other employees who have not been shifted from an existing location of the taxpayer or a related person in this state, the taxpayer shall be required to recapture a percentage of the credit allowed under this section on its tax return, as determined under the provisions of subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_h__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection. The commissioner shall provide notice of the required recapture amount to both the taxpayer and the Commissioner of Revenue Services.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_h__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the taxpayer is required under the provisions of subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_h__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection to recapture a portion of the credit during (A) the first of such four years, then ninety per cent of the credit allowed shall be recaptured on the tax return required to be filed for such year, (B) the second of such four years, then sixty-five per cent of the credit allowed for the entire period of eligibility shall be recaptured on the tax return required to be filed for such year, (C) the third of such four years, then fifty per cent of the credit allowed for the entire period of eligibility shall be recaptured on the tax return required to be filed for such year, (D) the fourth of such four years, then thirty per cent of the credit allowed for the entire period of eligibility shall be recaptured on the tax return required to be filed for such year.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_h__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the first of such four years, then ninety per cent of the credit allowed shall be recaptured on the tax return required to be filed for such year,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_h__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the second of such four years, then sixty-five per cent of the credit allowed for the entire period of eligibility shall be recaptured on the tax return required to be filed for such year,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_h__subsec_1__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the third of such four years, then fifty per cent of the credit allowed for the entire period of eligibility shall be recaptured on the tax return required to be filed for such year,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217ii__subsec_h__subsec_1__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the fourth of such four years, then thirty per cent of the credit allowed for the entire period of eligibility shall be recaptured on the tax return required to be filed for such year.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>