<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217ff"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217ff"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-217ff"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217ff/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217ff/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217ff/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217ff/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_208">
        <num>208</num>
        <heading>Estate Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_217ff">
          <num>12-217ff</num>
          <heading>Tax credit for donation of land for educational use. No credit allowed on or after January 1, 2013</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_217ff__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For purposes of this section, “donation of land for educational use” means the value of any land or interest in land conveyed without financial consideration, or the value of any discount of the sale price in any sale of land or interest in land, to any municipality or political subdivision of the state for educational use, as defined in section16-43b.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217ff__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>There shall be allowed a credit for all taxpayers against the tax imposed under section12-217, in an amount equal to fifty per cent of any donation of land for educational use. For purposes of calculating the credit under this section the amount of donation shall be based on the difference between the use value of the donated land and the amount received for such land. For the purposes of this subsection, “use value” means a fair market value of land at its highest and best use, as determined by a certified real estate appraiser.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217ff__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A credit that is allowed under this section, with respect to any taxable year commencing on or after January 1, 2004, but is not used by a taxpayer may be carried forward to each of the successive income years until such credit is fully taken. In no case shall a credit that is not used be carried forward for a period of more than fifteen years.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217ff__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No tax credit shall be allowed under this section with respect to any donation of land for educational use made on or after January 1, 2013.
See Sec. 12-217dd re tax credit for donation of land for educational use.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>