<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-453"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-453"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-453"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-453/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-453/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-453/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-453/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_220">
        <num>220</num>
        <heading>Controlled Substances Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_453">
          <num>12-453</num>
          <heading>Exceptions</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-453. Exceptions.The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to ethyl alcohol intended for use or used for the following purposes: For scientific, chemical, mechanical and industrial uses, for use in hospitals and public institutions, for medicinal purposes, in the manufacture of patented, proprietary, medicinal, pharmaceutical, antiseptic, toilet, scientific, chemical, mechanical and industrial preparations or products, which preparations or products are not sold as a beverage for human consumption. The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to wine and distilled liquors used in the manufacture of patented, proprietary or pharmaceutical preparations or products, or in the manufacture of fruit preserves. The Commissioner of Revenue Services shall formulate regulations effecting the proper administration of this section. The Department of Consumer Protection may approve the purchase of alcohol or wine from persons located outside of this state to be used for the purposes specified in this section, even though such alcohol or wine may have been shipped directly to the purchaser. The Department of Consumer Protection shall notify the Commissioner of Revenue Services of the approval of any such shipments. Any such alcohol shall not be subject to the provisions of section12-436.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>