<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-99"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-99"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-99"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-99/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-99/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-99/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-99/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319s">
        <num>319s</num>
        <heading>Connecticut Partnership for Long-Term Care</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_99">
          <num>17b-99</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-83k). Vendor fraud penalties. Distribution of medical assistance program rules. Regulations. Audits of service providers. Appeal</heading>
          <subsection eId="17b_99__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any vendor found guilty of vendor fraud under sections53a-290to53a-296, inclusive, shall be subject to forfeiture or suspension of any franchise or license held by such vendor from the state in accordance with this subsection, after hearing in the manner provided for in sections4-176eto4-180a, inclusive, and4-181a. Any vendor convicted of vendor fraud under sections53a-290to53a-296, inclusive, shall have such license or franchise revoked. Nothing in this subsection shall preclude any board or commission established under chapters 369 to 376, inclusive, 378 to 381, inclusive, and 383 to 388, inclusive, and the Department of Public Health with respect to professions under its jurisdiction which have no board or commission from taking any action authorized in section19a-17. Any vendor who is convicted in any state or federal court of a crime involving fraud in the Medicare program or Medicaid program or aid to families with dependent children program or state-administered general assistance program or temporary family assistance program or state supplement to the federal Supplemental Security Income Program or any federal or state energy assistance program or general assistance program or state-funded child care program or the refugee program shall be terminated from such programs, effective upon conviction, except that the Commissioner of Social Services may delay termination for a period he deems sufficient to protect the health and well-being of beneficiaries receiving services from such vendor. A vendor who is ineligible for federal financial participation shall be ineligible for participation in such programs. No vendor shall be eligible for reimbursement for any goods provided or services performed by a person convicted of a crime involving fraud in such programs. The convicted person may request a hearing concerning such ineligibility for reimbursement pursuant to sections4-176eto4-180a, inclusive, and4-181aprovided such request is filed in writing with the Comm</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_99__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purpose of determining compliance with subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_99__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, all vendors shall notify the commissioner within thirty days after the date of employment or conviction, whichever is later, of the identity, interest and extent of services performed by any person convicted of a crime involving fraud in the Medicare program or Medicaid program or aid to families with dependent children program or state-administered general assistance program or temporary family assistance program or state supplement to the federal Supplemental Security Income Program or any federal or state energy assistance program or general assistance program or state-funded child care program or the refugee program. Prior to the commissioner's acceptance of a provider agreement or at any time upon written request by the commissioner, the vendor shall furnish the commissioner with the identity of any person convicted of a crime involving fraud in such programs who has an ownership or control interest in the vendor or who is an agent or managing employee. The commissioner shall terminate, refuse to enter into or renew an agreement with a vendor, except a vendor providing room and board and services pursuant to section17b-340, if such convicted person has such interest or is such agent or employee. In the case of a vendor providing room and board and services pursuant to said section17b-340, the commissioner may terminate, refuse to enter into or renew an agreement after consideration of any adverse impact on beneficiaries of such termination or refusal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_99__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Social Services shall distribute to all vendors who are providers in the medical assistance program a copy of the rules, regulations, standards and laws governing the program. The Commissioner of Social Services shall adopt by regulation in the manner provided for in sections4-166to4-176, inclusive, administrative sanctions against providers in the Medicare program or Medicaid program or aid to families with dependent children program or state-funded child care program or state-administered general assistance program or temporary family assistance program or state supplement to the federal Supplemental Security Income Program including suspension from the program, for any violations of the rules, regulations, standards or law. The commissioner may adopt regulations in accordance with the provisions of chapter 54 to provide for the withholding of payments currently due in order to offset money previously obtained as the result of error or fraud. The department shall notify the proper professional society and licensing agency of any violations of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_99__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <paragraph eId="17b_99__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Commissioner of Social Services, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts for the purpose of conducting an audit of a service provider that participates as a provider of services in a program operated or administered by the department pursuant to this chapter or chapter 319t, 319v, 319y or 319ff, except a service provider for which rates are established pursuant to section17b-340, shall conduct any such audit in accordance with the provisions of this subsection. For purposes of this subsection, (A) “clerical error” means an unintentional typographical, scrivener's or computer error, (B) “extrapolation” means the determination of an unknown value by projecting the results of the review of a sample to the universe from which the sample was drawn, (C) “ninety-five per cent confidence level” means there is a probability of at least ninety-five per cent that the result is reliable, (D) “provider” means a person, public agency, private agency or proprietary agency that is licensed, certified or otherwise approved by the commissioner to supply services authorized by the programs set forth in said chapters, (E) “stratified sampling” means a method of sampling that involves the division of a population into smaller groups known as strata based on shared attributes, characteristics or similar paid claim amounts, (F) “statistically valid sampling and extrapolation methodology” means a methodology that is</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_d__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“clerical error” means an unintentional typographical, scrivener's or computer error,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_d__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“extrapolation” means the determination of an unknown value by projecting the results of the review of a sample to the universe from which the sample was drawn,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_d__subsec_1__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“ninety-five per cent confidence level” means there is a probability of at least ninety-five per cent that the result is reliable,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_d__subsec_1__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“provider” means a person, public agency, private agency or proprietary agency that is licensed, certified or otherwise approved by the commissioner to supply services authorized by the programs set forth in said chapters,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_d__subsec_1__subsec_E">
                <num>(E)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“stratified sampling” means a method of sampling that involves the division of a population into smaller groups known as strata based on shared attributes, characteristics or similar paid claim amounts,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_d__subsec_1__subsec_F">
                <num>(F)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“statistically valid sampling and extrapolation methodology” means a methodology that is</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_99__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>validated by a statistician who has completed graduate work in statistics and has significant experience developing statistically valid samples and extrapolating the results of such samples on behalf of government entities, (ii) provides for the exclusion of highly unusual claims that are not representative of the universe of paid claims, (iii) has a ninety-five per cent confidence level or greater, and (iv) includes stratified sampling when applicable, and (G) “universe” means a defined population of claims submitted by a provider during a specific time period.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Not less than thirty days prior to the commencement of any such audit, the commissioner, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts to conduct an audit of a participating provider, shall provide written notification of the audit to such provider and the statistically valid sampling and extrapolation methodology to be used in conducting such audit, unless the commissioner, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts to conduct an audit of a participating provider makes a good faith determination that (A) the health or safety of a recipient of services is at risk; or (B) the provider is engaging in vendor fraud. At the commencement of the audit, the commissioner, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts to conduct an audit of a participating provider, shall disclose</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the health or safety of a recipient of services is at risk; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_2__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the provider is engaging in vendor fraud. At the commencement of the audit, the commissioner, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts to conduct an audit of a participating provider, shall disclose</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_99__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the name and contact information of the assigned auditor or auditors, (ii) the audit location, including notice of whether such audit shall be conducted on-site or through record submission, (iii) the manner by which information requested shall be submitted, and (iv) the types of information to be reviewed in the audit. No audit shall include claims paid more than thirty-six months from the date claims are selected for the audit. The commissioner shall not apply an agency policy, guideline, bulletin or manual provision or other criteria, including, but not limited to, updated medical payment codes, to make determinations in an audit unless the policy, guideline, bulletin or manual provision or other criteria, together with the effective date, was promulgated and distributed to a provider prior to provision of a service included in a claim being audited. The commissioner shall accept a scanned copy of documentation supporting a claim when the original documentation is unavailable.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any clerical error discovered in a record or document produced for any such audit shall not of itself constitute a wilful violation of program rules unless proof of intent to commit fraud or otherwise violate program rules is established. In determining which providers shall be subject to audits, the Commissioner of Social Services may give consideration to the history of a provider's compliance in addition to other criteria used to select a provider for an audit.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A finding of overpayment or underpayment to a provider in a program operated or administered by the department pursuant to this chapter or chapter 319t, 319v, 319y or 319ff, except a provider for which rates are established pursuant to section17b-340, shall not be based on extrapolation unless the total net amount of extrapolated overpayment calculated from a statistically valid sampling and extrapolation methodology exceeds one and three-quarters per cent of total claims paid to the provider for the audit period.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In conducting any audit pursuant to this subsection, the commissioner, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts to conduct such audit, shall accept (A) as sufficient proof of a written order: A photocopy, facsimile image, an electronically maintained document or original pen and ink document, and (B) as sufficient proof of delivery of a covered item or service: A receipt signed by the recipient of medical assistance or a nursing facility representative or, in the case of delivery of a covered item or service by a shipping or delivery service, a supplier's detailed shipping invoice and the delivery service tracking information substantiating delivery. The commissioner, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts to conduct such audit, may seek additional documentation in circumstances including, but not limited to:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_5__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>as sufficient proof of a written order: A photocopy, facsimile image, an electronically maintained document or original pen and ink document, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_5__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>as sufficient proof of delivery of a covered item or service: A receipt signed by the recipient of medical assistance or a nursing facility representative or, in the case of delivery of a covered item or service by a shipping or delivery service, a supplier's detailed shipping invoice and the delivery service tracking information substantiating delivery. The commissioner, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts to conduct such audit, may seek additional documentation in circumstances including, but not limited to:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_99__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The proof provided is insufficiently legible, (ii) the proof provided is contradicted by other sources of information reviewed in the audit, or (iii) the commissioner, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts to conduct such audit, makes a good faith determination that the provider may be engaging in vendor fraud. A provider, in complying with the requirements of any such audit, shall be allowed not less than thirty days to provide documentation in connection with any discrepancy discovered and brought to the attention of such provider in the course of any such audit. Such documentation may include evidence that errors concerning payment and billing resulted from a provider's transition to a new payment or billing service or accounting system. The commissioner shall not calculate an overpayment based on extrapolation or attempt to recover such extrapolated overpayment when the provider presents credible evidence that an error by the commissioner, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts to conduct an audit pursuant to this subsection, caused the overpayment, provided the commissioner may recover the amount of the original overpayment.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commissioner, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts, for the purpose of conducting an audit of a provider of any of the programs operated or administered by the department pursuant to this chapter or chapter 319t, 319v, 319y or 319ff, except a service provider for which rates are established pursuant to section17b-340, shall produce a preliminary written report concerning any audit conducted pursuant to this subsection, and such preliminary report shall be provided to the provider that was the subject of the audit not later than sixty days after the conclusion of such audit.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commissioner, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts, for the purpose of conducting an audit of a provider of any of the programs operated or administered by the department pursuant to this chapter or chapter 319t, 319v, 319y or 319ff, except a service provider for which rates are established pursuant to section17b-340, shall, following the issuance of the preliminary report pursuant to subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, hold an exit conference with any provider that was the subject of any audit pursuant to this subsection for the purpose of discussing the preliminary report. Such provider may present evidence at such exit conference refuting findings in the preliminary report.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_8">
              <num>(8)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commissioner, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts, for the purpose of conducting an audit of a service provider, shall produce a final written report concerning any audit conducted pursuant to this subsection. Such final written report shall be provided to the provider that was the subject of the audit not later than sixty days after the date of the exit conference conducted pursuant to subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, unless the commissioner, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts for the purpose of conducting an audit of a service provider, agrees to a later date or there are other referrals or investigations pending concerning the provider.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_9">
              <num>(9)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any provider aggrieved by a decision contained in a final written report issued pursuant to subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_8">
              <num>(8)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection may, not later than thirty days after the receipt of the final report, request, in writing, a contested case hearing in accordance with chapter 54. Such request shall contain a detailed written description of each specific item of aggrievement. The designee of the commissioner who presides over the hearing shall be impartial and shall not be an employee of the Department of Social Services Office of Quality Assurance or an employee of an entity with which the commissioner contracts for the purpose of conducting an audit of a service provider. A provider shall be permitted to raise during such hearing that a negative audit finding was due to a provider's compliance with a state or federal law or regulation. Following review on all items of aggrievement, the designee of the commissioner who presides over the hearing shall issue a final decision not later than ninety days following the close of evidence or the date on which final briefs are filed, whichever occurs later. When a provider requests a hearing pursuant to this subdivision, and the provider is contesting an overpayment amount based on extrapolation, the Department of Social Services shall not recoup the overpayment amount at issue until a final decision is issued after the hearing.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_10">
              <num>(10)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to any audit conducted by the Medicaid Fraud Control Unit established within the Office of the Chief State's Attorney.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_11">
              <num>(11)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commissioner shall provide free training to providers on how to enter claims to avoid errors and shall post information on the department's Internet web site concerning the auditing process, standard audit procedures and methods to avoid clerical errors. The commissioner shall establish and publish on the department's Internet web site audit protocols to assist the Medicaid provider community in developing programs to improve compliance with Medicaid requirements under state and federal laws and regulations, provided audit protocols may not be relied upon to create a substantive or procedural right or benefit enforceable at law or in equity by any person, including a corporation. The commissioner shall establish audit protocols for specific providers or categories of service, including, but not limited to: (A) Licensed home health agencies, (B) drug and alcohol treatment centers, (C) durable medical equipment, (D) hospital outpatient services, (E) physician and nursing services, (F) dental services, (G) behavioral health services, (H) pharmaceutical services, (I) emergency and nonemergency medical transportation services, and (J) homemaker companion services. The commissioner shall ensure that the Department of Social Services, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts to conduct an audit pursuant to this subsection, has on staff or consults with, as needed, a medical or dental professional who is experienced in the use and review of electronic medical records, and the treatment, billing and coding procedures used by the provider being audited. The commissioner shall ensure that an auditor reviews any electronic medical record associated with a patient chart included in the audit.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_11__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Licensed home health agencies,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_11__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>drug and alcohol treatment centers,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_11__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>durable medical equipment,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_11__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>hospital outpatient services,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_11__subsec_E">
                <num>(E)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>physician and nursing services,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_11__subsec_F">
                <num>(F)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>dental services,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_11__subsec_G">
                <num>(G)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>behavioral health services,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_11__subsec_H">
                <num>(H)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>pharmaceutical services,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_11__subsec_I">
                <num>(I)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>emergency and nonemergency medical transportation services, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_99__subsec_i__subsec_11__subsec_J">
                <num>(J)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>homemaker companion services. The commissioner shall ensure that the Department of Social Services, or any entity with which the commissioner contracts to conduct an audit pursuant to this subsection, has on staff or consults with, as needed, a medical or dental professional who is experienced in the use and review of electronic medical records, and the treatment, billing and coding procedures used by the provider being audited. The commissioner shall ensure that an auditor reviews any electronic medical record associated with a patient chart included in the audit.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>