<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-137"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-137"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-137"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-137/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-137/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-137/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-137/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319s">
        <num>319s</num>
        <heading>Connecticut Partnership for Long-Term Care</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_137">
          <num>17b-137</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-303). Disclosure of property of recipients of state aid, care or child support enforcement services. Disclosure of property of persons liable to support recipients or subject to IV-D support case investigation. Access to records. Automated data match system. High-volume automated administrative enforcement</heading>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>(A) Any person who has in his possession or control any property of any person applying for or presently or formerly receiving aid or care or child support enforcement services, as defined in subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_137__subsec_a__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Any person who has in his possession or control any property of any person applying for or presently or formerly receiving aid or care or child support enforcement services, as defined in subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section46b-231, from the state or who is indebted to such applicant or recipient or has knowledge of any insurance, including health insurance or property currently or formerly belonging to him, or information pertaining to eligibility for such aid or care or services, and any officer who has control of the books and accounts of any corporation which has possession or control of any property belonging to any person applying for or receiving such aid or care or services or who is indebted to him, or has knowledge of any insurance, including health insurance or any person having in his employ any such person, shall, upon presentation by the Commissioner of Social Services, or the Commissioner of Administrative Services, or the Commissioner of Emergency Services and Public Protection, or a support enforcement officer of the Superior Court, or any person deputized by any of them, of a certificate, signed by him, stating that such applicant, recipient or employee has applied for or is receiving or has received such aid or care or services from the state, make full disclosure to such commissioner, such officer or such deputy of any such property, insurance, wages, indebtedness or information. Notwithstanding the provisions of this subparagraph, any health insurer, including a self-insured plan, group health plan, as defined in Section 607</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, service benefit plan, managed care organization, health care center, pharmacy benefit manager, dental benefit manager, third-party administrator or other party that is, by statute, contract or agreement, legally responsible for payment of a claim for a health care item or service, which may or may not be financially at risk for the cost of a health care item or service, shall, upon request of the Commissioner of Social Services, or the commissioner's designee, provide any and all information in a manner and format prescribed by the commissioner, or the commissioner's designee, to identify, determine or establish third-party coverage, including all information necessary to determine during what period a person, his or her spouse or his or her dependents may be, or may have been, covered by a health insurer and the nature of the coverage that is or was provided by the health insurer, including the name, address, date of birth, Social Security number, identifying number of the plan, plan type, types of covered services, effective dates of coverage and termination date for the policy holder. Such information shall be provided by such health insurer to the Commissioner of Social Services or the commissioner's designee not later than ninety days after the commissioner or the designee's initial request, and not less frequently than monthly thereafter. Such information shall also be provided by such health insurer to all third-party administrators, pharmacy benefit managers, dental benefit managers or other entities with which the health insurer has an arrangement to adjudicate claims for a health care item or service.
(B) At the request of the Commissioner of Social Services, any health insurer, including a self-insured plan, group health plan, as defined in Section 607</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_137__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>At the request of the Commissioner of Social Services, any health insurer, including a self-insured plan, group health plan, as defined in Section 607</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, service benefit plan, managed care organization, health care center, pharmacy benefit manager, dental benefit manager, third-party administrator or other party that is, by statute, contract or agreement, legally responsible for payment of a claim for a health care item or service, which may or may not be financially at risk for the cost of a health care item or service, shall be required to allow the commissioner, or the commissioner's designee, to conduct automated data matches to identify insurance coverage for recipients and the parents of recipients who are minors.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>(A) Such disclosure may be obtained in like manner of the property, wages or indebtedness of any person who is either:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_137__subsec_b__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Such disclosure may be obtained in like manner of the property, wages or indebtedness of any person who is either:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Liable for the support of any such applicant or recipient, including the parents of any child receiving aid or services through the Department of Children and Families, or one adjudged or acknowledged to be the parent of a child; or (ii) the subject of an investigation in a IV-D support case, as defined in subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_i__subsec_13">
              <num>(13)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section46b-231. Any company or officer who has control of the books and accounts of any corporation shall make full disclosure to the IV-D agency, as defined in subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_b__subsec_12">
              <num>(12)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section46b-231, or to the support enforcement officer of the Superior Court of any such property, wages or indebtedness in all support cases, including IV-D support cases, as defined in subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_b__subsec_13">
              <num>(13)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section46b-231.
(B) The Commissioner of Social Services, the Commissioner of Administrative Services, the Commissioner of Emergency Services and Public Protection or a support enforcement officer of the Superior Court, or any person deputized by any of them, may compel, by subpoena, the attendance and testimony under oath of any person who refuses to disclose in accordance with the provisions of this section, or of any person who is either:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Liable for the support of any such applicant or recipient; or (ii) the subject of an investigation in a IV-D support case, as defined in subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_i__subsec_13">
              <num>(13)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section46b-231, who refuses to disclose his own financial circumstances, and may so compel the production of books and papers pertaining to such information.
(C) The Commissioner of Social Services may subpoena the financial records of any financial institution concerning property of any person applying for or presently or formerly receiving aid or care from the state or who is indebted to such applicant or recipient. The Commissioner of Social Services may subpoena such records of any parent or parents of any child applying for or presently or formerly receiving assistance under the aid to families with dependent children program, the temporary family assistance program or the state-administered general assistance program.
(D) The commissioner, or a support enforcement officer of the Superior Court, or the person deputized by the commissioner or officer shall set a time and place for any examination under this subdivision, and any person summoned who, without reasonable excuse, fails to appear and testify or to produce such books and papers shall be fined fifty dollars for each such offense.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding any provision of the general statutes, the IV-D agency shall have access, including automated access in the case of records maintained in automated data bases, to information contained in the following:
(A) Records of other state and local government agencies, including:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_137__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Records of other state and local government agencies, including:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Vital statistics, including records of marriage, birth, death and dissolution of marriage; (ii) state and local tax and revenue records, including information on residence address, employer, income and assets; (iii) records concerning real and titled personal property; (iv) records of occupational and professional licenses and records concerning the ownership and control of corporations, partnerships and other business entities;</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_v">
            <num>(v)</num>
            <content>
              <p>employment security records; (vi) records of agencies administering public assistance programs; (vii) records of the Department of Motor Vehicles; and (viii) records of the Department of Correction.
(B) Certain records held by private entities with respect to individuals who owe or are owed support, or against or with respect to whom a support order is sought, consisting of:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The names and addresses of such individuals and the names and addresses of the employers of such individuals, as appearing in customer records of public utilities, cable television companies, and cellular mobile telephone and other wireless telecommunications service providers, pursuant to a subpoena issued under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section; and (ii) information, including information on assets and liabilities, on such individuals held by financial institutions.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>(A) The IV-D agency shall safeguard all information secured by or made available to it pursuant to subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_137__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The IV-D agency shall safeguard all information secured by or made available to it pursuant to subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection and shall not further disclose any such information except in connection with the administration of the title IV-D program.
(B) Any entity that provides access to or discloses any information in accordance with this subsection shall be relieved of any liability to any person for any such provision or disclosure.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_137__subsec_a__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Any entity that provides access to or discloses any information in accordance with this subsection shall be relieved of any liability to any person for any such provision or disclosure.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The IV-D agency and financial institutions, as defined in section 469A</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of the Social Security Act, doing business in this state shall enter into agreements to develop and operate a data match system, using automated data exchanges to the maximum extent feasible, in which each such financial institution is required to provide for each calendar quarter the name, record address, Social Security number or other taxpayer identification number and other identifying information for each noncustodial parent who maintains an account at such institution and who owes past-due support, as identified by the IV-D agency by name and Social Security number or other taxpayer identification number. Upon completion of such matches, the commissioner shall reimburse such financial institutions for the reasonable documented costs of conducting the matches. For the purposes of this section, “account” means a demand deposit account, checking or negotiable withdrawal order account, savings account, time deposit account or money-market mutual fund account.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A financial institution shall not be liable to any person for (A) disclosing information to the IV-D agency pursuant to this subsection, (B) encumbering or surrendering any assets held by such institution in response to a notice issued under subsections</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_137__subsec_d__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>disclosing information to the IV-D agency pursuant to this subsection,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_137__subsec_d__subsec_2__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>encumbering or surrendering any assets held by such institution in response to a notice issued under subsections</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section52-362d, or (C) any other action taken in good faith to comply with the requirements of subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_e__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For the purposes of this subsection, “high-volume automated administrative enforcement” means the identification of assets, through automated data matches with financial institutions and other entities, as provided in this section and required by federal law, and the seizure of such assets in accordance with subsections</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section52-362d.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_e__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The IV-D agency shall: (A) Use high-volume automated administrative enforcement, as defined in subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_137__subsec_e__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Use high-volume automated administrative enforcement, as defined in subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_e__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, to the same extent as in intrastate cases; and (B) promptly report the results of such enforcement procedure to the requesting state.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_137__subsec_e__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>promptly report the results of such enforcement procedure to the requesting state.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_e__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Support Enforcement Services or the IV-D agency may, by electronic or other means, transmit to another state a request for assistance in enforcing support orders administratively, in a manner similar to this subsection, which request shall: (A) Include information that shall enable the state to which the request is transmitted to compare the information about the cases to the information data bases of such state; and (B) constitute a certification by this state</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_137__subsec_e__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Include information that shall enable the state to which the request is transmitted to compare the information about the cases to the information data bases of such state; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_137__subsec_e__subsec_3__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>constitute a certification by this state</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_137__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the amount of support under an order the payment of which is in arrears, and (ii) that this state has complied with all procedural due process requirements applicable to each case.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_i__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the IV-D agency provides assistance under this subsection to another state concerning a case, such case shall not be considered transferred to the caseload of the IV-D agency.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_137__subsec_i__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The IV-D agency shall maintain records of: (A) The number of requests for assistance received under this subsection; (B) the number of cases for which such agency collected support in response to such requests; and (C) the amount of such collected support.
See Sec. 17b-745 re admissibility of evidence obtained under this section.
See Secs. 36a-42 and 36a-43 re disclosure of financial records by banks.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_137__subsec_i__subsec_5__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The number of requests for assistance received under this subsection;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_137__subsec_i__subsec_5__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the number of cases for which such agency collected support in response to such requests; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_137__subsec_i__subsec_5__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the amount of such collected support.
See Sec. 17b-745 re admissibility of evidence obtained under this section.
See Secs. 36a-42 and 36a-43 re disclosure of financial records by banks.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>