<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-83"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-83"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-83"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-83/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-83/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-83/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-83/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319s">
        <num>319s</num>
        <heading>Connecticut Partnership for Long-Term Care</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_83">
          <num>17b-83</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-82g). Form of aid. Direct payment for certain services. Payment of clean claims</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 17b-83. (Formerly Sec. 17-82g). Form of aid. Direct payment for certain services. Payment of clean claims.The aid granted under the state supplement program or the temporary family assistance program shall be in the form of money payments and shall be made by the commissioner within available Department of Social Services appropriations, directly to a licensed residential care home, as defined in section19a-490, a rated housing facility, as defined in section17b-82, the applicant or other person entitled to receive the same at such regular intervals as the Commissioner of Social Services determines, provided the payments of the costs of medical care and such other charges in connection with the care and maintenance of a beneficiary as the commissioner deems necessary and reasonable may be made to the licensed residential care home or rated housing facility, applicant or to those persons furnishing such services by the commissioner. Ninety per cent of clean claims for payments to persons furnishing such services shall be made not later than thirty days from receipt of the request for payment and ninety-nine per cent shall be made within ninety days of such receipt. For the purposes of this section “clean claim” means a claim which can be processed without obtaining additional substantiation from the person furnishing such services or other person entitled to receive payment. A claim submitted by any such person who is under investigation for fraud or abuse shall not be considered a clean claim.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>