<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-398"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-398"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-398"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-398/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-398/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-398/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-398/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_217">
        <num>217</num>
        <heading>Admissions and Dues Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_398">
          <num>12-398</num>
          <heading>Amended return. Additional assessment. Disclosure of return information by court of probate. Tax lien. Certificate of release of lien</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_398__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the amount of federal estate tax reported on an estate's federal estate tax return is changed or corrected by the United States Internal Revenue Service or other competent authority, the person required to make and file the estate tax return under this chapter shall provide notice of such change or correction to the commissioner by filing, on or before the date that is ninety days after the final determination of such change or correction, or as otherwise required by the commissioner, an amended return under this chapter, and shall concede the accuracy of such determination or state wherein it is erroneous, and thereafter promptly furnish to the commissioner any information, schedules, records, documents or papers relating to such change or correction as the commissioner requires. The time for filing such return may be extended by the commissioner upon due cause shown. If, upon examination, the commissioner finds that the estate is liable for the payment of an additional tax, the commissioner shall, within a reasonable time from the receipt of such return, notify the estate of the amount of such additional tax, together with interest thereon computed at the rate of one per cent per month or fraction thereof from the date when the original tax became due and payable. Within thirty days of the mailing of such notice, the estate shall pay to the commissioner, in cash or by check, draft or money order, drawn to the order of the Commissioner of Revenue Services, the amount of such additional tax and interest. If, upon examination of such return and related information, the commissioner finds that the estate has overpaid the tax due the state and has not received from or been allowed by the United States government, or any agency thereof, a credit or a benefit, as a deduction or otherwise, for or by reason of such overpayment, the estate shall be paid by the State Treasurer, upon order of the Comptroller, the amount of such overpayment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_398__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a person required to make and file the estate tax return under this chapter files an amended federal estate tax return with the United States Internal Revenue Service, such person shall also file, not later than ninety days following such amended federal estate tax filing, an amended return under this chapter and shall give such other information as the commissioner may require. The commissioner may adopt regulations in accordance with chapter 54, prescribing exceptions to the requirements of this section as he deems appropriate. If, upon examination of such amended return, the commissioner finds that the estate is liable for the payment of an additional tax, he shall, within a reasonable time from the receipt of such amended return, notify the estate of the amount of such additional tax, together with interest thereon computed at the rate of one per cent per month or fraction thereof from the date when the original tax became due and payable. Not later than thirty days following the mailing of such notice, the estate shall pay to the commissioner, in cash or by check, draft or money order, drawn to the order of the Commissioner of Revenue Services, the amount of such additional tax and interest. If, upon examination of such amended return, the commissioner finds that the estate has overpaid the tax due the state and has not received from or been allowed by the United States government, or any agency thereof, a credit or a benefit, as a deduction or otherwise, for or by reason of such overpayment, the estate shall be paid by the State Treasurer, upon order of the State Comptroller, the amount of such overpayment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_398__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_398__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of sections1-200,1-205,1-206,1-210to1-213, inclusive,1-225to1-232, inclusive,1-240and19a-342a court of probate shall not disclose to any person or state or municipal board, commission, department or agency, estate tax returns and estate tax return information that are provided to such court under this chapter, except the Probate Court shall, upon request, disclose such returns and return information to the Probate Court Administrator and to the Commissioner of Revenue Services, and may disclose such a return or return information to an executor, administrator, trustee, grantee, donee, beneficiary, surviving joint owner or other interested party, when any such person establishes, to the satisfaction of such court, that he or she has a material interest which will be affected by information contained in such return.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_398__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of sections1-200,1-205,1-206,1-210to1-213, inclusive,1-225to1-232, inclusive,1-240and19a-342the Probate Court Administrator shall not disclose to any person or state or municipal board, commission, department or agency, estate tax returns and estate tax return information that are provided to such administrator, except that the Probate Court Administrator shall, upon request, disclose such returns and return information to the Commissioner of Revenue Services and a return and return information concerning a decedent to the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, to the court of probate for the district within which real estate or tangible personal property of the decedent is situated, and may disclose such a return or return information to an executor, administrator, trustee, grantee, donee, beneficiary, surviving joint owner or other interested party, when any such person establishes, to the satisfaction of such administrator, that he has a material interest which will be affected by information contained in such return.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_398__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The tax imposed under this chapter shall be a lien in favor of the state of Connecticut upon the real property so transferred from the due date until paid, with the interest and costs that may accrue in addition thereto, except that such lien shall not be valid as against any lienor, mortgagee, judgment creditor or bona fide purchaser until notice of such lien is filed or recorded in the town clerk's office or place where mortgages, liens and conveyances of such property are required by statute to be filed or recorded. The lien upon any real property transferred, or a portion thereof, may be discharged by the payment of such amount of tax thereon as the commissioner may specify. Any person shall be entitled to a certificate that the tax upon the transfer of any real property has been paid, and such certificate may be recorded in the office of the town clerk of the town within which such real property is situated, and it shall be conclusive proof that the tax on the transfer of such real property has been paid and such lien discharged.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_398__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_398__subsec_e__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any person shall be entitled to a certificate of release of lien with respect to the interest of the decedent in such real property, if either the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, for the district within which real estate or tangible personal property of the decedent is situated, or the Commissioner of Revenue Services finds, upon evidence satisfactory to said court or said commissioner, as the case may be, that payment of the tax imposed under this chapter with respect to the interest of the decedent in such real property is adequately assured, or that no tax imposed under this chapter is due. The certificate of release of lien shall be issued by the court of probate, unless a tax return is required to be filed with the commissioner under subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_398__subsec_e__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_398__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-392, in which case the certificate of release of lien shall be issued by the commissioner. Any certificate of release of lien shall be valid if issued by a probate court prior to May 4, 2011, and recorded in the office of the town clerk of the town in which such real property is situated prior to May 4, 2011, for the estate of a decedent who died on or after January 1, 2011, and whose Connecticut taxable estate is more than two million dollars but equal to or less than three million five hundred thousand dollars.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_398__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A certificate of release of lien may be recorded in the office of the town clerk of the town within which such real property is situated, and it shall be conclusive proof that such real property has been released from the operation of such lien.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_398__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commissioner may adopt regulations in accordance with the provisions of chapter 54 that establish procedures to be followed by a court of probate or by said commissioner, as the case may be, for issuing certificates of release of lien, and that establish the requirements and conditions that must be satisfied in order for a court of probate or for the commissioner, as the case may be, to find that the payment of such tax is adequately assured or that no tax imposed under this chapter is due.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_398__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The amount of any tax, penalty or interest due and unpaid under the provisions of this chapter may be collected under the provisions of section12-35. The warrant provided under section12-35shall be signed by the commissioner or his authorized agent.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>