<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-461b"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-461b"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-461b"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-461b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-461b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-461b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-461b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_221">
        <num>221</num>
        <heading>Real Estate Conveyance Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_461b">
          <num>12-461b</num>
          <heading>Fuel in transport must be supported by valid invoices. Seller or consignor required to be distributor. Violations deemed fuel contraband and subject to seizure</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-461b. Fuel in transport must be supported by valid invoices. Seller or consignor required to be distributor. Violations deemed fuel contraband and subject to seizure.Every person who transports fuels upon the public highways, roads, streets or waterways of this state shall have in his actual possession invoices or delivery tickets for such fuels, which shall show the true name and address of the consignor or seller, the true name and address of the consignee or purchaser and the number of gallons and type of fuel so transported. If the fuel is consigned to or delivered to or purchased by any person in Connecticut, such seller or consignor shall be a distributor licensed as provided in section12-456; if the invoices or delivery tickets specify that the fuel is to be delivered to any person in any other state or jurisdiction, such seller or consignor shall be required to be authorized by the laws of such other state or jurisdiction to engage in the business of distributing fuel on which the taxes imposed by such other state or jurisdiction have not been paid. In the absence of such invoices or delivery tickets, or, if the name or address of the consignee or purchaser is falsified or if the seller or consignor is not authorized to distribute fuel, the fuel so transported shall be deemed contraband and shall be subject to confiscation. Any transporter, shipper or any person who violates any provision of this section shall be imprisoned not more than one year or be fined not more than one thousand dollars or both.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>