<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-176"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-176"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-176"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-176/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-176/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-176/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-176/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_205">
        <num>205</num>
        <heading>Tax Liens</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_176">
          <num>12-176</num>
          <heading>Fees of collectors and town clerks</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-176. Fees of collectors and town clerks.The fee of the collector for making out each certificate continuing a lien for any tax, the collection of which has been deferred for a period not exceeding fifteen years, and furnishing the information required to be furnished by the provisions of sections12-173and12-174, shall be two dollars. The fee of the collector for making out each certificate continuing a lien for any tax and furnishing the information required to be furnished by the provisions of sections12-173and12-175shall be three dollars. The fee of the collector for the preparation of a certificate discharging the lien for any tax subject to the provisions of sections12-171to12-175, inclusive, and the filing of the same with the town clerk for record, shall be one dollar. The fees herein provided for, and the fees of town clerks provided for under section7-34afor the recording of any of such certificates, in each case shall become a part of the tax and shall be collected from the taxpayer in addition to the amount of the tax and interest due thereon. Each collector and each town clerk, whose compensation is not in lieu of fees, shall, at the end of each three months, render a bill to his municipality for all fees to which he is entitled, under the provisions of this section, for continuing, releasing or recording any lien for any tax the collection of which has been deferred for a period not exceeding fifteen years under the provisions of sections12-173and12-174. Each such bill shall, upon approval by the proper authority, be forthwith paid by such municipality.
See Sec. 7-34a re town clerks' fees.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>