<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-186"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-186"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-186"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-186/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-186/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-186/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-186/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_205">
        <num>205</num>
        <heading>Tax Liens</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_186">
          <num>12-186</num>
          <heading>Publication and notice</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-186. Publication and notice.When the list has been thus marked, the clerk shall immediately give notice in writing to the tax collector of such fact and the tax collector shall, within one week of receipt of such notice, give notice of the pendency of the petition for foreclosure by causing a copy of the petition, with the parcels so marked “Withdrawn” deleted therefrom, to be published at least once in a newspaper having a general circulation in the municipality where the properties listed are located. Such notice shall be preceded by the following statement: “Notice of petition of foreclosure of tax liens by the collector of ..... Under the provisions of section12-182an action has been brought and is pending in the superior court for the judicial district of .... to foreclose tax liens upon the properties described below. No personal judgment will be rendered in such proceeding for the payment of such taxes against the owner or any person having an interest in any of such properties. All persons having or claiming an interest in any of them are hereby notified of the pendency of the action. With the exception of any properties withdrawn from said proceeding in accordance with the provisions of sections12-185and12-187, the right, title or interest of any person in any of said properties will be foreclosed unless the amounts due upon the tax lien or liens against the same, with any interest, fees and other charges thereon which have accrued since the bringing of the action, shall be paid before the expiration of the period designated therein for the redemption of such property.” The tax collector shall, on or before the date of publication of the notice, cause a copy of such notice to be filed in the office of the town clerk of the town in which the property is situated and such filing shall have the same force and effect as the filing of a notice of lis pendens in accordance with the provisions of section52-325and such notice shall be kept by the town clerk as part of the land records and be indexed in the same manner as a lis pendens as to the property being foreclosed and the names of the owners thereof or of any interest therein or encumbrances thereon as recited in such petition. The tax collector shall also, within such time, post a copy of such notice in some conspicuous place in the office of the town clerk and in his own office and shall cause a notice of the pendency of such action to be sent by registered or certified mail, postage prepaid, to the owner or owners of each of such properties and of any encumbrance thereon or interest therein, as they appear in such petition, directed to the best address of each that he is able to obtain from known and readily available sources, including city directories.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>