<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-506d"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-506d"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-506d"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-506d/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-506d/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-506d/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-506d/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_224">
        <num>224</num>
        <heading>Community Revitalization and Investment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_506d">
          <num>12-506d</num>
          <heading>Credit for tax paid in another state on gain from sale of certain property</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_506d__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-506shall be allowed for a tax paid to another state with respect to any gain from the sale or exchange of real property located in that state which had not been held for investment, income-producing or any business purpose by a taxpayer subject to tax under this chapter, provided such real property was used as the principal place of residence by such taxpayer for not less than six months during the period of twelve months immediately preceding the date of such sale or exchange. The credit allowed herein shall not exceed the lesser of</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_506d__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the tax paid to the other state with respect to such a gain or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_506d__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>that proportion of the total tax due under this chapter which the amount of gain taxed in both this and another state and qualifying for this credit bears to the entire net gain of the taxpayer for the same taxable year for which a return is filed under this chapter. If the taxpayer is allowed credit under this section based on more or less of another state's tax than he is finally required to pay, the taxpayer shall send notice of the difference to the Commissioner of Revenue Services who shall redetermine the tax for any years affected regardless of any otherwise applicable statute of limitations.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>