<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-689"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-689"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-689"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-689/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-689/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-689/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-689/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319j">
        <num>319j</num>
        <heading>Health Care For Uninsured Children</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_689">
          <num>17a-689</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 19a-126i). Liability of medical or police officer. False commitment and fraud, penalties</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_689__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No medical officer or staff member of a treatment facility or hospital who submits any report or files any petition required or authorized by sections17a-673and17a-680to17a-690, inclusive, shall be held to have violated any otherwise confidential relationship.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_689__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any medical officer or staff member of a treatment facility or hospital acting in compliance with sections17a-673and17a-680to17a-690, inclusive, shall be deemed to be acting in the course of his official duty and shall not be criminally or civilly liable therefor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_689__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any police officer acting in compliance with sections17a-465,17a-673and17a-680to17a-690, inclusive, shall be deemed to be acting in the course of official duty and shall not be criminally or civilly liable therefor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_689__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who is lawfully designated to assist in protective custody and transport under the provisions of section17a-683shall be deemed to be acting in the course of official duty and shall not be criminally or civilly liable therefor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_689__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who wilfully and knowingly causes or attempts to cause any person not an alcohol-dependent person or not a drug-dependent person to be committed pursuant to section17a-684, or section17a-685, or any person who knowingly makes a false statement of fact or belief in any petition, certificate or report required by sections17a-673and17a-680to17a-690, inclusive, or any person who wilfully and knowingly reports falsely to any court, judge, prosecutor or law enforcement officer that any person is an alcohol-dependent person or a drug-dependent person, may be imprisoned not more than one year or fined not more than one thousand dollars or both.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_689__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who fraudulently makes application for treatment as a drug-dependent person, or who makes more than one application for such treatment with the intent of obtaining controlled drugs in excess of that provided for a patient in treatment or to conceal or thwart a prior treatment program at another or the same treatment facility, shall be fined not more than five hundred dollars or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>