<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-685"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-685"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-685"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-685/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-685/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-685/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-685/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319j">
        <num>319j</num>
        <heading>Health Care For Uninsured Children</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_685">
          <num>17a-685</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 19a-126e). Application for involuntary commitment. Notice of hearing. Order of commitment. Recommitment. Discharge. Application for termination of commitment or recommitment and discharge</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <heading>Who may make application</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Any person, including the spouse, a relative or a conservator of a person sought to be committed, a physician issuing a certificate under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section or the administrator of a treatment facility may make application to the Probate Court to commit a person to an inpatient treatment facility for treatment for alcohol dependency or drug dependency. The application shall be brought to the probate court for the district in which the respondent resides, or, if the respondent's residence is out of state or unknown, for the district in which he or she is at the time of filing the application. In any case in which the person is being treated in a facility, and an application is filed in accordance with the provisions of this section, jurisdiction shall be vested in the probate court for the district in which the facility where such person is a patient is located. If the respondent is confined to a facility, notwithstanding the provisions of section45a-7, the judge of probate for the district in which the application was filed shall hold the hearing on the application at the facility where such person is confined.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <heading>Contents of application and physician's certificate</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Order for disclosure of medical information.The application shall allege that the person is an alcohol-dependent person or a drug-dependent person who is dangerous to himself or herself or dangerous to others when he or she is an intoxicated person or who is gravely disabled. The application shall contain a statement that the applicant has arranged for treatment in a treatment facility. A statement to that effect from such facility shall be attached to the application. At or before the hearing on the application, there shall be filed with the court a certificate of a licensed physician who has examined the person within two days before submission of the application. The physician's certificate shall set forth the physician's findings, including clinical observation or information, or the person's medical history, in support of the allegations of the application, and a finding of whether the person presently needs and is likely to benefit from treatment, and shall include a recommendation as to the type and length of treatment and inpatient facilities available for such treatment. A physician employed by the private treatment facility to which the person is to be committed is not eligible to be the certifying physician. An application filed by a person other than the certifying physician shall set forth the facts and information upon which the applicant bases his or her allegations and the names and addresses of all physicians. Upon the filing of an application under this section, the court may issue an order for the disclosure of the medical information required pursuant to this subsection.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <heading>Hearing date</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Notice.Upon receipt of the application, the court shall assign a time for a hearing not later than seven business days after the date the application was filed. A copy of the application and physician's certificate and the notice of the hearing, shall be served, by a state marshal, constable or indifferent person not later than three business days before the hearing on the respondent, unless the respondent is in a facility, in which case such notice shall be by regular mail. Such notice shall inform such respondent that he or she has a right to be present at the hearing, that he or she has the right to counsel and, if indigent, to have counsel appointed to represent him or her, and that such respondent has a right to cross-examine witnesses testifying at any hearing upon that application. The court shall cause a recording of the testimony of such hearing to be made, to be transcribed only in the event of an appeal from the decree rendered pursuant to this section. A copy of such transcript shall be furnished without charge to any appellant whom the Court of Probate finds is unable to pay for the same. The cost of said transcript shall be paid from funds appropriated to the Judicial Department. The court shall cause notice of said hearing to be given by regular mail to the respondent's next of kin, a parent or legal guardian if the respondent is a minor, the administrator of the treatment facility if the respondent has been committed for emergency treatment pursuant to section17a-684, and the administrator of the treatment facility to which the respondent is to be admitted. The court may order such notice as it directs to other persons having an interest in the respondent. If the court finds such respondent is indigent or otherwise unable to pay for counsel, the court shall appoint counsel for such respondent, unless such respondent refuses counsel and the court finds that the respondent understands the nature of such refusal. The court shall appoint counsel for the </p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <heading>Commitment order</heading>
            <content>
              <p>If, after hearing all relevant evidence, including the results of any diagnostic examination, the court finds, by clear and convincing evidence, that the respondent is an alcohol-dependent person or a drug-dependent person who is dangerous to himself or herself or dangerous to others when he or she is an intoxicated person or who is gravely disabled, it shall make an order of commitment to a treatment facility for inpatient treatment for a period of not less than thirty nor more than one hundred eighty days. The court may not order commitment of a respondent unless it determines that the treatment facility is able to provide adequate and appropriate treatment for such respondent and that the treatment is likely to be beneficial. In any proceeding pursuant to this subsection, the provisions of section17a-686shall apply.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <heading>Expiration of commitment period</heading>
            <content>
              <p>A person committed under this section shall remain in the custody of the administrator of the treatment facility for inpatient treatment for the commitment period unless sooner discharged under the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_k">
            <num>(k)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section by the administrator of the treatment facility. At the end of the commitment period, a person committed under this section shall be discharged automatically unless the administrator, before expiration of the period, obtains a court order for recommitment pursuant to the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section for inpatient treatment. When the person is discharged, the administrator shall, if recommended by the medical officer of the facility, refer the person to an outpatient treatment facility for treatment pursuant to the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_j">
            <num>(j)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <heading>Application for recommitment</heading>
            <content>
              <p>The administrator of an inpatient treatment facility, before expiration of the commitment period ordered in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, or the administrator of an outpatient treatment facility, before expiration of the outpatient treatment period set forth in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_j">
            <num>(j)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, may, on the advice of the medical officer of the facility, make application to the court for recommitment of the person to a treatment facility for inpatient treatment. An application for recommitment shall allege that the respondent is an alcohol-dependent person or a drug-dependent person who needs further inpatient treatment and is likely to benefit from such treatment, and, if the respondent is in an outpatient facility, that the respondent is not successfully participating in the outpatient program.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <heading>Recommitment hearing date</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Notice.Upon the receipt of an application for recommitment under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, the court shall assign a time for hearing no later than ten business days after the date the application was filed. A copy of the application and of the notice of the hearing, including the date fixed by the court, shall be sent by regular mail at least seven days before the hearing, to the respondent, the respondent's next of kin, the original applicant under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section if different from the applicant for recommitment, the respondent's parents or legal guardian if the respondent is a minor, the administrator of the treatment facility to which the respondent is admitted or to be admitted and any other person the court believes advisable. The applicant shall be notified of the hearing date not later than three business days before the hearing.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <heading>Recommitment order</heading>
            <content>
              <p>If after hearing all relevant evidence, including the results of any diagnostic examination, the court finds, by clear and convincing evidence, that the respondent is an alcohol-dependent person or a drug-dependent person who needs further inpatient treatment and who is likely to benefit from such treatment, and, if the respondent is in an outpatient treatment facility, that the respondent is not successfully participating in the outpatient program, it shall make an order of recommitment to an inpatient treatment facility for treatment for a period of not less than thirty nor more than one hundred eighty days. The court may not order recommitment of a respondent unless it determines that the treatment facility is able to provide adequate and appropriate treatment for such respondent and that the treatment is likely to be beneficial. The court shall not make more than one recommitment order immediately following an original commitment order under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section nor more than one recommitment order from an outpatient treatment facility. In any proceeding pursuant to this subsection, the provisions of section17a-686shall apply.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <heading>Expiration of recommitment period</heading>
            <content>
              <p>A person recommitted under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section who has not been discharged before the end of the recommitment period shall be discharged automatically at the expiration of that period. When the recommitted person is discharged, the administrator of the treatment facility shall, if advised to do so by the medical officer of the facility, refer the person to an outpatient treatment facility for treatment pursuant to the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_j">
            <num>(j)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_j">
            <num>(j)</num>
            <heading>Outpatient treatment after commitment or recommitment period</heading>
            <content>
              <p>A person referred to an outpatient treatment facility pursuant to the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section shall remain in outpatient treatment for a period of twelve months unless sooner discharged by the administrator of the treatment facility, on the advice of the medical officer of the facility, or unless, before expiration of the period of outpatient treatment, the administrator obtains a court order of recommitment for inpatient treatment as provided in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_k">
            <num>(k)</num>
            <heading>Discharge before expiration of commitment period</heading>
            <content>
              <p>The administrator of a treatment facility, on the advice of the medical officer, shall discharge a person committed or recommitted for treatment at any time before the end of the period for which such person has been committed if the person is no longer an alcohol-dependent person or a drug-dependent person in need of further treatment, further treatment will not be likely to bring about significant improvement in the person's condition or treatment is no longer adequate or appropriate.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_l">
            <num>(l)</num>
            <heading>Application to terminate commitment</heading>
            <content>
              <p>If a committed or recommitted person has not been discharged pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_k">
            <num>(k)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, any responsible person, including the committed or recommitted person, may make application to the Probate Court for termination of commitment or recommitment and discharge from the treatment facility. The application shall allege that the committed or recommitted person is no longer an alcohol-dependent person or a drug-dependent person in need of further treatment, that further treatment will not be likely to bring about significant improvement in the person's condition or that treatment is no longer adequate or appropriate. Upon receipt of any such application, such court shall assign a time, not later than ten business days thereafter, and a place for hearing such application, and shall cause reasonable notice thereof to be given to the applicant, the administrator of the treatment facility and any other person the court deems advisable. Such notice shall inform the applicant that he or she has the right to be present at the hearing and to present evidence at the hearing, that he or she has a right to counsel, that he or she, if indigent, has a right to have counsel appointed to represent him or her, and that such applicant has a right to cross-examine witnesses at any hearing on such application. The provisions of section17a-686shall apply. If, after hearing, the court determines that the grounds alleged in the application exist, it shall order termination of the commitment or recommitment and discharge of the committed or recommitted person, except that the court may not order the discharge of an alcohol-dependent person or drug-dependent person who the court determines is likely to become dangerous to himself or herself or dangerous to others when he is an intoxicated person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_m">
            <num>(m)</num>
            <heading>Temporary leave from treatment facility</heading>
            <content>
              <p>The administrator of a treatment facility to which a committed or recommitted person has been committed or recommitted may, under such restrictions or agreements as the administrator deems advisable and on the advice of the medical officer of the facility, permit the person to leave the treatment facility temporarily, in the charge of such person's guardian, conservator, relatives or friends, or by himself or herself.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_n">
            <num>(n)</num>
            <heading>Expenses</heading>
            <content>
              <p>All the expenses in connection with an application filed under sections17a-684to17a-686, inclusive, shall be paid by the applicant, unless the applicant is indigent, in which case such expenses shall be paid by the state from funds appropriated to the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services in accordance with rates established by said department, and attorney's fees shall be established by, and paid from funds appropriated to, the Judicial Department. If funds have not been included in the budget of the Judicial Department for such attorney's fees, such fees shall be established by the Probate Court Administrator and paid from the Probate Court Administration Fund, provided in no event shall the expenses under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_685__subsec_l">
            <num>(l)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section be paid for any one applicant for more than two hearings per year.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>