<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-855"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-855"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-855"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-855/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-855/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-855/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-855/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319l">
        <num>319l</num>
        <heading>Nursing Home Financial Assistance</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_855">
          <num>17a-855</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17a-310). State grants for community services and programs for older persons</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 17a-855. (Formerly Sec. 17a-310). State grants for community services and programs for older persons.The Department of Aging and Disability Services may make a grant to any city, town or borough or public or private agency, organization or institution for the following purposes: (1) For community planning and coordination of programs carrying out the purposes of the Older Americans Act of 1965, as amended; (2) for demonstration programs or activities particularly valuable in carrying out such purposes; (3) for training of special personnel needed to carry out such programs and activities; (4) for establishment of new or expansion of existing programs to carry out such purposes, including establishment of new or expansion of existing centers of service for older persons, providing recreational, cultural and other leisure time activities, and informational, transportation, referral and preretirement and postretirement counseling services for older persons and assisting such persons in providing volunteer community or civic services, except that no costs of construction, other than for minor alterations and repairs, shall be included in such establishment or expansion; and (5) for programs to develop or demonstrate approaches, methods and techniques for achieving or improving coordination of community services for older or aging persons and such other programs and services as may be allowed under Title III of the Older Americans Act of 1965, as amended, or to evaluate these approaches, techniques and methods, as well as others which may assist older or aging persons to enjoy wholesome and meaningful living and to continue to contribute to the strength and welfare of the state and nation.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>