<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-795"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-795"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-795"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-795/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-795/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-795/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-795/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319l">
        <num>319l</num>
        <heading>Nursing Home Financial Assistance</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_795">
          <num>17a-795</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17b-607). Assistive Technology Loan Program. Assistive technology evaluation and training services</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_795__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Aging and Disability Services is authorized to establish and administer state financing activities as outlined in the federal Assistive Technology Act of 2004, P.L. 108-364, as amended from time to time, to be known as the Assistive Technology Loan Program. The program shall be used by the commissioner to make and guarantee loans to persons with disabilities, older adults or the family members of persons with disabilities or older adults for the purchase of assistive technology and adaptive equipment and services. Each such loan shall be made for a term of not more than ten years. Any loans made under this section shall bear interest at a fixed rate not to exceed six per cent. The commissioner is authorized to expend any funds necessary for the reasonable direct expenses relating to the administration of the program. The commissioner shall adopt regulations, in accordance with the provisions of chapter 54, to implement the purposes of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_795__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The State Bond Commission shall have power from time to time to authorize the issuance of bonds of the state in one or more series in accordance with section3-20and in a principal amount necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, but not in excess of an aggregate amount of one million dollars. All of the bonds shall</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_795__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>be payable at such place or places as may be determined by the Treasurer pursuant to section3-19,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_795__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>bear such date or dates,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_795__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>mature at such time or times, not exceeding five years from their respective dates,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_795__subsec_b__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>bear interest at such rate or different or varying rates and payable at such time or times,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_795__subsec_b__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>be in such denominations,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_795__subsec_b__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>be in such form with or without interest coupons attached,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_795__subsec_b__subsec_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>carry such registration and transfer privileges,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_795__subsec_b__subsec_8">
              <num>(8)</num>
              <content>
                <p>be payable in such medium of payment, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_795__subsec_b__subsec_9">
              <num>(9)</num>
              <content>
                <p>be subject to such terms of redemption with or without premium as, irrespective of the provisions of section3-20, may be provided by the authorization of the State Bond Commission or fixed in accordance therewith. The proceeds of the sale of such bonds shall be deposited in the Assistive Technology Loan Program created by this section. Such bonds shall be general obligations of the state and the full faith and credit of the state of Connecticut are pledged for the payment of the principal of and interest on such bonds as the same become due. Accordingly, and as part of the contract of the state with the holders of such bonds, appropriation of all amounts necessary for punctual payment of such principal and interest is hereby made and the Treasurer shall pay such principal and interest as the same become due. Net earnings on investments or reinvestments of proceeds, accrued interest and premiums on the issuance of such bonds, after payment therefrom of expenses incurred by the Treasurer or State Bond Commission in connection with their issuance, shall be deposited in the General Fund of the state.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_795__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Connecticut Tech Act Project, within the Department of Aging and Disability Services and as authorized by 29 USC 3001, as amended from time to time, may provide assistive technology evaluation and training services upon the request of any person or any public or private entity, to the extent persons who provide assistive technology services are available. The project may charge a fee to any person or entity receiving such assistive technology evaluation and training services to reimburse the department for its costs. The Commissioner of Aging and Disability Services shall establish fees at reasonable rates that will cover the department's direct and indirect costs.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>