<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-818"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-818"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-818"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-818/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-818/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-818/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-818/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319l">
        <num>319l</num>
        <heading>Nursing Home Financial Assistance</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_818">
          <num>17a-818</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 10-303). Food service facilities and vending stands in public buildings controlled by Department of Aging and Disability Services. Permissible uses of vending machine income</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_818__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The authority in charge of any building or property owned, operated or leased by the state or any municipality therein shall grant to the Department of Aging and Disability Services a permit to operate in such building or on such property a food service facility, a vending machine or a stand for the vending of newspapers, periodicals, confections, tobacco products, food and such other articles as such authority approves when, in the opinion of such authority, such facility, machine or stand is desirable in such location. Any person operating such a stand in any such location on October 1, 1945, shall be permitted to continue such operation, but upon such person's ceasing such operation such authority shall grant a permit for continued operation to the Department of Aging and Disability Services. The department may establish a training facility at any such location.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_818__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <heading>Pursuant to the Randolph-Sheppard Vending Stand Act, 49 Stat</heading>
            <content>
              <p>1559</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_818__subsec_b__subsec_1936">
              <num>(1936)</num>
              <content>
                <p>, 20 USC 107, as amended from time to time, the Department of Aging and Disability Services is authorized to maintain a nonlapsing account and to accrue interest thereon for federal vending machine income which, in accordance with federal regulations, shall be used for the payment of fringe benefits to the vending facility operators by the Department of Aging and Disability Services.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_818__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Aging and Disability Services may maintain a nonlapsing account and accrue interest thereon for state and local vending machine income which shall be used for the payment of fringe benefits, training and support to vending facilities operators, to provide entrepreneurial and independent-living training and equipment to children who are blind or visually impaired and adults who are blind and for other vocational rehabilitation programs and services for adults who are blind.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_818__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Aging and Disability Services may disburse state and local vending machine income to student or client activity funds, as defined in section4-52.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>