<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-870"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-870"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-870"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-870/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-870/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-870/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-870/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319l">
        <num>319l</num>
        <heading>Nursing Home Financial Assistance</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_870">
          <num>17a-870</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17a-405). Office of the Long-Term Care Ombudsman. Regional ombudsmen. Appointments. Inclusion in classified service. Definitions</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_870__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <heading>As used in this chapter:
(1) “State agency” means the Department of Aging and Disability Services</heading>
            <paragraph eId="17a_870__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Office” or “Office of the Long-Term Care Ombudsman” means the organizational unit which is headed by the State Long-Term Care Ombudsman established in this section.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_870__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“State Ombudsman” means the individual who heads the office established in this section.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_870__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Program” means the long-term care ombudsman program established in this section.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_870__subsec_a__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Representative of the office” includes a regional ombudsman, a residents' advocate or an employee of the Office of the Long-Term Care Ombudsman who is individually designated by the State Ombudsman.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_870__subsec_a__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Resident” means an individual who resides in a long-term care facility.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_870__subsec_a__subsec_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Long-term care facility” means any skilled nursing facility, as defined in Section 1819</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_870__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the Social Security Act, (42 USC 1395i-3</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_870__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>) any nursing facility, as defined in Section 1919</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_870__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the Social Security Act, (42 USC 1396r</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_870__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>) a board and care facility as defined in Section 102</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_870__subsec_a__subsec_19">
              <num>(19)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of the federal Older Americans Act, (42 USC 3002</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_870__subsec_a__subsec_19">
              <num>(19)</num>
              <content>
                <p>) and for purposes of ombudsman program coverage, an institution regulated by the state pursuant to Section 1616</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_870__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the Social Security Act, (42 USC 1382e</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_870__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>) and any other adult care home similar to a facility or nursing facility or board and care home.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_870__subsec_e__subsec_8">
              <num>(8)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of Aging and Disability Services.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_870__subsec_e__subsec_9">
              <num>(9)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Applicant” means an individual who has applied for admission to a long-term care facility.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_870__subsec_e__subsec_10">
              <num>(10)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Resident representative” means (A) an individual chosen by the resident to act on behalf of the resident in order to support the resident in decision making, accessing medical, social or other personal information of the resident, managing financial matters, or receiving notifications; (B) a person authorized by state or federal law to act on behalf of the resident in order to support the resident in decision making, accessing medical, social or other personal information of the resident, managing financial matters, or receiving notifications; (C) a legal representative, as used in Section 712 of the Older Americans Act; or (D) the court-appointed guardian or conservator of a resident.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_870__subsec_e__subsec_10__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>an individual chosen by the resident to act on behalf of the resident in order to support the resident in decision making, accessing medical, social or other personal information of the resident, managing financial matters, or receiving notifications;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_870__subsec_e__subsec_10__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a person authorized by state or federal law to act on behalf of the resident in order to support the resident in decision making, accessing medical, social or other personal information of the resident, managing financial matters, or receiving notifications;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_870__subsec_e__subsec_10__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a legal representative, as used in Section 712 of the Older Americans Act; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_870__subsec_e__subsec_10__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the court-appointed guardian or conservator of a resident.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_870__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>There is established an independent Office of the Long-Term Care Ombudsman within the Department of Aging and Disability Services. The Commissioner of Aging and Disability Services shall appoint a State Ombudsman who shall be selected from among individuals with expertise and experience in the fields of long-term care and advocacy to head the office and the State Ombudsman shall appoint regional ombudsmen. In the event the State Ombudsman or a regional ombudsman is unable to fulfill the duties of the office, the commissioner shall appoint an acting State Ombudsman and the State Ombudsman shall appoint an acting regional ombudsman.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_870__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_870__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, on and after July 1, 1990, the positions of State Ombudsman and regional ombudsmen shall be classified service positions. The State Ombudsman and regional ombudsmen holding said positions on said date shall continue to serve in their positions as if selected through classified service procedures. As vacancies occur in such positions thereafter, such vacancies shall be filled in accordance with classified service procedures.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_870__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The activities of the State Ombudsman or representatives of the office do not constitute lobbying under 45 CFR Part 93.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>