<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-2b"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-2b"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-2b"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-2b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-2b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-2b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-2b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_201">
        <num>201</num>
        <heading>State and Local Revenue Services. Department of Revenue Services</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_2b">
          <num>12-2b</num>
          <heading>Duties of Secretary of Office of Policy and Management re municipal assessment</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-2b. Duties of Secretary of Office of Policy and Management re municipal assessment.The Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management shall:
(1) In consultation with the Commissioner of Agriculture, develop schedules of unit prices for property classified under sections12-107ato12-107d, inclusive, update such schedules by October 1, 1990, and every five years thereafter, and make such data, studies and schedules available to municipalities and the public;
(2) Develop regulations setting forth standards and tests for: Certifying revaluation companies and their employees, which regulations shall ensure that a revaluation company is competent in appraising and valuing property, certifying revaluation companies and their employees, requiring that a certified employee supervise all valuations performed by a revaluation company for municipalities, maintaining lists of certified revaluation companies and upon request, advising municipalities in drafting contracts with revaluation companies, and conducting investigations and withdrawing the certification of any revaluation company or employee found not to be conforming to such regulations. The regulations shall provide for the imposition of a fee payable to a testing service designated by the secretary to administer certification examinations;
(3) By the secretary, or by an agent whom the secretary may appoint, inquire if all property taxes that are due and collectible by each town or city not consolidated with a town, are in fact collected and paid to the treasurer thereof in the manner prescribed by law, and if accounts and records of the tax collectors and treasurers of such entities are adequate and properly kept. The secretary may hold meetings, conferences or schools for assessors, tax collectors or municipal finance officers and make recommendations concerning assessor, tax collector or municipal finance officer training, including, but not limited to, online or in-person training programs to be offered by public institutions of higher education for the purpose of supporting a career pathway for assessors, tax collectors and municipal finance officers; and
(4) Provide jointly with the Commissioner of Veterans Affairs a written notice annually to municipalities and veterans' organizations of the property tax exemptions that a municipality may opt to approve under chapter 203 for veterans, veterans' relatives or spouses or persons killed in action while performing active military duty with the armed forces.
See Sec. 12-1c re transfer of certain functions, powers and duties under this chapter to the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>