<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-18b"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-18b"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-18b"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-18b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-18b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-18b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-18b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_201">
        <num>201</num>
        <heading>State and Local Revenue Services. Department of Revenue Services</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_18b">
          <num>12-18b</num>
          <heading>Grants in lieu of taxes for certain property</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of this section:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“College and hospital property” means all real property described in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-20a;</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Equalized net grand list per capita” means the grand list of a municipality upon which taxes were levied for the general expenses of such municipality three years prior to the fiscal year in which a grant under this section is to be paid, equalized in accordance with the provisions of section10-261aand divided by the total population of such municipality;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Municipality” means any town, city, borough, consolidated town and city and consolidated town and borough;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“State, municipal or tribal property” means all real property described in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-19a;</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_a__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Tier one municipality” means a municipality with an equalized net grand list per capita of less than one hundred thousand dollars;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_a__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Tier two municipality” means a municipality with an equalized net grand list per capita of one hundred thousand dollars to two hundred thousand dollars; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_a__subsec_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Tier three municipality” means a municipality with an equalized net grand list per capita of greater than two hundred thousand dollars.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of sections12-19aand12-20a, on or before September thirtieth, annually, all funds appropriated for state grants in lieu of taxes shall be payable to municipalities and fire districts pursuant to the provisions of this section. On or before January first, annually, the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management shall determine the amount due, as a state grant in lieu of taxes, to each municipality and fire district in this state wherein college and hospital property is located and to each municipality and fire district in this state wherein state, municipal or tribal property, except that which was acquired and used for highways and bridges, but not excepting property acquired and used for highway administration or maintenance purposes, is located. Such determination shall be calculated based on assessed values provided to the Office of Policy and Management prior to the preceding April first, pursuant to section12-19b.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The grant payable to any municipality or fire district for state, municipal or tribal property under the provisions of this section in the fiscal year ending June 30, 2022, and each fiscal year thereafter, shall be equal to the total of:
(A) One hundred per cent of the property taxes that would have been paid with respect to any facility designated by the Commissioner of Correction, on or before August first of each year, to be a correctional facility administered under the auspices of the Department of Correction or a juvenile residential center under direction of the Judicial Branch that was used for incarcerative purposes during the preceding fiscal year. If a list containing the name and location of such designated facilities and information concerning their use for purposes of incarceration during the preceding fiscal year is not available from the Secretary of the State on August first of any year, the Commissioner of Correction shall, on said date, certify to the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management a list containing such information;
(B) One hundred per cent of the property taxes that would have been paid with respect to that portion of the John Dempsey Hospital located at The University of Connecticut Health Center in Farmington that is used as a permanent medical ward for prisoners under the custody of the Department of Correction. Nothing in this section shall be construed as designating any portion of The University of Connecticut Health Center John Dempsey Hospital as a correctional facility;
(C) One hundred per cent of the property taxes that would have been paid on any land designated within the 1983 Settlement boundary and taken into trust by the federal government for the Mashantucket Pequot Tribal Nation on or after June 8, 1999;
(D) One hundred per cent of the property taxes that would have been paid with respect to the property and facilities owned by the Connecticut Port Authority;
(E) Subject to the provisions of subsection</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>One hundred per cent of the property taxes that would have been paid with respect to any facility designated by the Commissioner of Correction, on or before August first of each year, to be a correctional facility administered under the auspices of the Department of Correction or a juvenile residential center under direction of the Judicial Branch that was used for incarcerative purposes during the preceding fiscal year. If a list containing the name and location of such designated facilities and information concerning their use for purposes of incarceration during the preceding fiscal year is not available from the Secretary of the State on August first of any year, the Commissioner of Correction shall, on said date, certify to the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management a list containing such information;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>One hundred per cent of the property taxes that would have been paid with respect to that portion of the John Dempsey Hospital located at The University of Connecticut Health Center in Farmington that is used as a permanent medical ward for prisoners under the custody of the Department of Correction. Nothing in this section shall be construed as designating any portion of The University of Connecticut Health Center John Dempsey Hospital as a correctional facility;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>One hundred per cent of the property taxes that would have been paid on any land designated within the 1983 Settlement boundary and taken into trust by the federal government for the Mashantucket Pequot Tribal Nation on or after June 8, 1999;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>One hundred per cent of the property taxes that would have been paid with respect to the property and facilities owned by the Connecticut Port Authority;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_E">
                <num>(E)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Subject to the provisions of subsection</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-19a, sixty-five per cent of the property taxes that would have been paid with respect to the buildings and grounds comprising Connecticut Valley Hospital and Whiting Forensic Hospital in Middletown;
(F) With respect to any municipality in which more than fifty per cent of the property is state-owned real property, one hundred per cent of the property taxes that would have been paid with respect to such state-owned property;
(G) Forty-five per cent of the property taxes that would have been paid with respect to all municipally owned airports; except for the exemption applicable to such property, on the assessment list in such municipality for the assessment date two years prior to the commencement of the state fiscal year in which such grant is payable. The grant provided pursuant to this section for any municipally owned airport shall be paid to any municipality in which the airport is located, except that the grant applicable to Sikorsky Airport shall be paid one-half to the town of Stratford and one-half to the city of Bridgeport;
(H) One hundred per cent of the property taxes that would have been paid with respect to any land designated within the 1983 Settlement boundary and taken into trust by the federal government for the Mashantucket Pequot Tribal Nation prior to June 8, 1999, or taken into trust by the federal government for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut, provided the real property subject to this subparagraph shall be the land only, and shall not include the assessed value of any structures, buildings or other improvements on such land; and
(I) Forty-five per cent of the property taxes that would have been paid with respect to all other state-owned real property.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The grant payable to any municipality or fire district for college and hospital property under the provisions of this section in the fiscal year ending June 30, 2017, and each fiscal year thereafter, shall be equal to the total of seventy-seven per cent of the property taxes that, except for any exemption applicable to any college and hospital property under the provisions of section12-81, would have been paid with respect to college and hospital property on the assessment list in such municipality or fire district for the assessment date two years prior to the commencement of the state fiscal year in which such grant is payable.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management shall list municipalities, boroughs and fire districts based on the equalized net grand list per capita. Boroughs and fire districts shall have the same equalized net grand list per capita as the town, city, consolidated town and city or consolidated town and borough in which such borough or fire district is located.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the fiscal year ending June 30, 2022, and each fiscal year thereafter:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The total amount of the grants paid to a municipality or fire district pursuant to the provisions of this subsection shall not be lower than the total amount of the payment in lieu of taxes grants received by such municipality or fire district for the fiscal year ending June 30, 2021.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the total of grants payable to each municipality and fire district in accordance with the provisions of subsections</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section exceeds the amount appropriated for the purposes of said subsection for a fiscal year:
(A) Each tier one municipality shall receive fifty-three per cent of the grant amount payable to such municipality as calculated under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section;
(B) Each tier two municipality shall receive forty-three per cent of the grant amount payable to such municipality as calculated under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section; and
(C) Each tier three municipality shall receive thirty-three per cent of the grant amount payable to such municipality as calculated under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Each municipality designated as an alliance district pursuant to section10-262uor in which more than fifty per cent of the property is state-owned real property shall be classified as a tier one municipality.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Each fire district shall receive the same percentage of the grant amount payable to the municipality in which it is located.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>(A) If the total of grants payable to each municipality and fire district in accordance with the provisions of subsection</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_5__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the total of grants payable to each municipality and fire district in accordance with the provisions of subsection</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section exceeds the amount appropriated for the purposes of said subsection, but such appropriated amount exceeds the amount required for grants payable to each municipality and fire district in accordance with the provisions of subdivisions</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>to</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>, inclusive, of this subsection, the amount of the grant payable to each municipality and fire district shall be increased proportionately.
(B) If the total of grants payable to each municipality and fire district in accordance with the provisions of subdivisions</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_4__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the total of grants payable to each municipality and fire district in accordance with the provisions of subdivisions</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>to</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>, inclusive, of this subsection exceeds the amount appropriated for the purposes of said subdivisions, the amount of the grant payable to each municipality and fire district shall be reduced proportionately, except that no grant shall be reduced below the amount set forth in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, inclusive, of this section and sections12-19band12-20b:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The grant payable to any municipality or fire district with respect to a campus of the United States Department of Veterans Affairs Connecticut Healthcare Systems shall be one hundred per cent;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For any municipality receiving payments under section15-120ss, property located in such municipality at Bradley International Airport shall not be included in the calculation of any state grant in lieu of taxes pursuant to this section;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_d__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The city of Bridgeport shall be due five million dollars, annually, which amount shall be in addition to the amount due such city pursuant to the provisions of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section;</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_d__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>There shall be an amount due the town of Voluntown, with respect to any state-owned forest, of an additional sixty thousand dollars, annually, for reimbursement to municipalities for loss of taxes on private tax-exempt property;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_d__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The amount due the town of Branford, with respect to the Connecticut Hospice located in said town, shall be one hundred thousand dollars, annually, for reimbursement to municipalities for loss of taxes on private tax-exempt property; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_d__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The amount due the city of New London, with respect to the United States Coast Guard Academy located in said city, shall be one million dollars, annually, for reimbursement to municipalities for loss of taxes on private tax-exempt property.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_18b__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For purposes of this section, any real property that is owned by The University of Connecticut Health Center Finance Corporation established pursuant to the provisions of sections10a-250to10a-263, inclusive, or by one or more subsidiary corporations established pursuant to subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_18b__subsec_f__subsec_13">
              <num>(13)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of section10a-254and that is free from taxation pursuant to the provisions of section10a-259shall be deemed to be state-owned real property.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>