<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129u"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129u"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-129u"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129u/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129u/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129u/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-129u/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_204">
        <num>204</num>
        <heading>Local Levy and Collection of Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_129u">
          <num>12-129u</num>
          <heading>Municipal option to abate taxes on historic agricultural structures</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_129u__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_129u__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Municipality” means any town, consolidated town and city, consolidated town and borough, city or borough;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_129u__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Historic agricultural structure” means a barn listed on the National Register of Historic Places, 16 USC 470a, as amended from time to time, or on the state register of historic places, as defined in section10-410, or a stone wall or other structure, including the land necessary for the function of the barn, stone wall or other structure, currently or formerly used for agricultural purposes and at least seventy-five years old, provided such barn, stone wall or other structure (A) provides scenic enjoyment to the general public from a public road, (B) is historically important on a local, regional, state or national level, either independently or as part of an historic district established under section7-147aor by special act, or (C) has physical or aesthetic features that contribute to the historic or cultural integrity of a property listed on or eligible for listing on the National Register of Historic Places, 16 USC 470a, as amended from time to time, or on the state register of historic places, as defined in section10-410;</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_129u__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>provides scenic enjoyment to the general public from a public road,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_129u__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>is historically important on a local, regional, state or national level, either independently or as part of an historic district established under section7-147aor by special act, or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_129u__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>has physical or aesthetic features that contribute to the historic or cultural integrity of a property listed on or eligible for listing on the National Register of Historic Places, 16 USC 470a, as amended from time to time, or on the state register of historic places, as defined in section10-410;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_129u__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Preservation easement” means an easement over an historic agricultural structure conveyed to a municipality for a term of up to ten years;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_129u__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Easement agreement” means the document conveying the preservation easement;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_129u__subsec_a__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Legislative body” means the legislative body of a municipality or, where the legislative body is a town meeting, the board of selectmen or town council; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_129u__subsec_a__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Property tax payment amount” means the amount of property tax due for an historic agricultural structure subject to a preservation easement as established by the legislative body. Such amount shall be fixed for the term of the easement.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_129u__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The legislative body of any municipality that has, by ordinance, adopted the preservation program described in this section may abate the property taxes due for a term of up to ten years with respect to an historic agricultural structure. Such term shall commence with the calendar year immediately preceding the beginning of the tax year for which such taxes are due. Application for such abatement shall include an offer to grant a preservation easement to the municipality for the term of the abatement. Such application shall be made on a form prescribed by the legislative body and shall contain a certification by the owner that, during the term of any such preservation easement accepted by the legislative body, the owner shall maintain the historic agricultural structure in keeping with its historic integrity and character. If the legislative body approves such application, it shall establish the property tax payment amount for such historic agricultural structure so as to reflect, in the sole discretion of the legislative body, the value of the public benefit received from the preservation easement.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_129u__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_129u__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The legislative body shall release a preservation easement upon request of the owner if the legislative body determines that (A) the owner cannot comply with the terms of the easement agreement due to extreme personal hardship, or (B) the historic agricultural structure has been significantly damaged or destroyed by fire, storm or any other unforeseen circumstance not within the control of the owner.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_129u__subsec_c__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the owner cannot comply with the terms of the easement agreement due to extreme personal hardship, or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_129u__subsec_c__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the historic agricultural structure has been significantly damaged or destroyed by fire, storm or any other unforeseen circumstance not within the control of the owner.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_129u__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If, during the term of a preservation easement, the legislative body determines that the owner has failed to maintain an historic agricultural structure in accordance with the easement agreement, the legislative body may terminate the easement and levy an early release penalty.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>