<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-476a"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-476a"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-476a"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-476a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-476a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-476a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-476a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_221">
        <num>221</num>
        <heading>Real Estate Conveyance Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_476a">
          <num>12-476a</num>
          <heading>Fuel transporters to report to commissioner. Penalty for violations</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-476a. Fuel transporters to report to commissioner. Penalty for violations.Every railroad company, every street, suburban or interurban railroad company, every pipe line company, every water transportation company, and every common carrier transporting fuel, either in interstate commerce to or from points within the state, and every person transporting fuel by whatever manner to or from a point in the state, shall at any time, and from time to time, upon written request of the commissioner, report under penalty of false statement on forms prescribed by said commissioner all deliveries of fuel so made to or from points within the state, for such periods as the commissioner may specify. Such reports shall show the name and address of the person to whom the deliveries of fuel have actually and in fact been made, the name and address of the originally named consignee, if fuel has been delivered to any other than the originally named consignee, the point of origin, the point of delivery, the date of delivery, and the number and initials of each tank car and the number of gallons contained therein, if shipped by rail, the name of the boat, barge or vessel, and the number of gallons contained therein, if shipped by water, the license number of each tank truck and the number of gallons contained therein, if transported by motor truck, or, if delivered by other means, the manner in which such delivery is made; and such other additional information relative to shipments of fuel as the commissioner may require. Any person who violates any provision of this section shall be fined five hundred dollars for each offense.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>