<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-20b"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-20b"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-20b"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-20b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-20b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-20b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-20b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_201">
        <num>201</num>
        <heading>State and Local Revenue Services. Department of Revenue Services</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_20b">
          <num>12-20b</num>
          <heading>Valuation of property of private colleges and hospitals for grants under section12-18bor12-20a. Revaluation. Appeals</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-20b. Valuation of property of private colleges and hospitals for grants under section12-18bor12-20a. Revaluation. Appeals.Not later than April first in each year, any municipality to which a grant is payable under the provisions of section12-18bor12-20ashall provide the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management with the assessed valuation of the tax-exempt real property as of the immediately preceding October first, adjusted in accordance with any gradual increase in or deferment of assessed values of real property implemented in accordance with section12-62c, which is required for computation of such grant. Any municipality which neglects to transmit to the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management the assessed valuation as required by this section shall forfeit two hundred fifty dollars to the state, provided the secretary may waive such forfeiture in accordance with procedures and standards adopted by regulation in accordance with chapter 54. Said secretary may, on or before the first day of August of the state fiscal year in which such grant is payable, reevaluate any such property when, in his or her judgment, the valuation is inaccurate and shall notify such municipality of such reevaluation. Any municipality aggrieved by the action of said secretary under the provisions of this section may, not later than ten business days following receipt of such notice, appeal to the secretary for a hearing concerning such reevaluation, provided such appeal shall be in writing and shall include a statement as to the reasons for such appeal. The secretary shall, not later than ten business days following receipt of such appeal, grant or deny such hearing by notification in writing, including in the event of a denial, a statement as to the reasons for such denial. If any municipality is aggrieved by the action of the secretary following such hearing or in denying any such hearing, the municipality may not later than two weeks after such notice, appeal to the superior court for the judicial district in which the municipality is located. Any such appeal shall be privileged. If any recomputation is effected as the result of the provisions of this section on or after the January first following the date on which the municipality has provided the assessed valuation in question, any adjustments to the amount due to any municipality for the period for which such adjustments were made shall be made in the next payment the Treasurer shall make to such municipality pursuant to this section.
See Sec. 12-1c re transfer of certain functions, powers and duties under this chapter to the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>