<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-34c"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-34c"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-34c"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-34c/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-34c/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-34c/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-34c/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_201">
        <num>201</num>
        <heading>State and Local Revenue Services. Department of Revenue Services</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_34c">
          <num>12-34c</num>
          <heading>Enabling the Commissioner of Revenue Services to enter into agreements with other states for purposes of reciprocal enforcement of tax laws of participating states</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_34c__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Revenue Services may enter into agreements with other states providing for reciprocal enforcement of the tax laws of the states entering into such reciprocal arrangements. As used herein, “state” shall include the District of Columbia. The provisions of such reciprocal arrangements may include, but are not limited to, the following:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_34c__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Each participating state may require any business within such state to collect or withhold those taxes for which a person becomes liable in another state in the arrangement as a result of a transaction or employment with such business in the participating state, provided such taxes are required to be collected or withheld under such circumstances in the other state;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_34c__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>each participating state may, with regard to any business within such state, administer, enforce, audit, assess and collect, on behalf of any other state participating in the agreement, the taxes which are imposed on such business under the laws of such other participating state;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_34c__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the appropriate official of each participating state may bring suit to collect the taxes which are imposed under the laws of such state in the courts of any other participating state;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_34c__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>each participating state shall bear the costs which are incurred by it under such reciprocal agreements, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_34c__subsec_a__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the participating states shall decide upon commencement and termination of such reciprocal agreements.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_34c__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For purposes of making payment of any taxes which are collected by the Commissioner of Revenue Services on behalf of any other participating state under reciprocal agreements as described in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_34c__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, the Comptroller, upon certification by the commissioner, is authorized to draw on the Treasurer in the amount of such payment and the Treasurer shall pay the amount thereof from the fund to which such taxes are credited.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>