<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-20a"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-20a"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-20a"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-20a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-20a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-20a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-20a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_201">
        <num>201</num>
        <heading>State and Local Revenue Services. Department of Revenue Services</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_20a">
          <num>12-20a</num>
          <heading>Grants in lieu of taxes on real property of private colleges, general hospitals, chronic disease hospitals and certain urgent care facilities</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_20a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Until the fiscal year commencing July 1, 2016, on or before January first, annually, the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management shall determine the amount due to each municipality in the state, in accordance with this section, as a state grant in lieu of taxes with respect to real property owned by any private nonprofit institution of higher learning or any nonprofit general hospital facility or freestanding chronic disease hospital or an urgent care facility that operates for at least twelve hours a day and that had been the location of a nonprofit general hospital for at least a portion of calendar year 1996 to receive payments in lieu of taxes for such property, exclusive of any such facility operated by the federal government, except a campus of the United States Department of Veterans Affairs Connecticut Healthcare Systems, or the state of Connecticut or any subdivision thereof. As used in this section, “private nonprofit institution of higher learning” means any such institution, as defined in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_20a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section10a-34, or any independent institution of higher education, as defined in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_20a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section10a-173, that is engaged primarily in education beyond the high school level, and offers courses of instruction for which college or university-level credit may be given or may be received by transfer, the property of which is exempt from property tax under any of the subdivisions of section12-81; “nonprofit general hospital facility” means any such facility that is used primarily for the purpose of general medical care and treatment, exclusive of any hospital facility used primarily for the care and treatment of special types of disease or physical or mental conditions; and “freestanding chronic disease hospital” has the same meaning as “chronic disease hospital” as defined in section19a-490, excluding any such facility having an ownership affiliation with and operated in the same location as a chronic and convalescent nursing home.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_20a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The grant payable to any municipality under the provisions of this section in the state fiscal year commencing July 1, 1999, and in each fiscal year thereafter, shall be equal to seventy-seven per cent of the property taxes which, except for any exemption applicable to any such institution of higher education or general hospital facility under the provisions of section12-81, would have been paid with respect to such exempt real property on the assessment list in such municipality for the assessment date two years prior to the commencement of the state fiscal year in which such grant is payable. The amount of the grant payable to each municipality in any year in accordance with this section shall be reduced proportionately in the event that the total of such grants in such year exceeds the amount appropriated for the purposes of this section with respect to such year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_20a__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_20a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, the amount of the grant payable to any municipality under the provisions of this section with respect to a campus of the United States Department of Veterans Affairs Connecticut Healthcare Systems shall be as follows:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_20a__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For the fiscal year ending June 30, 2007, twenty per cent of the amount payable in accordance with said subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_20a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>;</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_20a__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>for the fiscal year ending June 30, 2008, forty per cent of such amount;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_20a__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>for the fiscal year ending June 30, 2009, sixty per cent of such amount;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_20a__subsec_b__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>for the fiscal year ending June 30, 2010, eighty per cent of such amount;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_20a__subsec_b__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>for the fiscal year ending June 30, 2011, and each fiscal year thereafter, one hundred per cent of such amount.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_20a__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section and section12-20b, the word “municipality” means any town, consolidated town and city, consolidated town and borough, borough, district, as defined in section7-324, and any city not consolidated with a town.
See Sec. 12-1c re transfer of certain functions, powers and duties under this chapter to the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>