<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-782"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-782"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-782"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-782/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-782/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-782/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-782/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319l">
        <num>319l</num>
        <heading>Nursing Home Financial Assistance</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_782">
          <num>17a-782</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17b-653). Eligibility for services</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_782__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Vocational rehabilitation services shall be provided, with or without public cost, directly or through public or private instrumentalities, as part of an individual plan for employment for a person with disabilities determined to be eligible by the Department of Aging and Disability Services, in accordance with Title I of the Rehabilitation Act, 29 USC 701 et seq., as amended from time to time. Nothing in this section shall be construed to mean that an individual's ability or inability to share in the cost of vocational rehabilitation services may be taken into account during the determination of eligibility for such services.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_782__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If vocational rehabilitation services cannot be provided for all eligible persons with disabilities who apply for such services, the Department of Aging and Disability Services shall determine, in accordance with Title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, 29 USC 701 et seq., and federal regulations, as amended from time to time, the order to be followed in selecting those to whom such services will be provided.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_782__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing in section17a-781or subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_782__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section shall be construed to preclude provision of vocational rehabilitation services, with or without public cost, to a person with a disability under an extended evaluation for a total period not in excess of eighteen months, in accordance with Title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, 29 USC 701 et seq., as amended from time to time.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_782__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Aging and Disability Services may adopt regulations in accordance with the provisions of chapter 54 to establish standards and procedures governing the provision of vocational rehabilitation services and, where appropriate, a means test to determine, based upon the financial need of each eligible person with disabilities, the extent to which such services will be provided at public cost. Any funds received by the Department of Aging and Disability Services from individuals or third parties for the provision of vocational rehabilitation services shall be used by the department to provide such services. The regulations may also prescribe the procedures to be used when payment is made by individuals required to contribute to the cost of vocational rehabilitation services. Regulations developed to implement a means test shall include, but not be limited to:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_782__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An exemption for any individual with an income of less than one hundred per cent of the state median income and assets which are less than five thousand dollars;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_782__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>an exemption for services covered in an individual plan for employment in effect at the time of implementation of the means test;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_782__subsec_d__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>an exclusion from an individual's income of the costs of necessary and reasonable disability-related expenses including, but not limited to, personal attendant services and medications for which payment is unavailable to the individual through other benefits or resources;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_782__subsec_d__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>an exclusion from the individual's assets of the value of the individual's primary residence and motor vehicle;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_782__subsec_d__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a method by which the Commissioner of Aging and Disability Services may reduce the level of required contributions by an individual in the case of undue hardship; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_782__subsec_d__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a requirement that the Department of Aging and Disability Services notify an individual of the results of the means test analysis within thirty days of receipt of necessary financial information from the individual. Such means test shall not apply to services covered under a determination of financial need made by an institution of higher education. The Department of Aging and Disability Services shall develop the regulations in consultation with representatives of providers of vocational rehabilitation services and recipients of such services or their representatives.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>