<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-555b"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-555b"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-555b"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-555b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-555b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-555b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-555b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_225">
        <num>225</num>
        <heading>Room Occupancy Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_555b">
          <num>12-555b</num>
          <heading>Certificate of registration</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_555b__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No person whose activities make such person subject to this chapter shall engage in such activities in this state unless a certificate of registration has been issued to such person as hereinafter prescribed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_555b__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person desiring to engage in activities subject to this chapter shall file with the commissioner an application for a certificate of registration for each location where such activities are conducted. Each such application shall be made on a form prescribed by the commissioner and shall set forth the name under which the applicant operates or intends to operate, the location of his operations, and such other information as the commissioner requires. The application shall be signed by the owner, if a natural person, by a member or partner in the case of an association or partnership, or by an executive officer or any other person specifically authorized by the corporation to sign the application in the case of a corporation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_555b__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>After compliance with subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_555b__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_555b__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section by the applicant, the commissioner may grant and issue to such applicant a separate certificate for each place of operation within the state. A certificate of registration shall not be assignable and shall be valid only for the person in whose name it is issued. The certificate shall at all times be conspicuously displayed at the place for which issued. The commissioner may refuse to issue a certificate of registration if he believes that the payment of any amount due or likely to become due under this chapter is jeopardized. The commissioner may continue such refusal until he believes that the payment of such amounts are no longer in jeopardy.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_555b__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whenever any person fails to comply with any provision of this chapter or any regulation of the commissioner prescribed and adopted under this chapter, the commissioner, upon hearing, after ten days notice in writing to such person, specifying the time and place of hearing and requiring him to show cause why his certificate of registration should not be revoked, may revoke or suspend any one or more of the certificates of registration held by such person. The notice may be served personally or by registered or certified mail. The commissioner shall not issue a new certificate of registration after the revocation of a certificate of registration unless he is satisfied that the former holder of the certificate of registration will comply with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_555b__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who knowingly violates any provision of this section shall be fined not more than five hundred dollars or be imprisoned not more than three months or both for each offense.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>