<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-552"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-552"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-552"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-552/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-552/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-552/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-552/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_225">
        <num>225</num>
        <heading>Room Occupancy Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_552">
          <num>12-552</num>
          <heading>Records. Examinations. Hearings. Testimony</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_552__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Revenue Services may require all persons subject to a tax imposed under this chapter to keep such records as he may prescribe, and he may require the production of books, papers, documents and other data, to provide or secure information pertinent to the determination of the taxes imposed by this chapter and the enforcement and collection thereof.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_552__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner or any person authorized by him may examine the books, papers, records and equipment of any person liable under the provisions of this chapter and may investigate the character of the business of the person in order to verify the accuracy of any return made or, if no return is made by the person, to ascertain and determine the amount required to be paid.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_552__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner and any representative of the commissioner authorized to conduct any inquiry, investigation or hearing hereunder may administer oaths and take testimony under oath relative to the matter of inquiry or investigation. At any hearing ordered by the commissioner, the commissioner or his representative authorized to conduct such hearing and to issue such process may subpoena witnesses and require the production of books, papers and documents pertinent to such inquiry. No witness under subpoena authorized to be issued by the provisions of this chapter shall be excused from testifying or from producing books or other documentary evidence on the ground that such testimony or the production of such books or other documentary evidence would tend to incriminate him, but such evidence or the books or other documentary evidence so produced shall not be used in any criminal proceeding against him. If any person disobeys such process or, having appeared in obedience thereto refuses to answer any pertinent question put to him by the commissioner or his authorized representative, or to produce any books and other documentary evidence pursuant thereto, the commissioner or such representative may apply to the superior court for the county wherein the taxpayer resides or wherein the business has been conducted, or to any judge of said court if the same is not in session, setting forth such disobedience to process or refusal to answer, and said court or such judge shall cite such person to appear before said court or such judge to answer such question or to produce such books and documentary evidence and, upon his refusal so to do, shall commit such person to a community correctional center until he testifies, but not for a longer period than sixty days. Notwithstanding the serving of the term of such commitment by any person, the commissioner may proceed in all respects with such inquiry and examination as if the witness had not previously been called upon to testify.
</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>