<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-480"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-480"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-480"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-480/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-480/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-480/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-480/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_222">
        <num>222</num>
        <heading>Unrelated Business Income Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_480">
          <num>12-480</num>
          <heading>Credit on tax. Refund. Challenging legality of registration fee</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_480__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every such motor carrier shall be entitled to a credit on such tax equivalent to the rate per gallon of the tax in effect under said chapter 221 on all motor fuel purchased by such carrier within this state for use in its operations either within or without this state and upon which motor fuel the tax imposed by the laws of this state has been paid by such carrier. Evidence of the payment of such tax in such form as may be required by, or is satisfactory to, the Commissioner of Revenue Services shall be furnished by each such carrier claiming the credit herein allowed. When the amount of the credit herein provided to which any motor carrier is entitled for any quarter exceeds the amount of the tax for which such carrier is liable for the same quarter, such excess may, under regulations of the Commissioner of Revenue Services, be allowed as a credit on the tax for which such carrier would be otherwise liable for any of the four succeeding quarters; or such carrier may file, within one year from the due date for such quarter, an application verified and presented, in accordance with regulations adopted by the Commissioner of Revenue Services in accordance with chapter 54 and supported by such evidence as may be satisfactory to the Commissioner of Revenue Services, for a refund of such excess.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_480__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_480__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Commissioner of Revenue Services shall not allow such refund except after an audit of the applicant's records and he shall audit the records of an applicant at least once a year. The commissioner shall transmit all claims approved by him to the Comptroller, who shall draw an order on the State Treasurer for payment of such refund. If the commissioner determines that any such claim is not valid, either in whole or in part, he shall mail notice of the proposed disallowance to the claimant, which notice shall set forth briefly the commissioner's findings of fact and the basis of disallowance in each case decided in whole or in part adversely to the claimant. Sixty days after the date on which it is mailed, a notice of proposed disallowance shall constitute a final disallowance except only for such amounts as to which the claimant has filed, as provided in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_480__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, a written protest with the Commissioner of Revenue Services.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_480__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>On or before the sixtieth day after the mailing of the proposed disallowance, the claimant may file with the commissioner a written protest against the proposed disallowance in which the claimant sets forth the grounds on which the protest is based. If a protest is filed, the commissioner shall reconsider the proposed disallowance and, if the claimant has so requested, may grant or deny the claimant or the claimant's authorized representatives an oral hearing.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_480__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commissioner shall mail notice of his determination to the claimant, which notice shall set forth briefly the commissioner's findings of fact and the basis of decision in each case decided in whole or in part adversely to the claimant.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_480__subsec_b__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The action of the commissioner on the claimant's protest shall be final upon the expiration of one month from the date on which he mails notice of his action to the claimant unless within such period the claimant seeks judicial review of the commissioner's determination pursuant to subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_480__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-489.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_480__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_480__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any motor carrier who has registered any vehicle and paid a fee pursuant to section12-487, and who claims that such registration or payment is illegal for any reason, may claim a refund or credit, in writing, within six months after such registration or payment. If, upon examination of such claim, the commissioner determines that such registration or payment was illegal, the State Treasurer, upon order of the Comptroller, shall refund or credit the amount of any such fee to such motor carrier. If the commissioner determines that registration or payment was legal, he shall mail notice of the proposed disallowance to the motor carrier, which notice shall set forth briefly the commissioner's findings of fact and the basis of disallowance in each case decided in whole or in part adversely to the claimant. Sixty days after the date on which it is mailed, a notice of proposed disallowance shall constitute a final disallowance except only for such amounts as to which the claimant has filed, as provided in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_480__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, a written protest with the commissioner.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_480__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>On or before the sixtieth day after the mailing of the proposed disallowance, the claimant may file with the commissioner a written protest against the proposed disallowance in which the claimant sets forth the grounds on which the protest is based. If a protest is filed, the commissioner shall reconsider the proposed disallowance and, if the claimant has so requested, may grant or deny the claimant or the claimant's authorized representatives an oral hearing.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_480__subsec_c__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commissioner shall mail notice of his determination to the claimant, which notice shall set forth briefly the commissioner's findings of fact and the basis of decision in each case decided in whole or in part adversely to the claimant.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_480__subsec_c__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The action of the commissioner on the claimant's protest shall be final upon the expiration of one month from the date on which he mails notice of his action to the claimant unless within such period the claimant seeks judicial review of the commissioner's determination pursuant to subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_480__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-489.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>