<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-35g"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-35g"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-35g"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-35g/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-35g/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-35g/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-35g/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_202">
        <num>202</num>
        <heading>Collection of State Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_35g">
          <num>12-35g</num>
          <heading>Tax amnesty program for unpaid tax for periods ending November 30, 2008</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_35g__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Person” means person, as defined in section12-1;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Affected taxable period” means any taxable period ending on or before November 30, 2008, for which (A) a tax return was required by law to be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services and for which no return has been previously filed or made by the commissioner on behalf of an affected person, or (B) a tax return was previously filed but not examined by the Department of Revenue Services and on which return the tax was underreported;</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_35g__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a tax return was required by law to be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services and for which no return has been previously filed or made by the commissioner on behalf of an affected person, or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_35g__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a tax return was previously filed but not examined by the Department of Revenue Services and on which return the tax was underreported;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Affected person” means a person owing any tax for an affected taxable period;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Tax” means any tax imposed by any law of this state and required to be paid to the department, other than the tax imposed under chapter 222 on any licensee, as defined in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_35g__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-486;</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_c__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of Revenue Services; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_c__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Department” means the Department of Revenue Services.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_35g__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commissioner shall establish a tax amnesty program for persons owing any tax for any affected taxable period. The tax amnesty program shall be conducted during the period May 1, 2009, to June 25, 2009, inclusive.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An amnesty application shall be prepared by the commissioner to be filed by an affected person with the department, and shall provide for specification by the affected person of the tax and the affected taxable period for which amnesty is being sought under the tax amnesty program. The commissioner may require certain amnesty applications to be filed electronically, either by computer transmission or other technology specified by the commissioner. The commissioner may require payment of taxes and interest due under the tax amnesty program to be made by means of electronic funds transfer approved by the commissioner.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The tax amnesty program shall provide that, upon the filing of an amnesty application by the affected person during the tax amnesty period, and payment by such person of all taxes and interest due from such person to this state for affected tax periods, amnesty shall be granted to the applicant by the commissioner, and the commissioner shall waive any civil penalties that may be applicable and shall not seek criminal prosecution for any affected person for an affected taxable period for which amnesty has been granted.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_b__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An amnesty application, if filed by an affected person and if granted by the commissioner, shall constitute an express and absolute relinquishment by the affected person of all of the affected person's administrative and judicial rights of appeal that have not run or otherwise expired as of the date payment is made for affected taxable periods, and no payment made by an affected person pursuant to this section for affected taxable periods shall be refunded or credited to such person.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_b__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If an affected person who has filed an amnesty application during the tax amnesty period fails to pay all amounts due to this state for affected taxable periods, any amnesty granted pursuant to this section shall be invalid.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_b__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>No waiver of penalty or reduction of interest pursuant to this section shall entitle any affected person to a refund or credit of any amount previously paid.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_b__subsec_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In the case of taxes due for an affected taxable period that are paid in full on or before June 25, 2009, interest shall be computed at the rate of three-fourths of one per cent per month or fraction thereof from the date such taxes were originally due to the date of payment or June 25, 2009, whichever is earlier.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_35g__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Amnesty shall not be granted pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_35g__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section to any affected person who</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>has received notice from the department that an audit examination is being conducted in relation to the affected taxable period for which amnesty is being sought, or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_35g__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>is a party to any criminal investigation or to any civil or criminal litigation that is pending on November 25, 2008, in any court of the United States or this state for failure to file or failure to pay, or for fraud in relation to any tax imposed by any law of this state and required to be paid to the department.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_35g__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who wilfully delivers or discloses to the commissioner or the commissioner's authorized agent any application, list, return, account, statement or other document, known by such person to be fraudulent or false in any material matter, shall be ineligible for the tax amnesty program, and may, in addition to any other penalty provided by law, be fined not more than five thousand dollars or imprisoned not more than five years nor less than one year, or both.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_35g__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any provision of law, the commissioner may do all things necessary in order to provide for the timely implementation of this section.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>