<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-39g"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-39g"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-39g"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-39g/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-39g/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-39g/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-39g/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_202">
        <num>202</num>
        <heading>Collection of State Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_39g">
          <num>12-39g</num>
          <heading>State taxes and related penalties due from any taxpayer to be applied as reduction of any amount payable by the state to such taxpayer. Certain exceptions</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_39g__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon notification to the Comptroller by the Commissioner of Revenue Services that any taxes, including penalties and interest related thereto, are</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_39g__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>due to the state from any person and unpaid and a period in excess of thirty days has elapsed following the date on which such taxes were due and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_39g__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>are not the subject of a timely filed administrative appeal to said commissioner or of a timely filed appeal pending before any court of competent jurisdiction, the Comptroller shall withhold any order upon the Treasurer for payment of any amount payable by the state to such person unless the amount so payable is reduced by the amount of such taxes, penalties and interest, provided any such amount payable by the state shall not be so reduced if such amount payable is a payment of salary or wages, or any payment in lieu of or in addition to such salary or wages, to a state employee. The Comptroller shall promptly notify the Commissioner of Revenue Services of any payment reduced under the provisions of this section.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_39g__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For purposes of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_39g__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, any taxes for general or special purposes levied by a municipality, any taxes imposed under chapter 223 and payable to such municipality, any fines, penalties, costs or fees payable to such municipality for the violation of any lawful regulation or ordinance in furtherance of any general powers as enumerated in section7-148, or any charge payable to such municipality for connection with or for the use of a waterworks or sewerage system shall be treated as if they were taxes due to the state, where, pursuant to section12-2, an agreement exists between the commissioner and the governing authority of such municipality providing for the collection by the commissioner, on behalf of such municipality, of such taxes, fines, penalties, costs or fees, or charges, provided such taxes, fines, penalties, costs or fees, or charges are</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_39g__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>unpaid and a period in excess of thirty days has elapsed following the date on which they were due and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_39g__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>not the subject of a timely filed administrative appeal or of a timely filed appeal pending before any court of competent jurisdiction.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>