<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217qq"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217qq"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-217qq"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217qq/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217qq/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217qq/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-217qq/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_208">
        <num>208</num>
        <heading>Estate Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_217qq">
          <num>12-217qq</num>
          <heading>Tax credit for employers making student loan payments</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_217qq__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of Revenue Services;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Full-time” means required to work at least thirty-five hours per week;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Qualified employee” means an individual who (A) is a resident of the state, (B) has earned his or her first bachelor's degree from an institution of higher education in the immediately preceding five-year period, (C) is employed full-time in the state by a qualified employer, (D) is not an owner, member or partner of such qualified employer or a family member of an owner, member or partner of such qualified employer, and (E) has received a student education loan;</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>is a resident of the state,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>has earned his or her first bachelor's degree from an institution of higher education in the immediately preceding five-year period,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>is employed full-time in the state by a qualified employer,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>is not an owner, member or partner of such qualified employer or a family member of an owner, member or partner of such qualified employer, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_E">
                <num>(E)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>has received a student education loan;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Qualified employer” means a corporation licensed to operate a business in the state that is subject to tax under this chapter or chapter 207;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_a__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Qualified small business” means a qualified employer that has gross receipts of not more than five million dollars for the calendar or income year, as applicable, for which a credit under this section is allowed;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_a__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Student education loan” has the same meaning as provided in section36a-846; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_a__subsec_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Student loan servicer” has the same meaning as provided in section36a-846.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217qq__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For calendar or income years commencing on and after January 1, 2025, each qualified employer that employs a qualified employee and makes a payment directly to a student loan servicer on behalf of such qualified employee on a student education loan that was used to finance the qualified employee's attendance at an institution of higher education shall be eligible for a credit against the tax imposed under this chapter or chapter 207. Such credit shall be equal to fifty per cent of the amount of payments made to the outstanding principal balance of such loans by the qualified employer during the calendar or income year, provided (A) the credit shall not be allowed against the tax imposed under this chapter and chapter 207 for the same loan payment, and (B) the amount of credit allowed for any calendar or income year with respect to a specific qualified employee shall not exceed two thousand six hundred twenty-five dollars.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the credit shall not be allowed against the tax imposed under this chapter and chapter 207 for the same loan payment, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the amount of credit allowed for any calendar or income year with respect to a specific qualified employee shall not exceed two thousand six hundred twenty-five dollars.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A qualified employer may claim the credit under subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection for a payment made during the part of the calendar or income year the qualified employee worked and resided in the state, provided a qualified employee who worked and resided in the state for any part of a month shall be deemed to have worked and resided in the state for the entire month for purposes of this section.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217qq__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>To claim a credit under subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217qq__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, an eligible qualified employer shall file an application with the commissioner in a form and manner prescribed by the commissioner. Such qualified employer shall include a list of qualified employees for whom the qualified employer will be making a payment pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217qq__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, the total amount the qualified employer will pay toward such qualified employees' student education loans in the calendar or income year, the student loan servicer for each such student education loan and such other information as the commissioner may require for purposes of this section. Upon receipt of an application, the commissioner shall determine and reserve the amount of the credit the qualified employer will be entitled to claim and shall issue a voucher for such amount to the qualified employer. A qualified employer may not claim for any calendar or income year more than the amount set forth in such voucher.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The aggregate amount of tax credits that may be reserved by the commissioner under this section shall not exceed ten million dollars in any one calendar or income year and credits shall be reserved in the order of applications received by the commissioner.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A qualified employer that claims the credit under subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217qq__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section shall provide any documentation required by the commissioner in a form and manner prescribed by the commissioner.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217qq__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A qualified small business may apply to the commissioner in accordance with the provisions of subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection to exchange any credit allowed under subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217qq__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section for a credit refund equal to the value of the credit. Any amount of credit refunded under this subsection shall be refunded to the qualified small business in accordance with the provisions of this chapter or chapter 207, as applicable. No interest shall be allowed or paid on any amount of credit refunded under this subsection. Any amount of credit refunded under this subsection shall be subject to the provisions of section12-39g.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Each application for a credit refund under this subsection shall be filed, on such forms and containing such information as prescribed by the commissioner, on or before the original due date of the return prescribed under section12-205or12-222, as applicable, for the calendar or income year for which such credit was earned or, if applicable, the extended due date of such year's return. No application for a credit refund under this subsection may be filed after the due date or extended due date, as the case may be, of such return.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_217qq__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A qualified small business may not exchange for any calendar or income year more than the amount of the credit set forth in the voucher issued by the commissioner pursuant to subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_217qq__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>