<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-218"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-218"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-218"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-218/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-218/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-218/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-218/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_208">
        <num>208</num>
        <heading>Estate Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_218">
          <num>12-218</num>
          <heading>Apportionment of net income</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any taxpayer which is taxable both within and without this state shall apportion its net income as provided in this section. For purposes of apportionment of income under this section, a taxpayer is taxable in another state if in such state such taxpayer conducts business and is subject to a net income tax, a franchise tax for the privilege of doing business, or a corporate stock tax, or if such state has jurisdiction to subject such taxpayer to such a tax, regardless of whether such state does, in fact, impose such a tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, on and after January 1, 2016, the net income of the taxpayer shall be apportioned within and without the state by means of an apportionment fraction. The apportionment fraction shall represent the part of the taxpayer's gross receipts from sales or other sources during the income year, computed according to the method of accounting used in the computation of its entire net income, which is assignable to the state, and excluding any gross receipts attributable to an international banking facility as defined in section12-217. For the purposes of this subsection:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Gross receipts from sales of tangible personal property are assignable to this state if the property is delivered or shipped to a purchaser within this state, other than a company which qualifies as a Domestic International Sales Corporation (DISC) as defined in Section 992 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or any subsequent corresponding internal revenue code of the United States, as from time to time amended, and as to which a valid election under Subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of said Section 992 to be treated as a DISC is effective, regardless of the F.O.B. point or other conditions of the sale.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Gross receipts from services are assignable to this state if the market for services is in this state. The taxpayer's market for the services is in this state if and to the extent the service is used at a location in this state.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Gross receipts from the rental, lease or license of real or tangible personal property are assignable to this state to the extent such property is situated within the state.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Gross receipts from the rental, lease or license of intangible property are assignable to this state if and to the extent the property is used in this state. Intangible property utilized in marketing a good or service to a consumer is used in this state if that good or service is purchased by a consumer in this state.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Gross receipts from interest managed or controlled within the state are assignable to this state.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Gross receipts from the sale or other disposition of real property, tangible personal property or intangible property are excluded from the calculation of the apportionment fraction if such property is not held by the taxpayer primarily for sale to customers in the ordinary course of the taxpayer's trade or business.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Gross receipts, other than those receipts described in subdivisions</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>to</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>, inclusive, of this subsection, are assignable to this state to the extent the taxpayer's market for the sales is in this state.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_8">
              <num>(8)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a taxpayer concludes that it cannot reasonably determine the assignment of its receipts in accordance with subdivisions</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>to</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>, inclusive, of this subsection, such taxpayer may petition the commissioner for approval to use a methodology that reasonably approximates the assignment of such receipts provided for in this subsection. Any such petition shall be submitted not later than sixty days prior to the due date of the return for the first income year to which the petition applies, determined with regard to any extension of time for filing such return. The commissioner shall grant or deny such petition before such due date.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any motor bus company which is taxable both within and without this state shall apportion its net income derived from carrying of passengers for hire by means of an apportionment fraction, the numerator of which shall represent the total number of miles operated within this state and the denominator of which shall represent the total number of miles operated everywhere, but income derived by motor bus companies from sources other than the carrying of passengers for hire shall be apportioned as herein otherwise provided.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any motor carrier which transports property for hire and which is taxable both within and without this state shall apportion its net income derived from carrying of property for hire by means of an apportionment fraction, the numerator of which shall represent the total number of miles operated within this state and the denominator of which shall represent the total number of miles operated everywhere, but income derived by motor carriers from sources other than the carrying of property for hire shall be apportioned as herein otherwise provided.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_e__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Each taxpayer that provides management, distribution or administrative services, as defined in this subsection, to or on behalf of a regulated investment company, as defined in Section 851 of the Internal Revenue Code shall apportion its net income derived, directly or indirectly, from providing management, distribution or administrative services to or on behalf of a regulated investment company, including net income received directly or indirectly from trustees, and sponsors or participants of employee benefit plans which have accounts in a regulated investment company, in the manner provided in this subsection. Income derived by such taxpayer from sources other than the providing of management, distribution or administrative services to or on behalf of a regulated investment company shall be apportioned as provided in this chapter.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_e__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The numerator of the apportionment fraction shall consist of the sum of the Connecticut receipts, as described in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_e__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection. The denominator of the apportionment fraction shall consist of the total receipts from the sale of management, distribution or administrative services to or on behalf of all the regulated investment companies. For purposes of this subsection, “receipts” means receipts computed according to the method of accounting used by the taxpayer in the computation of net income.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_e__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For purposes of this subsection, Connecticut receipts shall be determined by multiplying receipts from the rendering of management, distribution or administrative services to or on behalf of each separate regulated investment company by a fraction (A) the numerator of which shall be the average of</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_e__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the numerator of which shall be the average of</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the number of shares on the first day of such regulated investment company's taxable year, for federal income tax purposes, which ends within or at the same time as the taxable year of the taxpayer, that are owned by shareholders of such regulated investment company then domiciled in this state and (ii) the number of shares on the last day of such regulated investment company's taxable year, for federal income tax purposes, which ends within or at the same time as the taxable year of the taxpayer, that are owned by shareholders of such regulated investment company then domiciled in this state; and (B) the denominator of which shall be the average of the number of shares that are owned by shareholders of such regulated investment company on such dates.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>(A) For purposes of this subsection, “management services” includes, but is not limited to, the rendering of investment advice directly or indirectly to a regulated investment company, making determinations as to when sales and purchases of securities are to be made on behalf of the regulated investment company, or the selling or purchasing of securities constituting assets of a regulated investment company, and related activities, but only where such activity or activities are performed</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_4__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For purposes of this subsection, “management services” includes, but is not limited to, the rendering of investment advice directly or indirectly to a regulated investment company, making determinations as to when sales and purchases of securities are to be made on behalf of the regulated investment company, or the selling or purchasing of securities constituting assets of a regulated investment company, and related activities, but only where such activity or activities are performed</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>pursuant to a contract with the regulated investment company entered into pursuant to 15 USC 80a-15</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, as from time to time amended, (ii) for a person that has entered into such contract with the regulated investment company, or (iii) for a person that is affiliated with a person that has entered into such contract with a regulated investment company.
(B) For purposes of this subsection, “distribution services” includes, but is not limited to, the services of advertising, servicing, marketing or selling shares of a regulated investment company, but, in the case of advertising, servicing or marketing shares, only where such service is performed by a person that is, or, in the case of a closed end company, was, either engaged in the service of selling such shares or affiliated with a person that is engaged in the service of selling such shares. In the case of an open end company, such service of selling shares shall be performed pursuant to a contract entered into pursuant to 15 USC 80a-15</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, as from time to time amended.
(C) For purposes of this subsection, “administrative services” includes, but is not limited to, clerical, fund or shareholder accounting, participant record keeping, transfer agency, bookkeeping, data processing, custodial, internal auditing, legal and tax services performed for a regulated investment company but only if the provider of such service or services during the income year in which such service or services are provided also provides, or is affiliated with a person that provides, management or distribution services to such regulated investment company.
(D) For purposes of this subsection, a person is “affiliated” with another person if each person is a member of the same affiliated group, as defined under Section 1504 of the Internal Revenue Code without regard to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of said section.
(E) For purposes of this subsection, the domicile of a shareholder shall be presumed to be such shareholder's mailing address as shown in the records of the regulated investment company except that for purposes of this subsection, if the shareholder of record is an insurance company which holds the shares of the regulated investment company as depositor for the benefit of a separate account, then the taxpayer may elect to treat as the shareholders the contract owners or policyholders of the contracts or policies supported by such separate account. An election made under this subparagraph shall apply to all shareholders that are insurance companies and shall be irrevocable for, and applicable for, five successive income years. In any year that such an election is applicable, it shall be presumed that the domicile of a shareholder is the mailing address of the contract owner or policyholder as shown in the records of the insurance company.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_f__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Each taxpayer that provides securities brokerage services, as defined in this subsection, shall apportion its net income derived, directly or indirectly, from rendering securities brokerage services in the manner provided in this subsection. Income derived by such taxpayer from sources other than the rendering of securities brokerage services shall be apportioned as provided in this chapter.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_f__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The numerator of the apportionment fraction shall consist of the brokerage commissions and total margin interest paid on behalf of brokerage accounts owned by the taxpayer's customers who are domiciled in this state during such taxpayer's income year, computed according to the method of accounting used in the computation of net income. The denominator of the apportionment fraction shall consist of brokerage commissions and total margin interest paid on behalf of brokerage accounts owned by all of the taxpayer's customers, wherever domiciled, during such taxpayer's income year, computed according to the method of accounting used in the computation of net income.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_f__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For purposes of this subsection:
(A) “Security brokerage services” means services and activities including all aspects of the purchasing and selling of securities rendered by a broker, as defined in 15 USC 78c</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_f__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“Security brokerage services” means services and activities including all aspects of the purchasing and selling of securities rendered by a broker, as defined in 15 USC 78c</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and registered under the provisions of 15 USC 78a to 78kk, inclusive, as from time to time amended, to effectuate transactions in securities for the account of others, and a dealer, as defined in 15 USC 78c</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_a__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and registered under the provisions of 15 USC 78a to 78kk, inclusive, as from time to time amended, to buy and sell securities, through a broker or otherwise. Security brokerage services shall not include services rendered by any person buying or selling securities for such person's own account, either individually or in some fiduciary capacity, but not as part of a regular business carried on by such person.
(B) “Securities” means security, as defined in 15 USC 78c</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_a__subsec_5__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“Securities” means security, as defined in 15 USC 78c</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_a__subsec_10">
              <num>(10)</num>
              <content>
                <p>, as from time to time amended.
(C) “Brokerage commission” means all compensation received for effecting purchases and sales for the account or on order of others, whether in a principal or agency transaction, and whether charged explicitly or implicitly as a fee, commission, spread, markup or otherwise.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_a__subsec_10__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“Brokerage commission” means all compensation received for effecting purchases and sales for the account or on order of others, whether in a principal or agency transaction, and whether charged explicitly or implicitly as a fee, commission, spread, markup or otherwise.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For purposes of this subsection, the domicile of a customer shall be presumed to be such customer's mailing address as shown in the records of the taxpayer.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_g__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any company that is (A) a limited partner in a partnership, other than an investment partnership, that does business, owns or leases property or maintains an office within this state and (B) not otherwise carrying on or doing business in this state shall pay the tax imposed under section12-214solely on its distributive share as a partner of the income or loss of such partnership to the extent such income or loss is derived from or connected with sources within this state, except that, if the commissioner determines that the company and the partnership are, in substance, parts of a unitary business engaged in a single business enterprise or if the company is a member of a combined group that files a combined unitary tax return, the company shall be taxed in accordance with the provisions of subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_g__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a limited partner in a partnership, other than an investment partnership, that does business, owns or leases property or maintains an office within this state and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_g__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>not otherwise carrying on or doing business in this state shall pay the tax imposed under section12-214solely on its distributive share as a partner of the income or loss of such partnership to the extent such income or loss is derived from or connected with sources within this state, except that, if the commissioner determines that the company and the partnership are, in substance, parts of a unitary business engaged in a single business enterprise or if the company is a member of a combined group that files a combined unitary tax return, the company shall be taxed in accordance with the provisions of subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_g__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection and not in accordance with the provisions of this subdivision, provided, in lieu of the payment of tax based solely on its distributive share, such company may elect for any particular income year, on or before the due date or, if applicable the extended due date, of its corporation business tax return for such income year, to apportion its net income within and without the state under the provisions of this chapter.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_g__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any company that is (A) a limited partner</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_g__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a limited partner</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>in an investment partnership or (ii) in a limited partnership, other than an investment partnership, that does business, owns or leases property or maintains an office within this state and (B) otherwise carrying on or doing business in this state shall apportion its net income, including its distributive share as a partner of such partnership income or loss, within and without the state under the provisions of this chapter, except that the numerator and the denominator of its apportionment fraction shall include its proportionate part, as a partner, of the numerator and the denominator of such partnership's apportionment fraction. For purposes of this section, such partnership shall compute its apportionment fraction and the numerator and the denominator of its apportionment fraction as if it were a company taxable both within and without this state.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any company that is a general partner in a partnership that does business, owns or leases property or maintains an office within this state shall, whether or not it is otherwise carrying on or doing business in this state, apportion its net income, including its distributive share as a partner of such partnership income or loss, within and without the state under the provisions of this chapter, except that the numerator and the denominator of its apportionment fraction shall include its proportionate part, as a partner, of the numerator and the denominator of such partnership's apportionment fraction. For purposes of this section, such partnership shall compute its apportionment fraction and the numerator and the denominator of its apportionment fraction as if it were a company taxable both within and without this state.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <heading>The provisions of this section shall not apply to insurance companies</heading>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any financial service company as defined in section12-218b, that has net income derived from credit card activities, as defined in this subsection, shall apportion its net income derived from credit card activities in the manner provided in this subsection. Income derived by such taxpayer from sources other than credit card activities shall be apportioned as provided in this chapter.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The numerator of the apportionment fraction shall consist of the Connecticut receipts, as described in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection. The denominator of the apportionment fraction shall consist of (A) the total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables, (B) receipts from fees charged to card holders, including, but not limited to, annual fees, irrespective of the billing address of the card holder, (C) net gains from the sale of credit card receivables, irrespective of the billing address of the card holder, and (D) all credit card issuer's reimbursement fees, irrespective of the billing address of the card holder.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_3__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>receipts from fees charged to card holders, including, but not limited to, annual fees, irrespective of the billing address of the card holder,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_3__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>net gains from the sale of credit card receivables, irrespective of the billing address of the card holder, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_3__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>all credit card issuer's reimbursement fees, irrespective of the billing address of the card holder.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For purposes of this subsection, “Connecticut receipts” shall be determined by adding (A) interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables and receipts from fees charged to card holders, including, but not limited to, annual fees, where the billing address of the card holder is in this state and (B) the product of</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables and receipts from fees charged to card holders, including, but not limited to, annual fees, where the billing address of the card holder is in this state and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_3__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the product of</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the sum of net gains from the sale of credit card receivables and all credit card issuer's reimbursement fees multiplied by (ii) a fraction, the numerator of which shall be interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables and receipts from fees charged to card holders, including, but not limited to, annual fees, where the billing address of the card holder is in this state, and the denominator of which shall be the total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables and receipts from fees charged to card holders, including, but not limited to, annual fees, irrespective of the billing address of the card holder.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For purposes of this subsection:
(A) “Credit card” means a credit, travel, or entertainment card;
(B) “Receipts” means receipts computed according to the method of accounting used by the taxpayer in the computation of net income;
(C) “Credit card issuer's reimbursement fee” means the fee that a taxpayer receives from a merchant's bank because one of the persons to whom the taxpayer or a related person, as defined in section12-218b, has issued a credit card has charged merchandise or services to the credit card;
(D) “Net income derived from credit card activities” means</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_4__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“Credit card” means a credit, travel, or entertainment card;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_4__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“Receipts” means receipts computed according to the method of accounting used by the taxpayer in the computation of net income;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_4__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“Credit card issuer's reimbursement fee” means the fee that a taxpayer receives from a merchant's bank because one of the persons to whom the taxpayer or a related person, as defined in section12-218b, has issued a credit card has charged merchandise or services to the credit card;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_4__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“Net income derived from credit card activities” means</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables and receipts from fees charged to card holders, including, but not limited to, annual fees, net gains from the sale of credit card receivables, credit card issuer's reimbursement fees, and credit card receivables servicing fees received in connection with credit cards issued by the taxpayer or a related person, as defined in section12-218b, less (ii) expenses related to such income, to the extent deductible under this chapter;
(E) “Billing address” shall be presumed to be the location indicated in the books and records of the taxpayer as the address where any notice, statement or bill relating to a card holder is to be mailed, as of the date of such mailing; and
(F) “Credit card activities” means those activities involving the underwriting and approval of credit card relationships or other business activities generally associated with the conduct of business by an issuer of credit cards from which it derives income.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Commissioner of Revenue Services may adopt regulations, in accordance with chapter 54, to permit a financial service company that is an owner of a financial asset securitization investment trust, as defined in Section 860H</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the Internal Revenue Code, to elect to apportion its share of the net income from credit card activities carried on by such trust, and to provide rules for apportioning such share of net income that are consistent with this subsection.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_j">
            <num>(j)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_j__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For income years commencing on or after January 1, 2001, the net income of a taxpayer which is primarily engaged in activities that, in accordance with the North American Industrial Classification System, United States Manual, United States Office of Management and Budget, 1997 edition, would be included in Sector 31, 32 or 33, shall be apportioned within and without the state by means of the apportionment fraction described in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_j__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection provided, in the income year commencing on January 1, 2001, each such taxpayer shall not take such apportionment fraction into account for purposes of installment payments on estimated tax under section12-242dfor calendar quarters ending prior to July 1, 2001, but shall make such payments in accordance with the apportionment fraction applicable to the income year commencing January 1, 2000.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_j__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The apportionment fraction of a taxpayer described in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_j__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection shall be the apportionment fraction calculated under subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>(A) Any taxpayer which is described in subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Any taxpayer which is described in subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection and seventy-five per cent or more of whose total gross receipts, as described in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, during the income year are from the sale of tangible personal property directly, or in the case of a subcontractor, indirectly, to the United States government may elect, on or before the due date or, if applicable, the extended due date, of its corporation business tax return for the income year, to apportion its net income within and without the state by means of the apportionment fraction described in subparagraph (B) of this subdivision. The election, if made by the taxpayer, shall be irrevocable for, and applicable for, five successive income years.
(B) The net income of the taxpayer making an election under subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subparagraph (A) of this subsection shall be apportioned within and without the state by means of an apportionment fraction, to be computed as the sum of the property factor, the payroll factor and twice the receipts factor, divided by four.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of this subsection shall be apportioned within and without the state by means of an apportionment fraction, to be computed as the sum of the property factor, the payroll factor and twice the receipts factor, divided by four.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The first of these fractions, the property factor, shall represent that part of the average monthly net book value of the total tangible property held and owned by the taxpayer during the income year which is held within the state, without deduction on account of any encumbrance thereon, and the value of tangible property rented to the taxpayer computed by multiplying the gross rents payable during the income year or period by eight. For the purpose of this section, gross rents shall be the actual sum of money or other consideration payable, directly or indirectly, by the taxpayer or for its benefit for the use or possession of the property, excluding royalties, but including interest, taxes, insurance, repairs or any other amount required to be paid by the terms of a lease or other arrangement and a proportionate part of the cost of any improvement to the real property made by or on behalf of the taxpayer which reverts to the owner or lessor upon termination of a lease or other arrangement, based on the unexpired term of the lease commencing with the date the improvement is completed, provided, where a building is erected on leased land by or on behalf of the taxpayer, the value of the land is determined by multiplying the gross rent by eight, and the value of the building is determined in the same manner as if owned by the taxpayer. (ii) The second fraction, the payroll factor, shall represent the part of the total wages, salaries and other compensation to employees paid by the taxpayer during the income year which was paid in this state, excluding any such wages, salaries or other compensation attributable to the production of gross income of an international banking facility as defined in section12-217. Compensation is paid in this state if (I) the individual's service is performed entirely within the state; or (II) the individual's service is performed both within and without the state, but the service performed without the state is incidental to the individual</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of said Section 992 to be treated as a DISC is effective, regardless of the F.O.B. point or other conditions of the sale, receipts from services performed within the state, rentals and royalties from properties situated within the state, royalties from the use of patents or copyrights within the state, interest managed or controlled within the state, net gains from the sale or other disposition of intangible assets managed or controlled within the state, net gains from the sale or other disposition of tangible assets situated within the state and all other receipts earned within the state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_k">
            <num>(k)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For income years commencing on or after October 1, 2001, any broadcaster which is taxable both within and without this state shall apportion its net income derived from the broadcast of video or audio programming, whether through the public airwaves, by cable, by direct or indirect satellite transmission or by any other means of communication, through an over-the-air television or radio network, through a television or radio station or through a cable network or cable television system and, if such broadcaster is a cable network, all net income derived from activities related to or arising out of the foregoing, including, but not limited to, broadcasting, entertainment, publishing, whether electronically or in print, electronic commerce and licensing of intellectual property created in the pursuit of such activities, by means of the apportionment fraction described in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, and any eligible production entity which is taxable both within and without this state shall apportion its net income derived from video or audio programming production services by means of the apportionment fraction described in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For purposes of this subsection:
(A) “Video or audio programming” means any and all performances, events or productions, including without limitation news, sporting events, plays, stories and other entertainment, literary, commercial, educational or artistic works, telecast or otherwise made available for video or audio exhibition through live transmission or through the use of video tape, disc or any other type of format or medium;
(B) A “subscriber” to a cable television system is an individual residence or other outlet which is the ultimate recipient of the transmission;
(C) “Telecast” or “broadcast” means the transmission of video or audio programming by an electronic or other signal conducted by radiowaves or microwaves, by wires, lines, coaxial cables, wave guides or fiber optics, by satellite transmissions directly or indirectly to viewers or listeners or by any other means of communication;
(D) “Eligible production entity” means a corporation which provides video or audio programming production services and which is affiliated, within the meaning of Sections 1501 to 1504 of the Internal Revenue Code and the regulations promulgated thereunder, with a broadcaster;
(E) “Release” or “in release” means the placing of video or audio programming into service. A video or audio program is placed into service when it is first broadcast to the primary audience for which the program was created. For example, video programming is placed in service when it is first publicly telecast for entertainment, educational, commercial, artistic or other purpose. Each episode of a television or radio series is placed in service when it is first broadcast; and
(F) “Broadcaster” means a corporation that is engaged in the business of broadcasting video or audio programming, whether through the public airwaves, by cable, by direct or indirect satellite transmission or by any other means of communication, through an over-the-air television or radio network, through a television or radio </p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“Video or audio programming” means any and all performances, events or productions, including without limitation news, sporting events, plays, stories and other entertainment, literary, commercial, educational or artistic works, telecast or otherwise made available for video or audio exhibition through live transmission or through the use of video tape, disc or any other type of format or medium;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_2__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A “subscriber” to a cable television system is an individual residence or other outlet which is the ultimate recipient of the transmission;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_2__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“Telecast” or “broadcast” means the transmission of video or audio programming by an electronic or other signal conducted by radiowaves or microwaves, by wires, lines, coaxial cables, wave guides or fiber optics, by satellite transmissions directly or indirectly to viewers or listeners or by any other means of communication;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_2__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“Eligible production entity” means a corporation which provides video or audio programming production services and which is affiliated, within the meaning of Sections 1501 to 1504 of the Internal Revenue Code and the regulations promulgated thereunder, with a broadcaster;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_2__subsec_E">
                <num>(E)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“Release” or “in release” means the placing of video or audio programming into service. A video or audio program is placed into service when it is first broadcast to the primary audience for which the program was created. For example, video programming is placed in service when it is first publicly telecast for entertainment, educational, commercial, artistic or other purpose. Each episode of a television or radio series is placed in service when it is first broadcast; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_2__subsec_F">
                <num>(F)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“Broadcaster” means a corporation that is engaged in the business of broadcasting video or audio programming, whether through the public airwaves, by cable, by direct or indirect satellite transmission or by any other means of communication, through an over-the-air television or radio network, through a television or radio station or through a cable network or cable television system, and that is primarily engaged in activities that, in accordance with the North American Industry Classification System, United States Manual, 1997 edition, are included in industry group 5131 or 5132.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>(A) Except as provided in subparagraph (B) of this subdivision with respect to the determination of the apportionment fraction for net income derived from the activities referred to in subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Except as provided in subparagraph</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_3__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of this subdivision with respect to the determination of the apportionment fraction for net income derived from the activities referred to in subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_k">
            <num>(k)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, the numerator of the apportionment fraction for a broadcaster shall consist of the broadcaster's gross receipts, as described in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, which are assignable to the state, as provided in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section. Except as provided in subparagraph (C) of this subdivision with respect to the determination of the apportionment fraction for the net income derived from the activities referred to in subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_k">
            <num>(k)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, the denominator of the apportionment fraction for a broadcaster shall consist of the broadcaster's total gross receipts, as described in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, whether or not assignable to the state.
(B) The numerator of the apportionment fraction for a broadcaster shall include the gross receipts of the taxpayer from sources within this state determined as follows:</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Gross receipts, including without limitation, advertising revenue, affiliate fees and subscriber fees, received by a broadcaster from video or audio programming in release to or by a broadcaster for telecast which is attributed to this state.
(ii) Gross receipts, including without limitation, advertising revenue, received by an over-the-air television or radio network or a television or radio station from video or audio programming in release to or by such network or station for telecast shall be attributed to this state in the same ratio that the audience for such over-the-air network or station located in this state bears to the total audience for such over-the-air network or station inside and outside of the United States. For purposes of this subparagraph, the audience shall be determined either by reference to the books and records of the taxpayer or by reference to the applicable year's published rating statistics, provided the method used by the taxpayer is consistently used from year to year for such purpose and fairly represents the taxpayer's activity in the state.
(iii) Gross receipts including, without limitation, advertising revenue, affiliate fees and subscriber fees, received by a cable network or a cable television system from video or audio programming in release to or by such cable network or cable television system for telecast and other receipts that are derived from the activities referred to in subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection shall be attributed to this state in the same ratio that the number of subscribers for such cable network or cable television system located in this state bears to the total of such subscribers of such cable network or cable television system inside and outside of the United States. For purpose of this subparagraph, the number of subscribers of a cable network shall be measured by reference to the number of subscribers of cable television systems that are affiliated with such network and that receive video or audio programming of such network. For purposes of this subparagraph, the number of subscribers of a cable television system shall be determined either by reference to the books and records of the taxpayer or by reference to the applicable year's published rating statistics located in published surveys, provided the method used by the taxpayer is consistently used from year to year for such purpose and fairly represents the taxpayer's activities in the state.
(C) The denominator of the apportionment fraction of a broadcaster shall include gross receipts of the broadcaster that are derived from the activities referred to in subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_1__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The denominator of the apportionment fraction of a broadcaster shall include gross receipts of the broadcaster that are derived from the activities referred to in subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_i__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_k">
            <num>(k)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, whether or not assignable to the state.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>(A) Except as provided in subparagraph (B) of this subdivision, with respect to the determination of the apportionment fraction for net income derived from video or audio programming production services, the numerator of the apportionment fraction for an eligible production entity shall consist of the eligible production entity's gross receipts, as described in subsection</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_4__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Except as provided in subparagraph</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_218__subsec_k__subsec_4__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of this subdivision, with respect to the determination of the apportionment fraction for net income derived from video or audio programming production services, the numerator of the apportionment fraction for an eligible production entity shall consist of the eligible production entity's gross receipts, as described in subsection</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, which are assignable to the state, as provided in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section. Except as provided in subparagraph (C) of this subdivision, with respect to the determination of the apportionment fraction for net income derived from video or audio programming production services, the denominator of the apportionment fraction for an eligible production entity shall consist of the eligible production entity's total gross receipts, as described in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, whether or not assignable to the state.
(B) The numerator of the apportionment fraction for an eligible production entity shall include gross receipts of the entity that are derived from video or audio programming production services relating to events which occur within this state.
(C) The denominator of the apportionment fraction for an eligible production entity shall include gross receipts of the entity that are derived from video or audio programming production services relating to events which occur within or without this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_l">
            <num>(l)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each taxable member of a combined group required to file a combined unitary tax return pursuant to section12-222shall, if one or more members of such group are taxable without this state, apportion its net income as provided in subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_218__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-218e.
See Sec. 12-244 re allocation of tax on air carriers.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>