<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-219a"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-219a"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-219a"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-219a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-219a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-219a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-219a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_208">
        <num>208</num>
        <heading>Estate Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_219a">
          <num>12-219a</num>
          <heading>Apportionment of tax base in and out of state. Insurance companies excepted</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_219a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a taxpayer is taxable both within and without the state, a tax shall be imposed on the base as provided in section12-219, apportioned on the following basis:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The average monthly value of all investments other than stock of private corporations, and all cash, credits and other intangible assets of the taxpayer shall be divided between (A) those having a tax situs within the state and (B) those having a tax situs without the state;</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>those having a tax situs within the state and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>those having a tax situs without the state;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the average monthly net book value of the tangible property held and owned by the taxpayer during the income year shall be divided between (A) that held within the state and (B) that held without the state; the numerator of the allocation fraction shall consist of the sum of subparagraph (A) of subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>that held within the state and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>that held without the state; the numerator of the allocation fraction shall consist of the sum of subparagraph</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection and subparagraph (A) of subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, and the denominator shall consist of the sum of subdivisions</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection; which allocation fraction shall be multiplied by the amount of the unallocated tax base as computed under the terms of said section12-219to obtain the tax base for such taxpayer. For the purposes of this section, the intangible assets of a company having its principal place of business within the state shall be deemed to have a tax situs within the state unless it can be clearly established that some or all of such assets are held in connection with business conducted during the income year without the state, and a similar rule shall apply to intangible assets of a company having its principal place of business without the state. Such assets shall be reported by the taxpayer at the valuations at which they appear upon its books, provided the Commissioner of Revenue Services shall exercise the powers with respect to such valuations granted him under the terms of said section12-219. For the purpose of apportionment of the base as provided in said section12-219, a taxpayer is taxable in another state if in such state such taxpayer conducts business and is subject to a net income tax, a franchise tax measured by net income, a franchise tax for the privilege of doing business or a corporate stock tax, or if such state has jurisdiction to subject such taxpayer to such a tax, regardless of whether such state does, in fact, impose such a tax.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_219a__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_219a__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any company that is (A) a limited partner in a partnership, other than an investment partnership, that does business, owns or leases property or maintains an office within this state and (B) not otherwise carrying on or doing business in this state shall apportion the average value of its partnership interest within and without this state under the provisions of subsection</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_219a__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a limited partner in a partnership, other than an investment partnership, that does business, owns or leases property or maintains an office within this state and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_219a__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>not otherwise carrying on or doing business in this state shall apportion the average value of its partnership interest within and without this state under the provisions of subsection</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_219a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, except that the numerator and the denominator of its apportionment fraction shall be its proportionate part of the partnership's apportionment factors. For purposes of this section, the partnership shall compute its apportionment fraction and the numerator and the denominator of its apportionment factors as if it were a company taxable both within and without this state. However, if the commissioner determines that the company and the partnership are, in substance, parts of a unitary business engaged in a single business enterprise, or, if the company is a member of a combined group that files a combined unitary tax return, the company shall be taxed in accordance with the provisions of subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection and not in accordance with the provisions of this subdivision.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any company that is (A) a limited partner</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a limited partner</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_219a__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>in an investment partnership or (ii) in a limited partnership, other than an investment partnership, that does business, owns or leases property or maintains an office within this state and (B) otherwise carrying on or doing business in this state shall apportion its additional tax base, including the average value of its partnership interest, within and without the state under the provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_219a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, except that the numerator and the denominator of its apportionment factors shall include its proportionate part of the numerator and the denominator of the partnership's apportionment factors. For purposes of this section, the partnership shall compute its apportionment fraction and the numerator and the denominator of its apportionment factors, as if it were a company taxable both within and without this state.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_219a__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any company that is a general partner in a partnership that does business, owns or leases property or maintains an office within this state shall, whether or not it is otherwise carrying on or doing business in this state, apportion its additional tax base, including the average value of its partnership interest, within and without the state under the provisions of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_219a__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, except that the numerator and the denominator of its apportionment factors shall include its proportionate part of the numerator and the denominator of the partnership's apportionment factors. For purposes of this section, the partnership shall compute its apportionment fraction and the numerator and the denominator of its apportionment factors, as if it were a company taxable both within and without this state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_219a__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <heading>This section shall not apply to insurance companies</heading>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_219a__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The additional tax base of taxable and nontaxable members of a combined group required to file a combined unitary tax return pursuant to section12-222shall be apportioned as provided in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_219a__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-218e.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>