<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-222"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-222"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-222"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-222/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-222/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-222/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-222/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_208">
        <num>208</num>
        <heading>Estate Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_222">
          <num>12-222</num>
          <heading>Annual return. Designated taxable member of combined group. Duties</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_222__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each company subject to the tax imposed under this part shall render to the commissioner an annual return, signed by one of its principal officers, on forms prescribed or furnished by the commissioner, stating specifically the name of the company and the location of its principal office, the state where organized and the date of organization, the names and locations of all subsidiaries, the amount of its paid-up capital and surplus at the end of the income year, the amount of its undivided profits and reserves at the end of such year, the par value of all indebtedness at the end of such year, the items of gross income received during such year, the deductions permitted by law, the interest and rental payments during such year, the dividend payments and changes in capital, surplus and undivided profits during such year, complete balance sheets at the beginning and end of such year or period and such other facts as the commissioner may require for the purpose of making any computation required by this part.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_222__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such return shall be due on or before the fifteenth day of the month next succeeding the due date of the company's corresponding federal income tax return for the income year, determined without regard to any extension of time for filing, or, in the case of any company that is not required to file a federal income tax return for the income year, on or before the fifteenth day of the fifth month next succeeding the end of the income year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_222__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner may grant a reasonable extension of time for filing a return, if the company files a tentative return and application for extension of time in which to file a return, on forms furnished or prescribed by the commissioner, and pays the tax reported to be due on such tentative return on or before the original due date of the return, as provided in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_222__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section. Any additional tax which may be found to be due on the filing of the return as allowed by such extension shall bear interest at the rate of one per cent per month or fraction thereof from the original due date of the return to the date of actual payment. Notwithstanding the provisions of section12-229, if the commissioner grants a reasonable extension of time for filing a return, no penalty shall be imposed on account of any failure to pay the amount of tax reported to be due on a return within the time specified under the provisions of this chapter if the excess of the amount of tax shown on the return over the amount of tax paid on or before the original due date of such return is no greater than ten per cent of the amount of tax shown on such return, and any balance due shown on such return is remitted with such return on or before the extended due date of such return.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_222__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In any case in which the commissioner believes that it would be advantageous for the computation of the tax as imposed by this part, such state return shall be accompanied by a true copy of the last income tax return, if any, made to the Internal Revenue Service.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_222__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The amount of tax reported to be due on such return or tentative return shall be due and payable on or before the original due date of the return, as defined in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_222__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_222__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Payment shall be made in cash or by check, draft or money order drawn to the order of the Commissioner of Revenue Services.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_222__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A combined group shall file a combined unitary tax return under this chapter in the form and manner prescribed by the Commissioner of Revenue Services. The designated taxable member of a combined group shall file the combined unitary tax return on behalf of the taxable members of the combined group and shall pay the tax on behalf of such taxable members. A designated taxable member shall not be liable to, and shall be entitled to recover a payment made pursuant to this subdivision from, the taxable member on whose behalf the payment was made.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a member of a combined group has a different income year than the group income year, such member with a different income year shall report amounts from its return for its income year that ends during the group income year, provided no such reporting of amounts shall be required of such member until its first income year beginning on or after January 1, 2016.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, each taxable member of a combined group is jointly and severally liable for the tax due from any taxable member under this chapter, whether or not such tax has been self-assessed, and for any interest, penalties or additions to tax due from any taxable member under this chapter.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In all cases where a combined group is eligible to select the designated taxable member of the combined group, notice of the selection shall be submitted in written form to the commissioner not later than the due date, or, if an extension of time to file has been requested and granted, not later than the extended due date of the combined unitary tax return for the initial income year that such a return is required. The subsequent selection of another designated taxable member shall be subject to the approval of the commissioner.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For purposes of this chapter, the designated taxable member is authorized to do the following acts on behalf of taxable and nontaxable members of the combined group, including, but not limited to: (A) Signing the combined unitary tax return, including any amendments to such return; (B) applying for extensions of time to file the return; (C) before the expiration of the time prescribed in section12-233for the examination of the return or the assessment of tax, consenting to an examination or assessment after such time and prior to the expiration of the period agreed upon; (D) making offers of compromise under section12-2d; (E) entering into closing agreements under section12-2e; and (F) receiving a refund or credit of a tax overpayment under this chapter.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_5__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Signing the combined unitary tax return, including any amendments to such return;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_5__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>applying for extensions of time to file the return;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_5__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>before the expiration of the time prescribed in section12-233for the examination of the return or the assessment of tax, consenting to an examination or assessment after such time and prior to the expiration of the period agreed upon;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_5__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>making offers of compromise under section12-2d;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_5__subsec_E">
                <num>(E)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>entering into closing agreements under section12-2e; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_5__subsec_F">
                <num>(F)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>receiving a refund or credit of a tax overpayment under this chapter.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For purposes of this chapter, the commissioner may, at the commissioner's sole discretion: (A) Send any notice to either the designated taxable member or a taxable member or members of the combined group; (B) make any deficiency assessment against either the designated taxable member or a taxable member or members of the combined group; (C) refund or credit any overpayment to either the designated taxable member or a taxable member or members of the combined group; (D) require any payment to be made by electronic funds transfer; and (E) require the combined unitary tax return to be electronically filed.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_6__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Send any notice to either the designated taxable member or a taxable member or members of the combined group;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_6__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>make any deficiency assessment against either the designated taxable member or a taxable member or members of the combined group;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_6__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>refund or credit any overpayment to either the designated taxable member or a taxable member or members of the combined group;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_6__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>require any payment to be made by electronic funds transfer; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_222__subsec_g__subsec_6__subsec_E">
                <num>(E)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>require the combined unitary tax return to be electronically filed.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>