<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-239a"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-239a"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-239a"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-239a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-239a/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-239a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-239a/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319v">
        <num>319v</num>
        <heading>Temporary Assistance for Needy Families</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_239a">
          <num>17b-239a</num>
          <heading>Payments to short-term general hospitals located in certain distressed municipalities and targeted investment communities with enterprise zones</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 17b-239a. Payments to short-term general hospitals located in certain distressed municipalities and targeted investment communities with enterprise zones.The Department of Social Services may, within available funds, make payments to all short-term general hospitals located in distressed municipalities, as defined in section32-9p, with a population greater than seventy thousand and to all short-term general hospitals located in targeted investment communities with enterprise zones, as defined in section32-70, with a population greater than one hundred thousand. The payment amount for each hospital shall be determined by the Commissioner of Social Services based upon the ratio that the number of inpatient discharges paid by Medicaid on a fee-for-service basis to the hospital for the most recently filed cost report period bears to the total hospital discharges paid by Medicaid on a fee-for-service basis for all qualifying hospitals. Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, no payment shall be made to a facility licensed as a children's hospital.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>