<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-521"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-521"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-521"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-521/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-521/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-521/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-521/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_521">
          <num>17a-521</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-198). Temporary leaves from institution. Return or recall of patient. Exception</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 17a-521. (Formerly Sec. 17-198). Temporary leaves from institution. Return or recall of patient. Exception.Except as otherwise provided in this section, the superintendent of any institution used wholly or in part for the care of persons with psychiatric disabilities or the director of the Whiting Forensic Hospital may, under such provisions or agreements as the director deems advisable for psychiatric supervision, permit any patient of the institution under the director's charge temporarily to leave such institution, in charge of his guardian, relatives or friends, or by himself or herself. A person confined to a hospital for psychiatric disabilities under the provisions of section17a-584may leave the hospital temporarily as provided under the provisions of section17a-587. In the case of committed persons, the original order of commitment shall remain in force and effect during absence from the institution either on authorized or unauthorized leave until such patient is officially discharged by the authorities of such institution or such order is superseded by a court of competent jurisdiction. In the case of a patient on authorized leave, if it appears to be for the best interest of the public or for the interest and benefit of such patient, the patient may return or be returned by the patient's guardian, relatives or friends or the patient may be recalled by the authorities of such institution, at any time during such temporary absence and prior to the patient's official discharge. With respect both to patients on authorized and unauthorized leave, state or local police shall, on the request of the authorities of any such institution, assist in the rehospitalization of any patient on temporary leave or of any other patient committed to such institution by a court of competent jurisdiction or any person who is a patient under the provisions of section17a-502, if, in the opinion of such authorities, the patient's condition warrants such assistance. The expense, if any, of such recall or return shall, in the case of an indigent, be paid by those responsible for the patient's support or, in the case of a pauper, by the state. Leave under this section shall not be available to any person who is under a term of imprisonment or who has not met the requirements of the condition of release set to provide reasonable assurance of such person's appearance in court.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>