<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-543"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-543"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-543"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-543/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-543/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-543/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-543/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_543">
          <num>17a-543</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-206d). Procedures governing medication, treatment, psychosurgery and shock therapy</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No patient shall receive medication for the treatment of the psychiatric disabilities of such patient without the informed consent of such patient, except in accordance with procedures set forth in subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>,</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>,</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section or in accordance with section17a-543a,17a-566or54-56d.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No medical or surgical procedures may be performed without the patient's written informed consent or, if the patient has been declared incapable of caring for himself or herself pursuant to sections45a-644to45a-662, inclusive, and a conservator of the person has been appointed pursuant to section45a-650, the written consent of such conservator. If the head of the hospital, in consultation with a physician, determines that the condition of an involuntary patient not declared incapable of caring for himself or herself pursuant to said sections is of an extremely critical nature and the patient is incapable of informed consent, medical or surgical procedures may be performed with the written informed consent of:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The patient's health care representative;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the patient's conservator or guardian, if he or she has one;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the patient's next of kin;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_b__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a person designated by the patient pursuant to section1-56r; or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_b__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a qualified physician appointed by a judge of the Probate Court. Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, if obtaining the consent provided for in this section would cause a medically harmful delay to a voluntary or involuntary patient whose condition is of an extremely critical nature, as determined by personal observation by a physician or the senior clinician on duty, emergency treatment may be provided without consent.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No psychosurgery or shock therapy shall be administered to any patient without the patient's written informed consent, except as provided in this subsection. Such consent shall be for a maximum period of thirty days and may be revoked at any time. If it is determined by the head of the hospital and two qualified physicians that the patient has become incapable of giving informed consent, shock therapy may be administered upon order of the Probate Court if, after hearing, such court finds that the patient is incapable of informed consent and there is no other, less intrusive beneficial treatment. An order of the Probate Court authorizing the administration of shock therapy pursuant to this subsection shall be effective for not more than forty-five days.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A facility may establish an internal procedure governing decisions concerning involuntary medication treatment for inpatients. Such procedure shall provide</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>that any decision concerning involuntary medication treatment shall be made by a person who is not employed by the facility in which the patient is receiving treatment, provided the selection of such person shall not be made until the patient's advocate has had reasonable opportunity to discuss such selection with the facility,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>written and oral notification to the patient of available advocacy services,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_d__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>notice to the patient and the patient's advocate, if one has been chosen, of any proceeding for the determination of the necessity for involuntary treatment not less than forty-eight hours prior to such proceeding,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_d__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the right of the patient to representation during any such proceeding,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_d__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>questioning of any witness at any such proceeding including, if requested, one or both of the physicians who made the determination pursuant to subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section concerning the patient's capacity to give informed consent and the necessity of medication for the patient's treatment, and</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_e__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a written decision. If a decision is made in accordance with the standards set forth in this section that a patient shall receive involuntary medication, and there is substantial probability that without such medication for the treatment of the psychiatric disabilities of the patient the condition of the patient will rapidly deteriorate, such involuntary medication may be provided for a period not to exceed thirty days or until a decision is made by the Probate Court under subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, whichever is sooner.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_e__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>(A) If it is determined by the head of the hospital and two qualified physicians that a patient is incapable of giving informed consent to medication for the treatment of the patient's psychiatric disabilities and such medication is deemed to be necessary for the patient's treatment, a facility may utilize the procedures established in subsection</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_543__subsec_e__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If it is determined by the head of the hospital and two qualified physicians that a patient is incapable of giving informed consent to medication for the treatment of the patient's psychiatric disabilities and such medication is deemed to be necessary for the patient's treatment, a facility may utilize the procedures established in subsection</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section and may apply to the Probate Court for appointment of a conservator of the person with specific authority to consent to the administration of medication or, in a case where a conservator of the person has previously been appointed under section45a-650, the facility or the conservator may petition the Probate Court to grant such specific authority to the conservator. The Probate Court may appoint a conservator with such specific authority pursuant to this subparagraph if the court finds by clear and convincing evidence that the patient is incapable of giving informed consent to medication for the treatment of the patient's psychiatric disability and such medication is necessary for the patient's treatment.
(B) The conservator shall meet with the patient and the physician, review the patient's written record and consider the risks and benefits from the medication, the likelihood and seriousness of adverse side effects, the preferences of the patient, the patient's religious views, and the prognosis with and without medication. After consideration of such information, the conservator shall either consent to the patient receiving medication for the treatment of the patient's psychiatric disabilities or refuse to consent to the patient receiving such medication.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The authority of a conservator to consent to the administration of medication under subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection shall be effective for not more than one hundred twenty days. In the case of continuous hospitalization of the patient beyond such one hundred twenty days, if the head of the hospital and two qualified physicians determine that the patient continues to be incapable of giving informed consent to medication for the treatment of the patient's psychiatric disabilities and such medication is deemed to be necessary for the patient's treatment, the authority of the conservator to consent to the administration of medication may be extended for a period not to exceed one hundred twenty days by order of the Probate Court without a hearing upon application by the head of the hospital. Prompt notice of the order shall be given to the patient, conservator and facility.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_f__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If it is determined by the head of the hospital and two qualified physicians that (A) a patient is capable of giving informed consent but refuses to consent to medication for treatment of the patient's psychiatric disabilities, (B) there is no less intrusive beneficial treatment, and (C) without medication, the psychiatric disabilities with which the patient has been diagnosed will continue unabated and place the patient or others in direct threat of harm, the facility may utilize the procedures established in subsection</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_543__subsec_f__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a patient is capable of giving informed consent but refuses to consent to medication for treatment of the patient's psychiatric disabilities,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_543__subsec_f__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>there is no less intrusive beneficial treatment, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_543__subsec_f__subsec_1__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>without medication, the psychiatric disabilities with which the patient has been diagnosed will continue unabated and place the patient or others in direct threat of harm, the facility may utilize the procedures established in subsection</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section and may apply to the Probate Court to authorize the administration to the patient of medication for the treatment of the patient's psychiatric disabilities, despite the refusal of the patient to consent to such medication. The Probate Court may authorize the administration of medication to the patient pursuant to this subdivision if the court finds by clear and convincing evidence that</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the patient is capable of giving informed consent but refuses to consent to medication for treatment of the patient's psychiatric disabilities, (ii) there is no less intrusive beneficial treatment, and (iii) without medication, the psychiatric disabilities with which the patient has been diagnosed will continue unabated and place the patient or others in direct threat of harm.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_i__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An order authorizing the administration of medication under subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_543__subsec_i__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection shall be effective for not more than one hundred twenty days. In the case of continuous hospitalization of the patient beyond such one hundred twenty days, if the head of the hospital and two qualified physicians determine that (A) the patient continues to be capable of giving informed consent but refuses to consent to medication for treatment of the patient's psychiatric disabilities, (B) there is no less intrusive beneficial treatment, and (C) without medication, the psychiatric disabilities with which the patient has been diagnosed will continue unabated and place the patient or others in direct threat of harm, the order may be extended for a period not to exceed one hundred twenty days by order of the Probate Court without a hearing. Prompt notice of the order shall be given to the patient and facility.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_543__subsec_i__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the patient continues to be capable of giving informed consent but refuses to consent to medication for treatment of the patient's psychiatric disabilities,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_543__subsec_i__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>there is no less intrusive beneficial treatment, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_543__subsec_i__subsec_1__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>without medication, the psychiatric disabilities with which the patient has been diagnosed will continue unabated and place the patient or others in direct threat of harm, the order may be extended for a period not to exceed one hundred twenty days by order of the Probate Court without a hearing. Prompt notice of the order shall be given to the patient and facility.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a decision has been made to administer involuntary medication to a patient pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, the patient may petition the Probate Court to expedite the hearing on an application filed by the facility pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section or, if no application has been filed, to hold a hearing to decide whether to allow the administration of involuntary medication. Either hearing shall be held within fifteen days after the date of the patient's petition.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of this section, “voluntary patient” means any patient sixteen years of age or older who applies in writing for, and is admitted to, a hospital for observation, diagnosis or treatment of a mental disorder.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_543__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Unless there is a serious risk of harm to the patient or others, based upon the patient's past history or current condition, nothing in this section authorizes any form of involuntary medical, psychological or psychiatric treatment of any patient who in the sincere practice of his or her religious beliefs is being treated by prayer alone in accordance with the principles and practices of a church or religious denomination by a duly accredited practitioner or ordained minister, priest or rabbi thereof. The Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services shall adopt regulations, in accordance with chapter 54, to implement the purposes of this subsection.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>