<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-540"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-540"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-540"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-540/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-540/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-540/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-540/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_540">
          <num>17a-540</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-206a). Definitions</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 17a-540. (Formerly Sec. 17-206a). Definitions.As used in sections17a-540to17a-550, inclusive, unless otherwise expressly stated or unless the context otherwise requires:
(1) “Facility” means any inpatient or outpatient hospital, clinic or other facility for the diagnosis, observation or treatment of persons with psychiatric disabilities;
(2) “Patient” means any person being treated in a facility;
(3) “Persons with psychiatric disabilities” means those children and adults who are suffering from one or more mental disorders, as defined in the most recent edition of the American Psychiatric Association's “Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders”;
(4) “Voluntary patient” means any patient sixteen years of age or older who applies in writing for and is admitted to a hospital for observation, diagnosis or treatment of a mental disorder or any patient under sixteen years of age whose parent or legal guardian applies in writing for such observation, diagnosis or treatment;
(5) “Involuntary patient” means any patient hospitalized pursuant to an order of a judge of the Probate Court after an appropriate hearing or a patient hospitalized for emergency diagnosis, observation or treatment upon certification of a qualified physician;
(6) “Family” means spouse or next of kin;
(7) “Head of the hospital” or “head of the facility” means the superintendent or medical director of a hospital or facility, or his designated delegate;
(8) “Informed consent” means permission given competently and voluntarily after a patient has been informed of the reason for treatment, the nature of the proposed treatment, the advantages or disadvantages of the treatment, medically acceptable alternative treatment, the risks associated with receiving the proposed treatment and the risk of no treatment;
(9) “Medically harmful” means capable of inflicting serious mental or physical injury on the patient, or producing in the patient a disturbed mental state or impaired judgment which may be grossly detrimental to his physical or mental well being;
(10) “Psychosurgery” means those operations defined as lobotomy, psychiatric surgery, behavioral surgery and all other forms of brain surgery, if the surgery is performed for the purpose of modification or control of thoughts, feelings, actions or behavior rather than the treatment of a known and diagnosed physical disease of the brain;
(11) “Shock therapy” means a form of psychiatric treatment in which electric current, insulin, carbon dioxide or indoklon, or other similar agent, is administered to the patient and results in a loss of consciousness or a convulsive or comatose reaction;
(12) “Direct threat of harm” means that the patient's clinical history demonstrates a pattern of serious physical injury or life-threatening injury to self or to others which is caused by the psychiatric disabilities with which the patient has been diagnosed and is documented by objective medical and other factual evidence. Such evidence of past pattern of dangerous behavior shall be manifested in the patient's medical history and there shall exist a high probability that the patient will inflict substantial harm on himself or others; and
(13) “Special limited conservator” means a licensed health care provider with specialized training in the treatment of persons with psychiatric disabilities appointed by a judge of the Probate Court with specific authority to consent to the administration of medication to a defendant during the pendency of such defendant's placement in the custody of the Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services pursuant to section54-56d. Upon the termination of the patient's placement in the custody of the commissioner pursuant to section54-56d, the special limited conservatorship shall automatically terminate.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>