<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-498"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-498"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-498"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-498/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-498/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-498/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-498/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_498">
          <num>17a-498</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-178). Hearing on commitment application. Notice. Rights of respondent. Examination by physicians. Order of commitment. Election of voluntary status prior to adjudication. Review of confinement</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon an application being filed in the Probate Court pursuant to the Probate Court's jurisdiction under section17a-497, such court shall assign a time, not later than ten business days after the date the application was filed, and a place for hearing such application, and shall cause reasonable notice of such hearing to be given to the respondent and to such relative or relatives and friends as the court deems advisable. The notice shall inform the respondent that he or she has a right to be present at the hearing; that he or she has a right to counsel; that he or she, if indigent, has a right to have counsel appointed to represent him or her; and that he or she has a right to cross-examine witnesses testifying at any hearing upon such application.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <paragraph eId="17a_498__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the court finds such respondent is indigent or otherwise unable to pay for counsel, the court shall appoint counsel for such respondent, unless such respondent refuses counsel and the court finds that the respondent understands the nature of his or her refusal. The court shall provide such respondent a reasonable opportunity to select his or her own counsel to be appointed by the court. If the respondent does not select counsel or if counsel selected by the respondent refuses to represent such respondent or is not available for such representation, the court shall appoint counsel for the respondent from a panel of attorneys admitted to practice in this state provided by the Probate Court Administrator in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Probate Court Administrator in accordance with section45a-77. The reasonable compensation of appointed counsel shall be established by, and paid from funds appropriated to, the Judicial Department, except that if funds have not been included in the budget of the Judicial Department for such purposes, such compensation shall be established by the Probate Court Administrator and paid from the Probate Court Administration Fund.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_498__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Prior to such hearing, such respondent or his or her counsel, in accordance with the provisions of sections52-146dto52-146i, inclusive, shall be afforded access to all records including, but not limited to, hospital records if such respondent is hospitalized, and shall be entitled to take notes from any of such records. If such respondent is hospitalized at the time of the hearing, the hospital shall make available at such hearing for use by such hospitalized respondent or his or her counsel all records in its possession relating to the condition of such hospitalized respondent. Notwithstanding the provisions of sections52-146dto52-146i, inclusive, and subject to the rules of evidence as provided in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, all such hospital records directly relating to the hospitalized respondent shall be admissible at the request of any party or the Probate Court in any proceeding relating to confinement to or release from a hospital for psychiatric disabilities.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <paragraph eId="17a_498__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The court shall require the certificates, signed under penalty of false statement, of at least two impartial physicians selected by the court, one of whom shall be a practicing psychiatrist, and each of whom shall be licensed to practice medicine in the state of Connecticut and shall have been a practitioner of medicine for at least one year and shall not be connected with the hospital for psychiatric disabilities to which the application is being made, or related by blood or marriage to the applicant, or to the respondent. Such certificates shall indicate that the physicians have personally examined the respondent not more than ten days prior to such hearing. The court shall appoint such physicians from a list of physicians and psychiatrists provided by the Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services and such appointments shall be made in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Probate Court Administrator in accordance with section45a-77. Each such physician shall make a report on a separate form provided for that purpose by the Probate Court Administrator and shall answer such questions as may be set forth on such form as fully and completely as reasonably possible. Such form shall include, but not be limited to, questions relating to the specific psychiatric disabilities alleged, whether or not the respondent is dangerous to himself or herself or others, whether or not such illness has resulted or will result in serious disruption of the respondent's mental and behavioral functioning, whether or not hospital treatment is both necessary and available, whether or not less restrictive placement is recommended and available and whether or not the respondent is incapable of understanding the need to accept the recommended treatment on a voluntary basis. Each such physician shall state upon the form the reasons for his or her opinions. Such respondent or his or her counsel shall have the right to present evidence and cross-examine witnesses who testify </p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_498__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The court shall cause a recording of the testimony of such hearing to be made, to be transcribed only in the event of an appeal from the decree rendered under this section. A copy of such transcript shall be furnished without charge to any appellant whom the Probate Court finds unable to pay for such copy. The cost of such transcript shall be paid from funds appropriated to the Judicial Department.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_498__subsec_c__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the court finds by clear and convincing evidence that the respondent has psychiatric disabilities and is dangerous to himself or herself or others or gravely disabled, the court shall make an order for his or her commitment, considering whether or not a less restrictive placement is available, to a hospital for psychiatric disabilities to be named in such order, there to be confined for the period of the duration of such psychiatric disabilities or until he or she is discharged or converted to voluntary status pursuant to section17a-506in due course of law. Such court order shall further command some suitable person to convey such person to such hospital for psychiatric disabilities and deliver him or her, with a copy of such order and of such certificates, to the keeper thereof. In appointing a person to execute such order, the court shall give preference to a near relative or friend of the person with psychiatric disabilities, so far as the court deems it practicable and judicious. Notice of any action taken by the court shall be given to the respondent and his or her attorney, if any, in such manner as the court concludes would be appropriate under the circumstances.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the respondent refuses to be examined by the court-appointed physicians as provided in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, the court may issue a warrant for the apprehension of the respondent and a police officer for the town in which such court is located or if there is no such police officer then the state police shall deliver the respondent to a general hospital where the respondent shall be examined by two physicians, one of whom shall be a practicing psychiatrist, in accordance with subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section. If as a result of such examination, the respondent is committed under section17a-502, transportation of the respondent to any such hospital, if such respondent is a female, shall be in accordance with the provisions of section17a-505. If the respondent is not committed under section17a-502, the respondent shall be released and the reports of such physicians shall be sent to the Probate Court to satisfy the requirement of examination by two physicians under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The respondent shall be given the opportunity to elect voluntary status under section17a-506at any time prior to adjudication of the application, subject to the following provisions:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_498__subsec_e__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In the event that a patient is in the hospital, the patient shall be informed by a member of the hospital staff within twenty-four hours prior to the time an application is filed with the court, that he or she may continue in the hospital on a voluntary basis under the provisions of section17a-506, and any application for involuntary commitment by the hospital shall include a statement that such voluntary status has been offered to the respondent and refused, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_498__subsec_e__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>in the event that a respondent is not hospitalized, the notice of hearing shall inform the respondent that the respondent has the right to enter the hospital on a voluntary basis under the provisions of section17a-506, and, if the respondent enters the hospital under section17a-506, the application for involuntary commitment shall be withdrawn. When any patient who has elected voluntary status following the filing of an application but prior to adjudication in any proceeding for involuntary commitment thereafter notifies the hospital that he or she wants to be released, a new application for involuntary commitment may be filed. If such new application is filed not later than forty-five days after the patient's election of voluntary status on a prior application, the application for involuntary commitment may, at the discretion of the judge, be heard on the merits, notwithstanding the patient's subsequent request to remain a voluntary patient under the provisions of section17a-506. Notwithstanding the provisions of sections17a-29,17a-540,17a-543,17a-544, subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section17a-547and section17a-548, if a patient under section17a-506refuses to accept medication or treatment in accordance with the treatment plan prescribed by the attending physician and such patient is imminently dangerous to himself or others, an application for involuntary commitment may be filed for such patient in accordance with the provisions of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <heading>The respondent shall be present at any hearing for his or her commitment under this section</heading>
            <content>
              <p>If the respondent is medicated at that time, the hospital shall provide written notice to the court of such fact and of the common effects of such medication.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The hospital shall notify each patient at least annually that such patient has a right to a further hearing pursuant to this section. If the patient requests such hearing, it shall be held by the Probate Court for the district in which the hospital is located. Any such request shall be immediately filed with the appropriate court by the hospital. After such request is filed with the Probate Court, it shall proceed in the manner provided in subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>,</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>,</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section. In addition, the hospital shall furnish the Probate Court for the district in which the hospital is located on a monthly basis with a list of all patients confined in the hospital involuntarily without release for one year since the last annual review under this section of the patient's commitment or since the original commitment. The hospital shall include in such notification the type of review the patient last received. If the patient's last annual review had a hearing, the Probate Court shall, within fifteen business days thereafter, appoint an impartial physician who is a psychiatrist from the list provided by the Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services as set forth in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section and not connected with the hospital in which the patient is confined or related by blood or marriage to the original applicant or to the respondent, which physician shall see and examine each such patient within fifteen business days after such physician's appointment and make a report forthwith to such court of the condition of the patient on forms provided by the Probate Court Administrator. If the Probate Court concludes that the confinement of any such patient should be reviewed by such court for possible release of the patient, the court, on its own motion, shall proceed in the manner provided in subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>,</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>,</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, except that the examining physician shall be considered one of the physicians required by subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section. If the patient's last annual review did not result in a hearing, and in any event at least every two years, the Probate Court shall, within fifteen business days, proceed with a hearing in the manner provided in subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>,</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>,</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section. All costs and expenses, including Probate Court entry fees provided by statute, in conjunction with the annual psychiatric review and the judicial review under this subsection, except costs for physicians appointed pursuant to this subsection, shall be established by, and paid from funds appropriated to, the Judicial Department, except that if funds have not been included in the budget of the Judicial Department for such costs and expenses, such payment shall be made from the Probate Court Administration Fund. Compensation of any physician appointed to conduct the annual psychiatric review, to examine a patient for any hearing held as a result of such annual review or for any other biennial hearing required pursuant to sections17a-75to17a-83, inclusive,17a-450to17a-483, inclusive,17a-495to17a-528, inclusive,17a-540to17a-550, inclusive,17a-560to17a-575, inclusive, and17a-615to17a-618, inclusive, shall be paid by the state from funds appropriated to the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services in accordance with rates established by the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_498__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The rules of evidence applicable to civil matters in the Superior Court shall apply to hearings under this section.
See Sec. 17a-507 re admission to general hospital having psychiatric facilities.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>