<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-485c"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-485c"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-485c"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-485c/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-485c/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-485c/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-485c/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_485c">
          <num>17a-485c</num>
          <heading>Permanent supportive housing initiatives. Requests for proposals</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_485c__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services, in collaboration with the Commissioners of Social Services, Correction, Children and Families, Housing, Developmental Services and Veterans Affairs, the Connecticut Housing Finance Authority and the Court Support Services Division of the Judicial Branch, shall establish permanent supportive housing initiatives to provide additional units of affordable housing and support services to eligible persons. Individuals and families with special needs and individuals and families that are homeless or at risk for homelessness shall be eligible for such permanent supportive housing initiatives.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_485c__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Connecticut Housing Finance Authority shall issue one or more requests for proposals by persons or entities interested in participating in such permanent supportive housing initiatives to applicants that include organizations deemed qualified to provide services by the Departments of Mental Health and Addiction Services, Social Services and Children and Families. The Connecticut Housing Finance Authority shall review and underwrite development projects undertaken pursuant to such permanent supportive housing initiatives.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_485c__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Departments of Mental Health and Addiction Services and Social Services shall issue, within available appropriations, one or more requests for proposals in a scattered site model for homeless individuals with psychiatric disabilities and substance use disorders.
See Sec. 17a-485e re state authority to enter into contracts with Connecticut Housing Finance Authority to effectuate permanent supportive housing initiatives.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>