<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-528"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-528"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-528"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-528/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-528/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-528/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-528/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_528">
          <num>17a-528</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-205a). Payment of commitment and transportation expenses</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_528__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When any person is found to have psychiatric disabilities, and is committed to a state hospital for psychiatric disabilities, upon proceedings had under sections17a-75to17a-83, inclusive,17a-450to17a-483, inclusive,17a-495to17a-528, inclusive,17a-540to17a-550, inclusive,17a-560to17a-575, inclusive, and17a-615to17a-618, inclusive, all fees and expenses incurred upon the probate commitment proceedings, payment of which is not otherwise provided for under said sections, shall be paid by the state within available appropriations from funds appropriated to the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services in accordance with rates established by said department; and, if such person is found not to have psychiatric disabilities, such fees and expenses shall be paid by the applicant.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_528__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Within available appropriations, the expenses, if any, of necessary transportation</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_528__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>from a state-aided, town-aided or other municipal-aided hospital to a state-operated facility, as defined in section17a-458, for detention of any person under section17a-502;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_528__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>for any voluntary patient who wishes to have emergency treatment for conditions defined in section17a-502at any such state-operated facility;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_528__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>for any patient who has been released on leave from any such state-operated facility and wishes to return; or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_528__subsec_b__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>for persons authorized by the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services to receive inpatient psychiatric services in a facility under contract with the department to provide such services, shall be paid by the state, unless, after investigation, the Department of Administrative Services determines such person is able to pay for the same. The presence of an appropriate emergency certificate under section17a-502shall be sufficient for payment by the state under subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_528__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, regardless of the eventual commitment or noncommitment of the person to the facility. The Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services may adopt regulations concerning the payment of transportation expenses by the state under this subsection.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_528__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The expenses of medically necessary transportation from any facility operated by the state to any other such facility shall be assumed by the facility which initiated the transfer of such person.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>