<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-476"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-476"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-476"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-476/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-476/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-476/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-476/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_476">
          <num>17a-476</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-226b). Grants to general hospitals, municipalities and nonprofit organizations for mental health services</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_476__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any general hospital, municipality or nonprofit organization in Connecticut may apply to the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services for funds to establish, expand or maintain psychiatric or mental health services. The application for funds shall be submitted on forms provided by the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services, and shall be accompanied by</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_476__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a definition of the towns and areas to be served;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_476__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a plan by means of which the applicant proposes to coordinate its activities with those of other local agencies presently supplying mental health services or contributing in any way to the mental health of the area;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_476__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a description of the services to be provided, and the methods through which these services will be provided; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_476__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>indication of the methods that will be employed to effect a balance in the use of state and local resources so as to foster local initiative, responsibility and participation. In accordance with subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_476__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of section17a-480, the regional behavioral health action organization serving the mental health region in which the applicant is located shall review each such application with the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services and make recommendations to the department with respect to each such application.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_476__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon receipt of the application with the recommendations of the regional behavioral health action organization and approval by the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services, the department shall grant such funds by way of a contract or grant-in-aid within the appropriation for any annual fiscal year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_476__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services may adopt regulations, in accordance with the provisions of chapter 54, concerning minimum standards for eligibility to receive said state contracted funds and any grants-in-aid. Any such funds or grants-in-aid made by the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services for psychiatric or mental health services shall be made directly to the agency submitting the application and providing such service or services.
See Sec. 17a-482 for applicable definitions.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>