<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-580"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-580"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-580"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-580/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-580/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-580/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-580/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_580">
          <num>17a-580</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-257a). Definitions</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 17a-580. (Formerly Sec. 17-257a). Definitions.As used in sections17a-581to17a-603, inclusive, and this section:
(1) “Acquittee” means any person found not guilty by reason of mental disease or defect pursuant to section53a-13;
(2) “Board” means the Psychiatric Security Review Board established pursuant to section17a-581;
(3) “Conditional release” means release of the acquittee from a hospital for psychiatric disabilities to the jurisdiction of the board for supervision and treatment and includes, but is not limited to, the monitoring of mental and physical health treatment;
(4) “Court” means the Superior Court;
(5) “Danger to himself or others” includes danger to the property of others;
(6) “Hospital for psychiatric disabilities” means any public or private hospital, retreat, institution, house or place in which a person with psychiatric disabilities or drug-dependent person is received or detained as a patient, but does not include any correctional institution of the state;
(7) “Psychiatric disability” includes any mental illness in a state of remission when the illness may, with reasonable medical probability, become active. “Psychiatric disability” does not include an abnormality manifested only by repeated criminal or otherwise antisocial conduct;
(8) “Intellectual disability” has the same meaning as provided in section1-1g;
(9) “Person who should be conditionally released” means an acquittee who has psychiatric disabilities or has intellectual disability to the extent that his final discharge would constitute a danger to himself or others but who can be adequately controlled with available supervision and treatment on conditional release;
(10) “Person who should be confined” means an acquittee who has psychiatric disabilities or has intellectual disability to the extent that such acquittee's discharge or conditional release would constitute a danger to the acquittee or others and who cannot be adequately controlled with available supervision and treatment on conditional release;
(11) “Person who should be discharged” means an acquittee who does not have psychiatric disabilities or does not have intellectual disability to the extent that such acquittee's discharge would constitute a danger to the acquittee or others;
(12) “Psychiatrist” means a physician specializing in psychiatry and licensed under the provisions of sections20-9to20-12, inclusive;
(13) “Psychologist” means a clinical psychologist licensed under the provisions of sections20-186to20-195, inclusive;
(14) “State's attorney” means the state's attorney for the judicial district wherein the acquittee was found not guilty by reason of mental disease or defect pursuant to section53a-13; and
(15) “Superintendent” means any person, body of persons or corporation, or the designee of any such person, body of persons or corporation, which has the immediate supervision, management and control of a hospital for psychiatric disabilities and the patients therein.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>