<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-587"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-587"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-587"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-587/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-587/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-587/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-587/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_587">
          <num>17a-587</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-257h). Temporary leave. Notification to victim. Application for order of temporary leave. Supervision of acquittee on temporary leave</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_587__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If at any time after the confinement of an acquittee in a hospital for psychiatric disabilities or the placement of an acquittee with the Commissioner of Developmental Services pursuant to order of the board, the superintendent of such hospital or said commissioner is of the opinion that the acquittee's psychiatric supervision and treatment would be advanced by permitting the acquittee to leave such hospital or the custody of said commissioner temporarily, the superintendent or said commissioner shall apply to the board for an order authorizing temporary leaves. The application shall include a statement of reasons in support thereof. The board shall send a copy of the application to the state's attorney. The board may order a hearing on the application and shall order such a hearing if the state's attorney files with the board a request therefor within ten days of his receipt of the application. The board shall grant the application, subject to such conditions and supervision as the board may set in the order for temporary leave, if it concludes that the acquittee's temporary leave, under the conditions specified, would not constitute a danger to the acquittee or others. If the board grants such application,</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_587__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the acquittee may be permitted to leave such hospital or the custody of said commissioner temporarily, under the charge of his guardian, relatives or friends, or by himself or herself, at such times and under such conditions as the superintendent or said commissioner deems appropriate, unless the order of the board provides otherwise, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_587__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the board shall notify the victim, as defined in section17a-601, of the acquittee regarding such temporary leave.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_587__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>At any time after the confinement of an acquittee in a hospital for psychiatric disabilities or the placement of an acquittee with the Commissioner of Developmental Services, the acquittee, or another person acting on the acquittee's behalf, may apply to the board for an order of temporary leave. On receipt of the application, the board shall request that the superintendent of the hospital or said commissioner report on whether such superintendent or said commissioner is of the opinion that the acquittee should be granted temporary leave. The report shall include facts supporting such opinion. An application for temporary leave under this subsection shall not be filed more frequently than once every six months from the date of the initial hearing held by the board pursuant to section17a-583. The board shall not be required to hold a hearing on the first application made by an acquittee under this subsection any earlier than ninety days after the date of such initial hearing. Any hearing resulting from any subsequent application of the acquittee shall be held not less than thirty days but not more than ninety days after the date of the filing of such application. If the board grants an application made under this subsection,</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_587__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the acquittee may be permitted to leave such hospital or the custody of said commissioner temporarily, under the charge of his guardian, relatives or friends, or by himself or herself, at such times and under such conditions as the superintendent or said commissioner deems appropriate, unless the order of the board provides otherwise, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_587__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the board shall notify the victim, as defined in section17a-601, regarding such temporary leave.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_587__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board may designate any capable person or appropriate public or private agency to supervise the acquittee on temporary leave pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_587__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_587__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section. Prior to any designation, the board shall notify the person or agency that the board contemplates designating to supervise the acquittee's temporary leave and provide the person or agency with an opportunity to be heard before the board. Any person or agency designated by the board to supervise the acquittee's temporary leave shall comply with such conditions as the board sets in the order for temporary leave.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>