<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-582"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-582"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-582"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-582/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-582/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-582/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-582/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319i">
        <num>319i</num>
        <heading>Connecticut HUSKY Plan</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_582">
          <num>17a-582</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-257c). Confinement of acquittee for examination. Court order of commitment to board or discharge</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_582__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When any person charged with an offense is found not guilty by reason of mental disease or defect pursuant to section53a-13, the court shall order such acquittee committed to the custody of the Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services who shall cause such acquittee to be confined, pending an order of the court pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_582__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, in any of the state hospitals for psychiatric disabilities or to the custody of the Commissioner of Developmental Services, for an examination to determine his mental condition.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_582__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Not later than sixty days after the order of commitment pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_582__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, the superintendent of such hospital or the Commissioner of Developmental Services shall cause the acquittee to be examined and file a report of the examination with the court, and shall send a copy thereof to the state's attorney and counsel for the acquittee, setting forth the superintendent's or said commissioner's findings and conclusions as to whether the acquittee is a person who should be discharged. The report shall indicate whether the acquittee submitted or refused to submit to the taking of a blood or other biological sample pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_582__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section54-102g.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_582__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Not later than ten days after receipt of such superintendent's or said commissioner's report, either the state's attorney or counsel for the acquittee may file notice of intent to perform a separate examination of the acquittee. An examination conducted on behalf of the acquittee may be performed by a psychiatrist or psychologist chosen by the acquittee and shall be performed at the acquittee's expense unless the acquittee is indigent. If the acquittee is indigent, the court shall provide the acquittee with the services of a psychiatrist or psychologist to perform the examination at the expense of the state. The superintendent or said commissioner who conducted the initial examination shall, not later than five days after a request of any party conducting a separate examination pursuant to this subsection, release to such party all records and reports compiled in the initial examination of the acquittee. Any separate examination report shall be filed with the court not later than thirty days after the filing with the court of the initial examination report by the superintendent or said commissioner.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_582__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall commence a hearing not later than fifteen days after its receipt of any separate examination report or if no notice of intent to perform a separate examination has been filed under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_582__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, not later than twenty-five days after the filing of such initial examination report.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_582__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>At the hearing, the court shall make a finding as to the mental condition of the acquittee and, considering that its primary concerns are the protection of society and the safety and well-being of the acquittee, make one of the following orders:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_582__subsec_e__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the court finds that the acquittee is a person who should be confined or conditionally released, the court shall order the acquittee committed to the jurisdiction of the board and either confined in a hospital for psychiatric disabilities or placed with the Commissioner of Developmental Services, for custody, care and treatment pending a hearing before the board pursuant to section17a-583; provided (A) the court shall fix a maximum term of commitment, not to exceed the maximum sentence that could have been imposed if the acquittee had been convicted of the offense, and (B) if there is reason to believe that the acquittee is a person who should be conditionally released, the court shall include in the order a recommendation to the board that the acquittee be considered for conditional release pursuant to subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_582__subsec_e__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the court shall fix a maximum term of commitment, not to exceed the maximum sentence that could have been imposed if the acquittee had been convicted of the offense, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17a_582__subsec_e__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>if there is reason to believe that the acquittee is a person who should be conditionally released, the court shall include in the order a recommendation to the board that the acquittee be considered for conditional release pursuant to subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_582__subsec_e__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of section17a-584; or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_582__subsec_e__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the court finds that the acquittee is a person who should be discharged, the court shall order the acquittee discharged from custody.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_582__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>At the hearing before the court, the acquittee shall have the burden of proving by a preponderance of the evidence that the acquittee is a person who should be discharged.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_582__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An order of the court pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_582__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section may be appealed by the acquittee or the state's attorney to the Appellate Court. The court shall so notify the acquittee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_582__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <content>
              <p>During any term of commitment to the board, the acquittee shall remain under the jurisdiction of the board until discharged by the court pursuant to section17a-593. Except as provided in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_582__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of said section, the acquittee shall be immediately discharged at the expiration of the maximum term of commitment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_582__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On committing an acquittee to the jurisdiction of the board, the court shall advise the acquittee of the right to a hearing before the board in accordance with section17a-583.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>