<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-206"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-206"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-206"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_207">
        <num>207</num>
        <heading>Gift Tax</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_206">
          <num>12-206</num>
          <heading>Penalties for late filing and wilful submission of fraudulent return or document</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_206__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any company fails to pay the amount of tax reported to be due on its return within the time specified under the provisions of this chapter, there shall be imposed a penalty equal to ten per cent of such amount due and unpaid, or fifty dollars, whichever is greater. Such amount shall bear interest at the rate of one per cent per month or fraction thereof, from the due date of such tax until the date of payment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_206__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any company has not made its return within three months after the time specified under the provisions of this chapter, the commissioner may make such return at any time thereafter, according to the best information obtainable and according to the form prescribed. To the tax imposed upon the basis of such return, there shall be added an amount equal to ten per cent of such tax, or fifty dollars, whichever is greater. The tax shall bear interest at the rate of one per cent per month or fraction thereof, from the due date of such tax until the date of payment. No taxpayer shall be subject to a penalty under both subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_206__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_206__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section in relation to the same tax period.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_206__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subject to the provisions of section12-3a, the commissioner may waive all or part of the penalties provided under this chapter when it is proven to his satisfaction that the failure to pay any tax was due to reasonable cause and was not intentional or due to neglect.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_206__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person required under this chapter to pay any tax, or required under this chapter or by regulations adopted in accordance with the provisions of section12-204gto make a return, keep any records or supply any information, who wilfully fails to pay such tax, make such return, keep such records or supply such information, at the time required by law or regulations, shall, in addition to any other penalty provided by law, be fined not more than one thousand dollars or imprisoned not more than one year or both. As used in this subsection, “person” includes any officer or employee of a corporation, or a member or employee of a partnership under a duty to pay such tax, to make such return, keep such records or supply such information. Notwithstanding the provisions of section54-193, no person shall be prosecuted for a violation of the provisions of this subsection committed on or after July 1, 1997, except within three years next after such violation has been committed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_206__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who wilfully delivers or discloses to the commissioner or his authorized agent any list, return, account, statement, or other document, known by him to be fraudulent or false in any material matter, shall, in addition to any other penalty provided by law, be guilty of a class D felony. No person shall be charged with an offense under both subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_206__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_206__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section in relation to the same tax period but such person may be charged and prosecuted for both such offenses upon the same information.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_206__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_206__subsec_f__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any company subject to any tax or charge under this chapter, believing that it has overpaid any tax, other than any estimated tax paid pursuant to section12-204c, due under the provisions of this chapter may file a claim for refund in writing with the commissioner within three years from the due date for which such overpayment was made, stating the specific grounds upon which the claim is founded. Failure to file a claim within the time prescribed in this section constitutes a waiver of any demand against the state on account of overpayment. Not later than ninety days following receipt of such claim for refund, the commissioner shall determine whether such claim is valid and, if so determined, said commissioner shall notify the State Comptroller of the amount of such refund and the State Comptroller shall draw an order on the State Treasurer in the amount thereof for payment to the taxpayer. If the commissioner determines that such claim is not valid, either in whole or in part, he shall mail notice of the proposed disallowance in whole or in part of the claim to the claimant, which notice shall set forth briefly the commissioner's findings of fact and the basis of disallowance in each case decided in whole or in part adversely to the claimant. Sixty days after the date on which it is mailed, a notice of proposed disallowance shall constitute a final disallowance except only for such amounts as to which the company has filed, as provided in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_206__subsec_f__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, a written protest with the commissioner.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_206__subsec_f__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>On or before the sixtieth day after the mailing of the proposed disallowance, the company may file with the commissioner a written protest against the proposed disallowance in which it sets forth the grounds on which the protest is based. If a protest is filed, the commissioner shall reconsider the proposed disallowance and, if the company has so requested, may grant or deny the company or its authorized representatives an oral hearing.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_206__subsec_f__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commissioner shall mail notice of his determination to the company, which notice shall set forth briefly the commissioner's findings of fact and the basis of decision in each case decided in whole or in part adversely to the company.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_206__subsec_f__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The action of the commissioner on the company's protest shall be final upon the expiration of one month from the date on which he mails notice of his action to the company unless within such period the company seeks judicial review of the commissioner's determination pursuant to subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_206__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-208.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>