<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-683"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-683"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-683"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-683/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-683/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-683/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-683/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319j">
        <num>319j</num>
        <heading>Health Care For Uninsured Children</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_683">
          <num>17a-683</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 19a-126c). Police assistance for intoxicated persons. Protective custody of person incapacitated by alcohol. Medical examination. Detention and release. Notification to family. Assistance for nonadmitted person</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_683__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any police officer finding a person who appears to be intoxicated in a public place and in need of help may, with such person's consent, assist such person to his home, a treatment facility, or a hospital or other facility able to accept such person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_683__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any police officer finding a person who appears to be incapacitated by alcohol shall take him into protective custody and have him brought forthwith to a treatment facility which provides medical triage in accordance with regulations adopted pursuant to section19a-495or to a hospital. The police, in detaining the person and in having him brought forthwith to such a treatment facility or a hospital, shall be taking him into protective custody and shall make every reasonable effort to protect his health and safety. In taking the person into protective custody, the detaining officer may take reasonable steps to protect himself. A taking into protective custody under this section is not an arrest. No entry or other record shall be made to indicate that the person has been arrested or charged with a crime. For purposes of this section “medical triage” means a service which provides immediate assessment of symptoms of substance abuse, the immediate care and treatment of these symptoms as necessary, a determination of need for treatment, and assistance in attaining appropriate continued treatment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_683__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who is brought to a treatment facility which provides medical triage in accordance with regulations adopted pursuant to section19a-495or to a hospital shall be examined by a medical officer or his designee as soon as possible. The medical officer shall determine whether the person requires inpatient treatment based upon the medical examination of the person and upon a finding that the person is incapacitated by alcohol.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_683__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the medical officer determines that the person requires inpatient treatment, the person shall be</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_683__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>admitted to, referred to or detained at a treatment facility that provides medical treatment for detoxification or a hospital, or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_683__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>committed to a treatment facility operated by the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services for emergency treatment pursuant to the provisions of section17a-684. A person treated under subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17a_683__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection shall be admitted as a voluntary patient, or, if necessary, detained for necessary treatment. If such person is referred to another treatment facility or another hospital, the referring facility or hospital shall arrange for his transportation.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_683__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person admitted or detained as a patient under subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17a_683__subsec_e__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_683__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section shall be released once he is no longer incapacitated by alcohol or within forty-eight hours, whichever is shorter, unless he consents to further medical evaluation or treatment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_683__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a patient is admitted to a treatment facility or hospital, his family or next of kin shall, unless prohibited by federal law, be notified as promptly as possible. If a patient who is not incapacitated by alcohol requests that there be no notification, his request shall be respected.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_683__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who is not admitted to a treatment facility or a hospital, is not referred to another treatment facility or hospital and has no funds may be taken to his home, if any. If he has no home, the facility shall assist him in obtaining shelter.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>