<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-680"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-680"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-680"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-680/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-680/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-680/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-680/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319j">
        <num>319j</num>
        <heading>Health Care For Uninsured Children</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_680">
          <num>17a-680</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 19a-126). Definitions</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 17a-680. (Formerly Sec. 19a-126). Definitions.For purposes of sections17a-673and17a-680to17a-690, inclusive:
(1) “Alcohol-dependent person” means a person who meets the criteria for moderate or severe alcohol use disorder, as described in the most recent edition of the American Psychiatric Association's “Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders”;
(2) “Business day” means Monday to Friday, inclusive, except when a legal holiday falls on any such day;
(3) “Department” means the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services;
(4) “Dangerous to himself” means there is a substantial risk that physical harm will be inflicted by a person on himself or herself;
(5) “Dangerous to others” means there is a substantial risk that physical harm will be inflicted by a person on another person;
(6) “Drug or drugs” means a controlled drug as defined in section21a-240;
(7) “Drug-dependent person” means a person who meets the criteria for moderate or severe substance use disorder, as described in the most recent edition of the American Psychiatric Association's “Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders”;
(8) “Commissioner” means the Commissioner of Mental Health and Addiction Services;
(9) “Gravely disabled” means a condition in which a person, as a result of the use of alcohol or drugs on a periodic or continuous basis, is in danger of serious physical harm because (A) he or she is not providing for his or her essential needs such as food, clothing, shelter, vital medical care, or safety, (B) he or she needs, but is not receiving, inpatient treatment for alcohol dependency or drug dependency, and (C) he or she is incapable of determining whether to accept such treatment because his or her judgment is impaired;
(10) “Hospital” means an establishment licensed under the provisions of sections19a-490to19a-503, inclusive, for the lodging, care and treatment of persons suffering from disease or other abnormal physical or mental conditions, and includes inpatient psychiatric services in general hospitals;
(11) “Incapacitated by alcohol” means a condition in which a person as a result of the use of alcohol has his or her judgment so impaired that he or she is incapable of realizing and making a rational decision with respect to his or her need for treatment;
(12) “Incompetent person” means a person who has been adjudged incompetent by a court of competent jurisdiction;
(13) “Intoxicated person” means a person whose mental or physical functioning is substantially impaired as a result of the use of alcohol or drugs;
(14) “Medical officer” means a licensed physician in attendance at a treatment facility or hospital;
(15) “Respondent” means a person who is alleged to be alcohol-dependent or drug-dependent and for whom a petition for commitment or recommitment to an inpatient treatment facility has been filed;
(16) “Treatment” means any emergency, outpatient, intermediate and inpatient services and care, including diagnostic evaluation, medical, psychiatric, psychological and social services, vocational and social rehabilitation and other appropriate services, which may be extended to alcohol-dependent persons, drug-dependent persons and intoxicated persons;
(17) “Treatment facility” means (A) a facility providing treatment and operating under the direction and control of the department, or (B) a private facility providing treatment and licensed under the provisions of sections19a-490to19a-503, inclusive.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>