<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-676"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-676"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-676"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-676/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-676/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-676/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-676/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319j">
        <num>319j</num>
        <heading>Health Care For Uninsured Children</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_676">
          <num>17a-676</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 19a-4c). Applications for funds to the department by nonprofit organizations or municipal departments or units</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 17a-676. (Formerly Sec. 19a-4c). Applications for funds to the department by nonprofit organizations or municipal departments or units.Any nonprofit organization in Connecticut or any municipal department or unit which offers or proposes to offer education services, prevention services, public information, community intervention, employees' assistance, training or job development services to alcohol-dependent or drug-dependent persons in the state or treatment or rehabilitation services to such persons either as part of comprehensive community-based services on alcohol dependence or drug dependence or as part of a narcotic addiction treatment center in an area of high incidence of drug addiction, may apply to the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services for state and federal funds to establish, expand or maintain such services. The department may accept requests for funds from any nonprofit organization in Connecticut or any municipal department or unit which offers or proposes to offer the above services, and such services may be funded if they meet the requirements of the department and are in conformance with the state plans concerning alcohol and drug abuse. In the case of treatment or rehabilitation services, the department may accept requests for funds from such organizations, departments or units which offer or propose to offer certain selected services on a demonstration or research basis or which propose services contributing to alcohol and drug dependence services, and such services may be funded in whole or in part if they meet such requirements as the department shall specify by regulation. The application for funds shall be made on forms provided by the department and shall be accompanied by (1) a definition of the area to be served; (2) a plan setting forth the means by which the applicant proposes to coordinate its activities with those of other local agencies presently supplying such services; (3) a description of the services to be provided and the methods through which such services will be provided; and (4) an indication of the methods that will be employed to effect a balance in the use of state and local resources so as to foster local initiative, responsibility and participation. Upon approval of any such application, the department shall grant such funds within available appropriations for any fiscal year. No funds authorized by this section shall be used for the construction or renovation of buildings. The department may adopt regulations, in accordance with the provisions of chapter 54, concerning minimum standards for eligibility to receive such state funds.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>