<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-682"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-682"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-682"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-682/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-682/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-682/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-682/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319j">
        <num>319j</num>
        <heading>Health Care For Uninsured Children</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_682">
          <num>17a-682</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 19a-126b). Voluntary admissions to treatment facilities operated by the department. Assistance on leaving</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_682__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An alcohol-dependent person or a drug-dependent person may apply for voluntary treatment directly to a treatment facility operated by the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services. If the proposed patient is a minor or an incompetent person, he, a parent, a legal guardian or other legal representative may make the application.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_682__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subject to regulations adopted by the department, the administrator of a treatment facility operated by the department may determine, on the advice of the medical officer of the facility, who shall be admitted for treatment. If a person is refused admission to a treatment facility operated by the department, the administrator, subject to regulations adopted by the department, shall refer the person to another treatment facility operated by the department or to a private treatment facility for treatment if possible and appropriate.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_682__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a patient receiving inpatient care leaves a treatment facility operated by the department, he shall be encouraged to consent to appropriate outpatient or intermediate treatment. If it appears to the administrator in charge of the treatment facility, on the advice of the medical officer of the facility, that the patient is an alcohol-dependent person or drug-dependent person who requires help, the department shall arrange for assistance in obtaining supportive services and residential facilities.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_682__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a patient leaves a treatment facility operated by the department, with or against the advice of the administrator of the facility, the department shall make reasonable provisions for his transportation to another facility or to his home. If he has no home, he shall be assisted in obtaining shelter. If he is a minor or an incompetent person, the request for discharge from an inpatient facility shall be made by a parent, legal guardian or other legal representative or by the minor or incompetent person if he was the original applicant.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>