<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-277"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-277"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-277"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-277/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-277/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-277/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-277/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319c">
        <num>319c</num>
        <heading>Early Childhood Programs</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_277">
          <num>17a-277</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 19a-451). Placement of persons with intellectual disability in residential facilities or residential programs</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 17a-277. (Formerly Sec. 19a-451). Placement of persons with intellectual disability in residential facilities or residential programs.A regional or training school director may place any resident with intellectual disability committed or admitted to such training school, regional facility or other residential facility provided for the care and training of persons with intellectual disability, under the provisions of sections17a-210to17a-247, inclusive, and17a-273, in a community companion home, community living arrangement, group home, other residential facility or residential program to be cared for in accordance with the following conditions:
(1) Such resident shall, despite such transfer, remain subject to the control of the regional or training school director and the director may, at any time, order and provide for the return of any such resident to such training school, regional facility or other residential facility provided for the care and training of persons with intellectual disability;
(2) When the transfer of any such resident has been authorized or when, having been transferred to a community companion home, community living arrangement, group home, other residential facility or residential program for persons with intellectual disability, such resident has returned to the training school, regional facility or other residential facility, the regional or training school director shall forthwith so notify the Commissioner of Developmental Services;
(3) Such community companion home, community living arrangement, group home, other residential facility or residential program shall be licensed or certified by the Department of Developmental Services, licensed by the Department of Children and Families or certified by the Department of Public Health under such regulations as the departments adopt, in accordance with chapter 54; and
(4) The Commissioner of Developmental Services shall, upon request, be given access to the complete record of any resident placed in a community companion home, community living arrangement, group home, other residential facility or residential program pursuant to this section.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>