<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-62"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-62"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-62"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-62/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-62/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-62/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-62/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_62">
          <num>12-62</num>
          <heading>Revaluation of real property. Regulations. Treatment of certain Indian lands</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this chapter:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Assessor” means the person responsible for establishing property assessments for purposes of a town's grand list and includes a board of assessors;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Field review” means the process by which an assessor, a member of an assessor's staff or person designated by an assessor examines each parcel of real property in its neighborhood setting, compares observable attributes to those listed on such parcel's corresponding property record, makes any necessary corrections based on such observation and verifies that such parcel's attributes are accounted for in the valuation being developed for a revaluation;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Full inspection” or “fully inspect” means to measure or verify the exterior dimensions of a building or structure and to enter and examine the interior of such building or structure in order to observe and record or verify the characteristics and conditions thereof, provided permission to enter such interior is granted by the property owner or an adult occupant;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Planning region” has the same meaning as provided in section4-124i;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_a__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Real property” means all the property described in section12-64;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_a__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Revaluation” or “revalue” means to establish the present true and actual value of all real property in a town as of a specific assessment date;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_a__subsec_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Revaluation zone” means one of five geographic areas in the state established by the secretary utilizing the boundaries of the planning regions;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_a__subsec_8">
              <num>(8)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Secretary” means the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management, or said secretary's designee; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_a__subsec_9">
              <num>(9)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“Town” means any town, consolidated town and city or consolidated town and borough.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>(A) Commencing October 1, 2006, and until September 30, 2023, each town shall implement a revaluation not later than the first day of October that follows, by five years, the October first assessment date on which the town's previous revaluation became effective, provided, a town that opted to defer a revaluation, pursuant to section12-62l, shall implement a revaluation not later than the first day of October that follows, by five years, the October first assessment date on which the town's deferred revaluation became effective. The town shall use assessments derived from each such revaluation for the purpose of levying property taxes for the assessment year in which such revaluation is effective and for each assessment year that follows until the ensuing revaluation becomes effective.
(B) Commencing October 1, 2023,</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_62__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Commencing October 1, 2006, and until September 30, 2023, each town shall implement a revaluation not later than the first day of October that follows, by five years, the October first assessment date on which the town's previous revaluation became effective, provided, a town that opted to defer a revaluation, pursuant to section12-62l, shall implement a revaluation not later than the first day of October that follows, by five years, the October first assessment date on which the town's deferred revaluation became effective. The town shall use assessments derived from each such revaluation for the purpose of levying property taxes for the assessment year in which such revaluation is effective and for each assessment year that follows until the ensuing revaluation becomes effective.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_62__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Commencing October 1, 2023,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>each town shall implement a revaluation not later than the first day of October that follows, by five years, an October first assessment date set in accordance with a revaluation date schedule prescribed by the secretary for each revaluation zone, (ii) any town's required revaluation subsequent to any delayed revaluation implemented pursuant to subparagraph (A) of this subdivision shall be implemented in accordance with this section, and (iii) any such revaluation subsequent to any delayed revaluation or revaluation implemented prior to such scheduled date shall recommence on the date set in such revaluation date schedule prescribed for the revaluation zone in which such town is located, which revaluation date schedule applied to such town prior to such delay or scheduled date. The town shall use assessments derived from each such revaluation for the purpose of levying property taxes for the assessment year in which such revaluation is effective and for each assessment year that follows until the ensuing revaluation becomes effective.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_i__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When conducting a revaluation, an assessor shall use generally accepted mass appraisal methods which may include, but need not be limited to, the market sales comparison approach to value, the cost approach to value and the income approach to value. Prior to the completion of each revaluation, the assessor shall conduct a field review. Except in a town that has a single assessor, the members of the board of assessors shall approve, by majority vote, all valuations established for a revaluation.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_i__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An assessor, member of an assessor's staff or person designated by an assessor may, at any time, fully inspect any parcel of improved real property in order to ascertain or verify the accuracy of data listed on the assessor's property record for such parcel. Except as provided in subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_i__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, the assessor shall fully inspect each such parcel once in every ten assessment years, provided, if the full inspection of any such parcel occurred in an assessment year preceding that commencing October 1, 1996, the assessor shall fully inspect such parcel not later than the first day of October of 2009, and shall thereafter fully inspect such parcel in accordance with this section. Nothing in this subsection shall require the assessor to fully inspect all of a town's improved real property parcels in the same assessment year and in no case shall an assessor be required to fully inspect any such parcel more than once during every ten assessment years.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_i__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An assessor may, at any time during the period in which a full inspection of each improved parcel of real property is required, send a questionnaire to the owner of such parcel to (A) obtain information concerning the property's acquisition, and (B) obtain verification of the accuracy of data listed on the assessor's property record for such parcel. An assessor shall develop and institute a quality assurance program with respect to responses received to such questionnaires. If satisfied with the results of said program concerning such questionnaires, the assessor may fully inspect only those parcels of improved real property for which satisfactory verification of data listed on the assessor's property record has not been obtained and is otherwise unavailable. The full inspection requirement in subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_62__subsec_i__subsec_4__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>obtain information concerning the property's acquisition, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_62__subsec_i__subsec_4__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>obtain verification of the accuracy of data listed on the assessor's property record for such parcel. An assessor shall develop and institute a quality assurance program with respect to responses received to such questionnaires. If satisfied with the results of said program concerning such questionnaires, the assessor may fully inspect only those parcels of improved real property for which satisfactory verification of data listed on the assessor's property record has not been obtained and is otherwise unavailable. The full inspection requirement in subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_i__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection shall not apply to any parcel of improved real property for which the assessor obtains satisfactory verification of data listed on the assessor's property record.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The following shall be available for public inspection in the assessor's office, in the manner provided for access to public records in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section1-210, not later than the date written notices of real property valuations are mailed in accordance with subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_f__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any criteria, guidelines, price schedules or statement of procedures used in such revaluation by the assessor or by any revaluation company that the assessor designates to perform mass appraisal or field review functions, all of which shall continue to be available for public inspection until the town's next revaluation becomes effective; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_f__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a compilation of all real property sales in each neighborhood for the twelve months preceding the date on which each revaluation is effective, the selling prices of which are representative of the fair market values of the properties sold, which compilation shall continue to be available for public inspection for a period of not less than twelve months immediately following a revaluation's effective date. If the assessor changes any property valuation as determined by the revaluation company, the assessor shall document, in writing, the reason for such change and shall append such written explanation to the property card for the real estate parcel whose revaluation was changed. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to permit the assessor to post a plan or drawing of a dwelling unit of a residential property's interior on the Internet or to otherwise publish such plan or drawing.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The chief executive officer of a town shall notify the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management that the town is effecting a revaluation by sending a written notice to the secretary not later than thirty days after the date on which such town's assessor signs a grand list that reflects assessments of real property derived from a revaluation. Any town that fails to effect a revaluation for the assessment date required by this section shall be subject to a penalty effective for the fiscal year commencing on the first day of July following such assessment date, and continuing for each successive fiscal year in which the town fails to levy taxes on the basis of such revaluation, provided the secretary shall not impose such penalty with respect to any assessment year in which the provisions of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-117are applicable. Such penalty shall be the forfeit of the amount otherwise allocable to such town pursuant to section7-536, and the loss of fifty per cent of the amount of the grant that is payable to such town pursuant to sections3-55i,3-55jand3-55k. Upon imposing said penalty, the secretary shall notify the chief executive officer of the amount of the town's forfeiture for said fiscal year and that the secretary's certification to the State Comptroller for the payments of such grant in said year shall reflect the required reduction.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The secretary may waive such penalty if, in the secretary's opinion, there appears to be reasonable cause for the town not having implemented a revaluation for the required assessment date, provided the chief executive officer of the town submits a written request for such waiver. Reasonable cause shall include: (A) An extraordinary circumstance or an act of God, (B) the failure on the part of any revaluation company to complete its contractual duties in a time and manner allowing for the implementation of such revaluation, and provided the town imposed the sanctions for such failure provided in a contract executed with said company, (C) the assessor's death or incapacitation during the conduct of a revaluation, which results in a delay of its implementation, or (D) an order by the superior court for the judicial district in which the town is located postponing such revaluation, or the potential for such an order with respect to a proceeding brought before said court. The chief executive officer shall submit such written request to the secretary not earlier than thirty business days after the date on which the assessor signs a grand list that does not reflect real property assessments based on values established for such required revaluation, and not later than thirty days preceding the July first commencement date of the fiscal year in which said penalty is applicable. Such request shall include the reason for the failure of the town to comply with the provisions of subsection</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_62__subsec_b__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>An extraordinary circumstance or an act of God,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_62__subsec_b__subsec_2__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the failure on the part of any revaluation company to complete its contractual duties in a time and manner allowing for the implementation of such revaluation, and provided the town imposed the sanctions for such failure provided in a contract executed with said company,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_62__subsec_b__subsec_2__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the assessor's death or incapacitation during the conduct of a revaluation, which results in a delay of its implementation, or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_62__subsec_b__subsec_2__subsec_D">
                <num>(D)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>an order by the superior court for the judicial district in which the town is located postponing such revaluation, or the potential for such an order with respect to a proceeding brought before said court. The chief executive officer shall submit such written request to the secretary not earlier than thirty business days after the date on which the assessor signs a grand list that does not reflect real property assessments based on values established for such required revaluation, and not later than thirty days preceding the July first commencement date of the fiscal year in which said penalty is applicable. Such request shall include the reason for the failure of the town to comply with the provisions of subsection</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section. The chief executive officer of such town shall promptly provide any additional information regarding such failure that the secretary may require. Not later than sixty days after receiving such request and any such additional information, the secretary shall notify the chief executive officer of the secretary's decision to grant or deny the waiver requested, provided the secretary may delay a decision regarding a waiver related to a potential court order until not later than sixty days after the date such court renders the decision. The secretary shall not grant a penalty waiver under the provisions of this subsection with respect to consecutive years unless the General Assembly approves such action.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When conducting a revaluation, an assessor may designate a revaluation company certified in accordance with section12-2bto perform parcel data collection, analysis of such data and any mass appraisal valuation or field review functions, pursuant to a method or methods the assessor approves, and may require such company to prepare and mail the valuation notices required by subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, provided nothing in this subsection shall relieve any assessor of any other requirement relating to such revaluation imposed by any provisions of the general statutes, any public or special act, the provisions of any municipal charter that are not inconsistent with the requirements of this section, or any regulations adopted pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Not earlier than the assessment date that is the effective date of a revaluation and not later than the tenth calendar day immediately following the date on which the grand list for said assessment date is signed, the assessor shall mail a written notice to the last-known address of the owner of each parcel of real property that was revalued. Such notice shall include the valuation of such parcel as of said assessment date and the valuation of such parcel in the last-preceding assessment year, and shall provide information describing the property owner's rights to appeal the valuation established for said assessment date, including the manner in which an appeal may be filed with the board of assessment appeals.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_g">
            <num>(g)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The secretary shall adopt regulations, in accordance with the provisions of chapter 54, which an assessor shall use when conducting a revaluation. Such regulations shall include</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_g__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>provisions governing the management of the revaluation process, including, but not limited to, the method of compiling and maintaining property records, documenting the assessment year during which a full inspection of each parcel of improved real property occurs, and the method of determining real property sales data in support of the mass appraisal process, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_g__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>provisions establishing criteria for measuring the level and uniformity of assessments generated from a revaluation, provided such criteria shall be applicable to different classes of real property with respect to which a sufficient number of property sales exist. Certification of compliance with not less than one of said regulatory provisions shall be required for each revaluation and the assessor shall, not later than the date on which the grand list reflecting assessments of real property derived from a revaluation is signed, certify to the secretary and the chief executive officer, in writing, that the revaluation was conducted in accordance with said regulatory requirement. Any town effecting a revaluation with respect to which an assessor is unable to certify such compliance shall be subject to the penalty provided in subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section. In the event the assessor designates a revaluation company to perform mass appraisal valuation or field review functions with respect to a revaluation, the assessor and the employee of said company responsible for such function or functions shall jointly sign such certification. The assessor shall retain a copy of such certification and any data in support thereof in the assessor's office. The provisions of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section concerning the public inspection of criteria, guidelines, price schedules or statement of procedures used in a revaluation shall be applicable to such certification and supporting data.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_h">
            <num>(h)</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section shall require the revaluation of real property</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_h__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>designated within the 1983 Settlement boundary and taken into trust by the federal government for the Mashantucket Pequot Tribal Nation before June 8, 1999, or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_62__subsec_h__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>taken into trust by the federal government for the Mohegan Tribe of Indians of Connecticut.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each assessor shall file with the secretary parcel data from each revaluation implemented pursuant to this section upon forms prescribed and furnished by the secretary, which forms shall be so prescribed and furnished not later than thirty days prior to the date set by such secretary for such filing.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>