<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-120"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-120"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-120"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_120">
          <num>12-120</num>
          <heading>Assessor or board of assessors to send abstract of assessment lists to Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-120. Assessor or board of assessors to send abstract of assessment lists to Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management.The assessor or board of assessors of each town, after the assessment lists have been examined and corrected by the board of assessment appeals, shall, on or before the first day of May, annually, transmit to the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management an abstract of such lists, including the twenty-five per cent added by the assessor, board of assessors or board of assessment appeals, made in accordance with forms which shall be furnished by the secretary, at least thirty days before the date on which they are to be filed. Such form shall be designed to reduce paperwork requirements for the assessor or board of assessors. Prior to such transmittal and the making of such abstract, the assessor or board of assessors shall correct any clerical error which appears upon any such corrected assessment list. Any assessor who or board of assessors which neglects to transmit to the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management an abstract of assessment lists as required by this section shall forfeit one hundred dollars to the state, provided the secretary may waive such forfeiture in accordance with procedures and standards adopted by regulation in accordance with chapter 54.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>