<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-81mm"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-81mm"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-81mm"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-81mm/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-81mm/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-81mm/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-81mm/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_81mm">
          <num>12-81mm</num>
          <heading>Municipal option to abate property taxes on recreational trails</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_81mm__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of this section,</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_81mm__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“nonprofit land conservation organization” means a nonprofit land conservation organization that is tax exempt under Section 501</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_81mm__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_81mm__subsec_c__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or any subsequent corresponding internal revenue code of the United States, as amended from time to time,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_81mm__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“greenway” has the same meaning as provided in section23-100, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_81mm__subsec_c__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“conservation restriction” has the same meaning as provided in section47-42a.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_81mm__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each municipality may establish by ordinance a program to provide for the abatement of real property taxes due on any portion of land that</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_81mm__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>meets the criteria for designation as a greenway established under subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_81mm__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section23-102,</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_81mm__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>is a terrestrial recreational trail with a clearly defined trail corridor that does not exceed one hundred feet in width at its widest point, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_81mm__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>is subject to a recorded permanent conservation restriction conveyed by the owner of the land, or such owner's predecessor in title, to the municipality, the state or a nonprofit land conservation organization, provided such conservation easement or any other encumbrance on the land shall not prohibit the public use of any such terrestrial recreational trail for compatible recreation.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_81mm__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whenever any municipality enacts an ordinance required by subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_81mm__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, an owner of land may apply for its abatement under such ordinance by filing a written application for such abatement with the assessor of such municipality. Any application filed under this subsection shall be made upon a form prescribed by the assessor and shall include</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_81mm__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a description of the land,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_81mm__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a copy of the recorded permanent conservation restriction concerning the land,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_81mm__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a copy of the deed that establishes such owner's ownership interest in the land,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_81mm__subsec_b__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a certified land survey that depicts the boundaries of the terrestrial recreational trail on the land of such owner, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_81mm__subsec_b__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>such other information as the assessor may require to aid in determining whether such land qualifies for such tax abatement pursuant to such ordinance. Any certification of a survey required by this subsection shall be made by a licensed surveyor and such certification shall be made in accordance with chapter 390.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_81mm__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Not later than thirty days after receipt of a written application under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_81mm__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section, the assessor shall submit such written application with the assessor's recommendation to either approve or deny the tax abatement based on the criteria set forth in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_81mm__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section to the legislative body of the municipality or, in a municipality where the legislative body is a town meeting, to the board of selectmen.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_81mm__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The abatement of any real property taxes under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_81mm__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section shall be approved by vote of the legislative body of the municipality or, in a municipality where the legislative body is a town meeting, by vote of the board of selectmen.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_81mm__subsec_f">
            <num>(f)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any abatement under this section shall continue upon the sale or transfer of the land unless the legislative body of the municipality, or in a municipality where the legislative body is a town meeting, the board of selectmen, votes to discontinue such abatement.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>