<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-81r"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-81r"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-81r"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-81r/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-81r/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-81r/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-81r/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_81r">
          <num>12-81r</num>
          <heading>Municipal option to abate or forgive taxes or fix assessment on contaminated real property</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_81r__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any municipality may</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_81r__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>enter into an agreement with the owner or prospective owner of any real property to abate the property tax due as of the date of the agreement for a period not to exceed seven years if the property has been subject to a spill, as defined in section22a-452c, and the owner or prospective owner agrees to conduct any environmental site assessment, demolition and remediation of the spill necessary to redevelop the property. Any such tax abatement shall only be for the period of remediation and redevelopment and shall be contingent upon the continuation and completion of the remediation and redevelopment process with respect to the purposes specified in the agreement. The abatement shall cease upon the sale or transfer of the property for any other purpose unless the municipality consents to its continuation. The municipality may also establish a recapture provision in the event of sale provided such recapture shall not exceed the original amount of taxes abated and may not go back further than the date of the agreement;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_81r__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>enter into an agreement with a prospective owner of any real property that is a brownfield, as defined in section32-760, or deemed by the municipality to be abandoned, to forgive all or a portion of the principal balance and interest due on delinquent property taxes for the benefit of such prospective owner, provided such prospective owner has agreed to (A) enter into a program for the remediation of the property pursuant to section22a-133x,22a-133y,32-768or32-769, or (B) complete the investigation and remediation of the property in accordance with section22a-134a;</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_81r__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>enter into a program for the remediation of the property pursuant to section22a-133x,22a-133y,32-768or32-769, or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_81r__subsec_a__subsec_2__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>complete the investigation and remediation of the property in accordance with section22a-134a;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_81r__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>enter into an agreement with the owner or prospective owner of any real property to fix the assessment of the property as of the last assessment date prior to commencement of remediation activities for a period not to exceed seven years, provided the owner or prospective owner has agreed to (A) enter into a program for remediation of the property pursuant to section22a-133x,22a-133y,32-768or32-769, or (B) complete the investigation and remediation of the property in accordance with section22a-134a; or</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_81r__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>enter into a program for remediation of the property pursuant to section22a-133x,22a-133y,32-768or32-769, or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_81r__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>complete the investigation and remediation of the property in accordance with section22a-134a; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_81r__subsec_a__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>forgive all or a portion of the principal balance and interest due on delinquent property taxes for the benefit of any Connecticut brownfield land bank, as defined in section32-760, that has acquired or will acquire any real property within the municipality.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_81r__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any abatement or forgiveness of taxes or fixed assessment or any combination thereof under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_81r__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section shall be approved by vote of the board of finance, if applicable, and the legislative body of the municipality, or by vote of the board of finance, if applicable, and the board of selectmen in a municipality where the legislative body is a town meeting and contingent upon any other conditions deemed appropriate by such body.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_81r__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A municipality shall notify the Commissioner of Energy and Environmental Protection, the Commissioner of Economic and Community Development and the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management not later than thirty days after granting any abatement or forgiveness of taxes or any fixed assessment under subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_81r__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section. Such notice shall provide the owner's or purchaser's name, as the case may be, and the address of the property.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>