<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-107g"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-107g"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-107g"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-107g/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-107g/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-107g/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-107g/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_107g">
          <num>12-107g</num>
          <heading>Classification of land as marine heritage land</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_107g__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An owner of land may apply for its classification as maritime heritage land, as defined in section12-107b, on any grand list of a municipality by filing a written application for such classification with the assessor thereof not earlier than thirty days before or later than thirty days after the assessment date, provided in a year in which a revaluation of all real property in accordance with section12-62becomes effective such application may be filed not later than ninety days after such assessment date. The assessor shall determine whether such land is maritime heritage land and, if such assessor determines that it is maritime heritage land, he or she shall classify and include it as such on the grand list.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_107g__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An application for classification of land as maritime heritage land shall be made upon a form prescribed by the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management and shall set forth a description of the land, a general description of the use to which it is being put, a statement of the potential liability for tax under the provisions of sections12-504ato12-504f, inclusive, and such other information as the assessor may require to aid the assessor in determining whether such land qualifies for such classification.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_107g__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Failure to file an application for classification of land as maritime heritage land within the time limit prescribed in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_107g__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section and in the manner and form prescribed in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_107g__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section shall be considered a waiver of the right to such classification on such assessment list.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_107g__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person aggrieved by the denial of any application for the classification of land as maritime heritage land shall have the same rights and remedies for appeal and relief as are provided in the general statutes for taxpayers claiming to be aggrieved by the doings of assessors or boards of assessment appeals.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>