<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-54"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-54"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-54"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-54/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-54/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-54/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-54/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_54">
          <num>12-54</num>
          <heading>Examination by assessors when declaration not filed</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 12-54. Examination by assessors when declaration not filed.Each person liable to give in a declaration of such person's taxable tangible personal property and failing to do so may, within sixty days after the expiration of the time fixed by law for filing such declaration, be notified in writing by the assessor or a majority of the board of assessors to appear before them to be examined under oath as to such person's property liable to taxation and for the purpose of verifying a declaration made out by them under the provisions of section12-41. Any person who wilfully neglects or refuses to appear before the assessors and make oath as to such person's taxable property within ten days after having been so notified or who, having appeared, refuses to answer shall be fined not more than one thousand dollars. The assessors shall promptly notify the proper prosecuting officers of any violation of any provision of this section. Nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude the assessor from performing an audit of such person's taxable personal property, as provided in section12-53.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>