<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-62x"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-62x"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-62x"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-62x/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-62x/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-62x/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-62x/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_203">
        <num>203</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Assessment</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_62x">
          <num>12-62x</num>
          <heading>Optional regional property tax base revenue sharing: Administrative auditor</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_62x__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On or before August 1, 2016, and each even-numbered year thereafter, the regional council of governments for each planning region participating in the regional property tax base revenue sharing system shall meet and elect from among their number one member to serve as administrative auditor for a period of two years and until a successor is elected. If a majority is unable to agree upon a person to serve as administrative auditor, the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management shall appoint one member from among the council's members. If the administrative auditor ceases to serve as a member within the planning region during the term for which elected or appointed, a successor shall be chosen in the same manner as provided in this subsection for the original selection, to serve for the unexpired term.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_62x__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <heading>The administrative auditor shall utilize the staff and facilities of the planning region</heading>
            <content>
              <p>The planning region shall be reimbursed for the marginal expenses incurred by its staff by contribution from each other municipality in the planning region in an amount which bears the same proportion of the total expenses as the population of such municipality bears to the total population of the planning region. The administrative auditor shall annually, on or before February first, certify the amount of total expenses for the preceding calendar year, and the share of each municipality, to the treasurer or other fiscal officer of each municipality within the planning region. Payment shall be made by the treasurer or other fiscal officer of each municipality to the treasurer or other fiscal officer of the planning region on or before the succeeding March first.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>