<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-753"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-753"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-753"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-753/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-753/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-753/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-753/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319k">
        <num>319k</num>
        <heading>Connecticut Home Care Program for Elders</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_753">
          <num>17a-753</num>
          <heading>Five-year strategic plan</heading>
          <subsection eId="17a_753__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On or before October 1, 1998, the regional negotiating council shall develop a five-year strategic plan that addresses the human services needs of the northeastern region. Such plan shall be submitted to the legislative body of each town constituting the northeastern region, the United States Congress, the Secretary of the Office of Policy and Management and the joint standing committee of the General Assembly having cognizance of matters relating to appropriations.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_753__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The five-year strategic plan shall be developed by means of a negotiated investment strategy and shall set forth goals to meet basic human needs for the northeastern region and establish benchmarks to measure progress towards achieving such goals. The plan shall identify regional issues and needs and resources and address efficiency and effectiveness of service delivery. The plan shall be consistent with the planning and policy objectives of the state that are implemented in the state budget and shall comply with state and federal law. The plan shall include a project component relating specific regional and local proposals to state planning goals and a component which describes the administration and fund distribution process. The project component shall be updated annually. The plan shall include a description of the planning process used to identify needs and set priorities for the region, a description of the programs to be funded, a description of any eligibility standards to be used, an implementation schedule and a budget detailing the specific use of funds available under the regional human services pilot program and related funds. The plan shall identify opportunities for state agencies to award grants on a regional basis and shall identify state, local and federal funding sources and make recommendations for legislation to implement the plan for the biennium beginning July 1, 1999. The plan shall include an analysis of the fiscal and administrative impact on the state and municipalities outside of the pilot region. If the plan recommends continuation of the negotiating council, the negotiating council shall continue.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17a_753__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The five-year plan developed under this section shall not impact existing state, local or federal funds received by human service providers or the existing programs of northeastern region human service providers. Any realignment of existing human service programs shall be done by an affirmative action of the governing body of the program and be consistent with the five-year strategic plan.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>