<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-39dd"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-39dd"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-39dd"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-39dd/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-39dd/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-39dd/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-39dd/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_202">
        <num>202</num>
        <heading>Collection of State Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_39dd">
          <num>12-39dd</num>
          <heading>Duplicate information returns required to be filed by reporting entities. Penalties</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_39dd__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For purposes of this section,</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_39dd__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“payment settlement entity”, “third party settlement organization” and “electronic payment facilitator” have the same meanings as provided in Section 6050W of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or any subsequent corresponding internal revenue code of the United States, as amended from time to time, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_39dd__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>“reporting entity” means any payment settlement entity, third party settlement organization, electronic payment facilitator or other third party acting on behalf of a payment settlement entity, that processes reportable payment transactions with respect to a participating payee located in Connecticut.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_39dd__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_39dd__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Each reporting entity shall file with the Department of Revenue Services, not later than thirty days after the reporting entity files information returns with the Internal Revenue Service, a duplicate of all such information returns, in such form and manner as prescribed by the commissioner.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_39dd__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any reporting entity that fails to file a duplicate information return required under subdivision</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_39dd__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection within the time prescribed shall be subject to a civil penalty of (A) fifty dollars for each such failure if the failure is for not more than one month after such duplicate was required to be filed, and (B) an additional fifty dollars for each month or fraction thereof during which such failure continues, except the total amount of the penalty imposed on a reporting entity under this subdivision shall not exceed two hundred fifty thousand dollars annually. Subject to the provisions of section12-3a, the commissioner may waive all or part of the penalties provided under this subdivision when it is proven to the commissioner's satisfaction that the failure to timely file such duplicate was due to reasonable cause and was not due to wilful neglect.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_39dd__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>fifty dollars for each such failure if the failure is for not more than one month after such duplicate was required to be filed, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_39dd__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>an additional fifty dollars for each month or fraction thereof during which such failure continues, except the total amount of the penalty imposed on a reporting entity under this subdivision shall not exceed two hundred fifty thousand dollars annually. Subject to the provisions of section12-3a, the commissioner may waive all or part of the penalties provided under this subdivision when it is proven to the commissioner's satisfaction that the failure to timely file such duplicate was due to reasonable cause and was not due to wilful neglect.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>