<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-392"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-392"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-392"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-392/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-392/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-392/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-392/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_217">
        <num>217</num>
        <heading>Admissions and Dues Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_392">
          <num>12-392</num>
          <heading>Payment of tax. Penalties for late filing. Extension of time. Interest on overpayment. Method of filing. Notice to court of probate</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_392__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For the estates of decedents dying prior to July 1, 2009, the tax imposed by this chapter shall become due at the date of the taxable transfer and shall become payable, and shall be paid, without assessment, notice or demand, to the Commissioner of Revenue Services at the expiration of nine months from the date of death. For the estates of decedents dying on or after July 1, 2009, the tax imposed by this chapter shall become due at the date of the taxable transfer and shall become payable and shall be paid, without assessment, notice or demand, to the commissioner at the expiration of six months from the date of death. Executors, administrators, trustees, grantees, donees, beneficiaries and surviving joint owners shall be liable for the tax and for any interest or penalty thereon until it is paid, notwithstanding any provision of chapter 802b, except that no executor, administrator, trustee, grantee, donee, beneficiary or surviving joint owner shall be liable for a greater sum than the value of the property actually received by him or her. If the amount of tax reported to be due on the return is not paid, for the estates of decedents dying prior to July 1, 2009, within such nine months, or for the estates of decedents dying on or after July 1, 2009, within such six months, there shall be imposed a penalty equal to ten per cent of such amount due and unpaid, or fifty dollars, whichever is greater. Such amount shall bear interest at the rate of one per cent per month or fraction thereof from the due date of such tax until the date of payment. Subject to the provisions of section12-3a, the commissioner may waive all or part of the penalties provided under this chapter when it is proven to the commissioner's satisfaction that the failure to pay any tax was due to reasonable cause and was not intentional or due to neglect.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_392__subsec_a__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Commissioner of Revenue Services may, for reasonable cause shown, extend the time for payment. The commissioner may require the filing of a tentative return and the payment of the tax reported to be due thereon in connection with such extension. Any additional tax which may be found to be due on the filing of a return as allowed by such extension shall bear interest at the rate of one per cent per month or fraction thereof from the original due date of such tax to the date of actual payment.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_392__subsec_a__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>(A) Whenever there is a claimed overpayment of the tax imposed by this chapter, the Commissioner of Revenue Services shall return to the fiduciary or transferee the overpayment which shall bear interest at the rate of two-thirds of one per cent per month or fraction thereof, such interest commencing, for the estates of decedents dying prior to July 1, 2009, from the expiration of nine months after the death of the transferor or date of payment, whichever is later, or, for the estates of decedents dying on or after July 1, 2009, from the expiration of six months after the death of the transferor or date of payment, whichever is later, as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C) of this subdivision.
(B) In case of such overpayment pursuant to a tax return, no interest shall be allowed or paid under this subdivision on such overpayment for any month or fraction thereof prior to</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_392__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Whenever there is a claimed overpayment of the tax imposed by this chapter, the Commissioner of Revenue Services shall return to the fiduciary or transferee the overpayment which shall bear interest at the rate of two-thirds of one per cent per month or fraction thereof, such interest commencing, for the estates of decedents dying prior to July 1, 2009, from the expiration of nine months after the death of the transferor or date of payment, whichever is later, or, for the estates of decedents dying on or after July 1, 2009, from the expiration of six months after the death of the transferor or date of payment, whichever is later, as provided in subparagraphs</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_392__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_392__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of this subdivision.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_392__subsec_a__subsec_3__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In case of such overpayment pursuant to a tax return, no interest shall be allowed or paid under this subdivision on such overpayment for any month or fraction thereof prior to</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the ninety-first day after the last day prescribed for filing the tax return associated with such overpayment, determined without regard to any extension of time for filing, or (ii) the ninety-first day after the date such return was filed, whichever is later.
(C) In case of such overpayment pursuant to an amended tax return, no interest shall be allowed or paid under this subdivision on such overpayment for any month or fraction thereof prior to the ninety-first day after the date such amended tax return was filed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <paragraph eId="12_392__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The tax imposed by this chapter shall be reported on a tax return which shall be filed on or before the date fixed for paying the tax, determined without regard to any extension of time for paying the tax. The commissioner shall design a form of return and forms for such additional statements or schedules as the commissioner may require to be filed. Such forms shall provide for the setting forth of such facts as the commissioner deems necessary for the proper enforcement of this chapter. The commissioner shall furnish appropriate forms to each taxpayer upon application or otherwise as the commissioner deems necessary. Failure to receive a form shall not relieve any person from the obligation to file a return under the provisions of this chapter. In any case in which the commissioner believes that it would be advantageous to him or her in the administration of the tax imposed by this chapter, the commissioner may require that a true copy of the federal estate tax return made to the Internal Revenue Service be provided.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_392__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any tax return or other document, including any amended tax return under section12-398, that is required to be filed under this chapter shall be filed, and shall be treated as filed, only if filed with (A) the Commissioner of Revenue Services, if required under subdivision</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_392__subsec_b__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the Commissioner of Revenue Services, if required under subdivision</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_392__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, and (B)</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_392__subsec_b__subsec_3__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death, or, (ii) if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, in the court of probate for the district within which real estate or tangible personal property of the decedent is situated. The return shall contain a statement, to be signed under penalty of false statement by the person who is required to make and file the return under this chapter, that the return has been filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services, if required under subdivision</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_392__subsec_i__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of this subsection, and the appropriate court of probate.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_392__subsec_i__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>(A) A tax return shall be filed, in the case of every decedent who died prior to January 1, 2005, and at the time of death was</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_392__subsec_i__subsec_3__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A tax return shall be filed, in the case of every decedent who died prior to January 1, 2005, and at the time of death was</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a resident of this state, or (ii) a nonresident of this state whose gross estate includes any real property situated in this state or tangible personal property having an actual situs in this state, whenever the personal representative of the estate is required by the laws of the United States to file a federal estate tax return.
(B) A tax return shall be filed, in the case of every decedent who dies on or after January 1, 2005, but prior to January 1, 2010, and at the time of death was</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a resident of this state, or (ii) a nonresident of this state whose gross estate includes any real property situated in this state or tangible personal property having an actual situs in this state. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is over two million dollars, such tax return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services and a copy of such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is two million dollars or less, such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated, and no such return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services. The judge of probate for the district in which such return is filed shall review each such return and shall issue a written opinion to the estate representative in each case in which the judge determines that the estate is not subject to tax under this chapter.
(C) A tax return shall be filed, in the case of every decedent who dies on or after January 1, 2010, but prior to January 1, 2011, and at the time of death was</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a resident of this state, or (ii) a nonresident of this state whose gross estate includes any real property situated in this state or tangible personal property having an actual situs in this state. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is over three million five hundred thousand dollars, such tax return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services and a copy of such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is three million five hundred thousand dollars or less, such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated, and no such return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services. The judge of probate for the district in which such return is filed shall review each such return and shall issue a written opinion to the estate representative in each case in which the judge determines that the estate is not subject to tax under this chapter.
(D) A tax return shall be filed, in the case of every decedent who dies on or after January 1, 2011, but prior to January 1, 2018, and at the time of death was</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a resident of this state, or (ii) a nonresident of this state whose gross estate includes any real property situated in this state or tangible personal property having an actual situs in this state. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is over two million dollars, such tax return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services and a copy of such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is two million dollars or less, such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated, and no such return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services. The judge of probate for the district in which such return is filed shall review each such return and shall issue a written opinion to the estate representative in each case in which the judge determines that the estate is not subject to tax under this chapter.
(E) A tax return shall be filed, in the case of every decedent who dies on or after January 1, 2018, but prior to January 1, 2019, and at the time of death was</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a resident of this state, or (ii) a nonresident of this state whose gross estate includes any real property situated in this state or tangible personal property having an actual situs in this state. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is over two million six hundred thousand dollars, such tax return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services and a copy of such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is two million six hundred thousand dollars or less, such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated, and no such return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services. The judge of probate for the district in which such return is filed shall review each such return and shall issue a written opinion to the estate representative in each case in which the judge determines that the estate is not subject to tax under this chapter.
(F) A tax return shall be filed, in the case of every decedent who dies on or after January 1, 2019, but prior to January 1, 2020, and at the time of death was</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a resident of this state, or (ii) a nonresident of this state whose gross estate includes any real property situated in this state or tangible personal property having an actual situs in this state. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is over three million six hundred thousand dollars, such tax return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services and a copy of such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is three million six hundred thousand dollars or less, such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated, and no such return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services. The judge of probate for the district in which such return is filed shall review each such return and shall issue a written opinion to the estate representative in each case in which the judge determines that the estate is not subject to tax under this chapter.
(G) A tax return shall be filed, in the case of every decedent who dies on or after January 1, 2020, but prior to January 1, 2021, and at the time of death was</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a resident of this state, or (ii) a nonresident of this state whose gross estate includes any real property situated in this state or tangible personal property having an actual situs in this state. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is over five million one hundred thousand dollars, such tax return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services and a copy of such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is five million one hundred thousand dollars or less, such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated, and no such return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services. The judge of probate for the district in which such return is filed shall review each such return and shall issue a written opinion to the estate representative in each case in which the judge determines that the estate is not subject to tax under this chapter.
(H) A tax return shall be filed, in the case of every decedent who dies on or after January 1, 2021, but prior to January 1, 2022, and at the time of death was</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a resident of this state, or (ii) a nonresident of this state whose gross estate includes any real property situated in this state or tangible personal property having an actual situs in this state. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is over seven million one hundred thousand dollars, such tax return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services and a copy of such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is seven million one hundred thousand dollars or less, such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated, and no such return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services. The judge of probate for the district in which such return is filed shall review each such return and shall issue a written opinion to the estate representative in each case in which the judge determines that the estate is not subject to tax under this chapter.
(I) A tax return shall be filed, in the case of every decedent who dies on or after January 1, 2022, but prior to January 1, 2023, and at the time of death was</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a resident of this state, or (ii) a nonresident of this state whose gross estate includes any real property situated in this state or tangible personal property having an actual situs in this state. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is over nine million one hundred thousand dollars, such tax return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services and a copy of such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is nine million one hundred thousand dollars or less, such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated, and no such return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services. The judge of probate for the district in which such return is filed shall review each such return and shall issue a written opinion to the estate representative in each case in which the judge determines that the estate is not subject to tax under this chapter.
(J) A tax return shall be filed, in the case of every decedent who dies on or after January 1, 2023, and at the time of death was</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_i">
            <num>(i)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a resident of this state, or (ii) a nonresident of this state whose gross estate includes any real property situated in this state or tangible personal property having an actual situs in this state. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is over the federal basic exclusion amount, such tax return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services and a copy of such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated. If the decedent's Connecticut taxable estate is equal to or less than the federal basic exclusion amount, such return shall be filed with the court of probate for the district within which the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, the court of probate for the district within which such real property or tangible personal property is situated, and no such return shall be filed with the Commissioner of Revenue Services. The judge of probate for the district in which such return is filed shall review each such return and shall issue a written opinion to the estate representative in each case in which the judge determines that the estate is not subject to tax under this chapter.</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_392__subsec_i__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The duly authorized executor or administrator shall file the return. If there is more than one executor or administrator, the return shall be made jointly by all. If there is no executor or administrator appointed, qualified and acting, each person in actual or constructive possession of any property of the decedent is constituted an executor for purposes of the tax and shall make and file a return. If in any case the executor is unable to make a complete return as to any part of the gross estate, the executor shall provide all the information available to him or her with respect to such property, including a full description, and the name of every person holding a legal or beneficial interest in the property. If the executor is unable to make a return as to any property, each person holding a legal or equitable interest in such property shall, upon notice from the commissioner, make a return as to that part of the gross estate.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_392__subsec_i__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>On or before the last day of the month next succeeding each calendar quarter, and commencing with the calendar quarter ending September 30, 2005, each court of probate shall file with the commissioner a report for the calendar quarter in such form as the commissioner may prescribe. The report shall pertain to returns filed with the court of probate during the calendar quarter.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_392__subsec_i__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Commissioner of Revenue Services may, for reasonable cause shown, extend the time for filing the return.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_392__subsec_i__subsec_7">
              <num>(7)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If any person required to make and file the tax return under this chapter fails to file the return within the time prescribed, the commissioner may assess and compute the tax upon the best information obtainable. To the tax imposed upon the basis of such return, there shall be added an amount equal to ten per cent of such tax or fifty dollars, whichever is greater. The tax shall bear interest at the rate of one per cent per month or fraction thereof from the due date of such tax until the date of payment.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_392__subsec_i__subsec_8">
              <num>(8)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commissioner shall provide notice of any (A) deficiency assessment with respect to the payment of any tax under this chapter, (B) assessment with respect to any failure to make and file a return under this chapter by a person required to file, and (C) tax return or other document, including any amended tax return under section12-398that is required to be filed under this chapter to the court of probate for the district within which the commissioner contends that the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, to the court of probate for the district within which the commissioner contends that real estate or tangible personal property of the decedent is situated.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_392__subsec_i__subsec_8__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>deficiency assessment with respect to the payment of any tax under this chapter,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_392__subsec_i__subsec_8__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>assessment with respect to any failure to make and file a return under this chapter by a person required to file, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_392__subsec_i__subsec_8__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>tax return or other document, including any amended tax return under section12-398that is required to be filed under this chapter to the court of probate for the district within which the commissioner contends that the decedent resided at the date of his or her death or, if the decedent died a nonresident of this state, to the court of probate for the district within which the commissioner contends that real estate or tangible personal property of the decedent is situated.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No person shall be subject to a penalty under both subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_392__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section in relation to the same tax period.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>