<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-28e"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-28e"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-28e"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-28e/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-28e/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-28e/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-28e/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319o">
        <num>319o</num>
        <heading>Personal Care Assistance</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_28e">
          <num>17b-28e</num>
          <heading>Amendment to Medicaid state plan re hospice, podiatry and independent behavioral health clinician services</heading>
          <subsection eId="17b_28e__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner of Social Services shall amend the Medicaid state plan to include, on and after January 1, 2009, hospice services as optional services covered under the Medicaid program. Said state plan amendment shall supersede any regulations of Connecticut state agencies concerning such optional services. Hospice services covered under the Medicaid program for individuals who are residents in long-term care facilities shall be paid at a rate that is ninety-five per cent of the facility's per diem rate.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_28e__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Not later than October 1, 2011, the Commissioner of Social Services shall amend the Medicaid state plan to include podiatry as an optional service under the Medicaid program.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_28e__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Not later than October 1, 2014, the Commissioner of Social Services shall amend the Medicaid state plan to include services provided by the following licensed behavioral health clinicians in independent practice to Medicaid recipients who are twenty-one years of age or older:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28e__subsec_c__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Psychologists licensed under chapter 383,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28e__subsec_c__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>clinical social workers licensed under subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_28e__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_28e__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section20-195n,</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28e__subsec_e__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>alcohol and drug counselors licensed under section20-74s,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28e__subsec_e__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>professional counselors licensed under sections20-195ccand20-195dd, and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28e__subsec_e__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>marital and family therapists licensed under section20-195c. The commissioner shall include such services as optional services covered under the Medicaid program and provide direct Medicaid reimbursements to such licensed behavioral health clinicians who are enrolled as Medicaid providers and who treat such Medicaid recipients in independent practice settings. The commissioner may implement policies and procedures necessary to implement this subsection in advance of regulations, provided the commissioner prints notice of intent to adopt the regulations in accordance with section17b-10not later than twenty days after the date of implementation of such policies and procedures. Such policies and procedures shall be valid until the time final regulations are adopted.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_28e__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28e__subsec_d__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Not later than October 1, 2022, the Commissioner of Social Services shall provide Medicaid payments to an enrolled independent licensed behavioral health clinician in private practice for covered services performed by an associate licensed behavioral health clinician working within such associate clinician's scope of practice under the supervision of such independent clinician, provided such independent clinician is (A) authorized under state law to supervise such associate clinician, and (B) complies with any supervision and documentation requirements required by law. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to alter any requirement concerning such services, including, but not limited to, scope of practice, supervision and documentation requirements.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_28e__subsec_d__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>authorized under state law to supervise such associate clinician, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_28e__subsec_d__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>complies with any supervision and documentation requirements required by law. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to alter any requirement concerning such services, including, but not limited to, scope of practice, supervision and documentation requirements.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="17b_28e__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For purposes of this subsection, (A) “independent licensed behavioral health clinician” means a psychologist licensed under chapter 383, marital and family therapist licensed under chapter 383a, clinical social worker licensed under chapter 383b or professional counselor licensed under chapter 383c, (B) “associate licensed behavioral health clinician” means a marital and family therapy associate licensed under chapter 383a, master social worker licensed under chapter 383b or professional counselor associate licensed under chapter 383c, and (C) “private practice” means a practice setting that does not require a facility or institutional license and includes both solo and group practices of independent licensed behavioral health clinicians.</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_28e__subsec_d__subsec_2__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“independent licensed behavioral health clinician” means a psychologist licensed under chapter 383, marital and family therapist licensed under chapter 383a, clinical social worker licensed under chapter 383b or professional counselor licensed under chapter 383c,</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_28e__subsec_d__subsec_2__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“associate licensed behavioral health clinician” means a marital and family therapy associate licensed under chapter 383a, master social worker licensed under chapter 383b or professional counselor associate licensed under chapter 383c, and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="17b_28e__subsec_d__subsec_2__subsec_C">
                <num>(C)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>“private practice” means a practice setting that does not require a facility or institutional license and includes both solo and group practices of independent licensed behavioral health clinicians.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_28e__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Not later than October 1, 2022, the Commissioner of Social Services shall amend the Medicaid state plan to add services provided by a naturopath licensed pursuant to chapter 373 as a covered service.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>