<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-56"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-56"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-56"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-56/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-56/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-56/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-56/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319o">
        <num>319o</num>
        <heading>Personal Care Assistance</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_56">
          <num>17b-56</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-21a). Compact</heading>
          <subsection eId="17b_56__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No person who has removed himself from one party state to another party state shall be ineligible for a welfare service in such other party state because of failure to meet that state's residence or settlement requirements for eligibility. The cost of providing a welfare service to any person made eligible therefor by reason of this compact shall be charged within the state in accordance with the laws of such state.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_56__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The appropriate official, department or agency of the state where application for a welfare service is made pursuant to this compact shall be entitled to request and receive any pertinent information available from any other party state with respect to such applicant.
ARTICLE IV</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_56__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The duly constituted administrative authorities of any two or more party states may enter into supplementary agreements for the provision of any service or facility in the field of social welfare which may be in addition to those denominated as welfare services in this compact whenever the states concerned shall find that such agreements will improve social welfare, its services or facilities. No such supplementary agreement shall be construed so as to relieve any party state of any obligation which it otherwise would have under other provisions of this compact; nor shall it authorize or require any party state to assume any obligation not otherwise authorized by law.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_56__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing in this compact shall be construed to invalidate any reciprocal agreement between a party state and a nonparty state relating to the reciprocal provision of welfare services nor to invalidate any statutory authority for such agreements.
ARTICLE V
Each party state shall appoint a compact administrator who shall act as general coordinator of activities under the compact in his state, and whose duty it shall be to cooperate with the compact administrators of other party states. The compact administrators of the respective party states shall have power to promulgate reasonable regulations to carry out the terms and provisions of this compact.
ARTICLE VI</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_56__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>This compact shall enter into full force and effect as to any state when enacted by it into law and such state shall thereafter be a party thereto with any and all states legally joining therein.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_56__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <heading>A state party to this compact may withdraw therefrom by enacting a statute repealing the same</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Such withdrawal shall take effect six months after notice thereof has been communicated officially and in writing to the governors and compact administrators of all other party states. However, the withdrawal of any state shall not affect the rights of any person who is receiving a welfare service pursuant to the provisions of this compact.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_56__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Withdrawal from any supplementary agreement made pursuant to Article IV shall be in accordance with the terms of such agreement.
ARTICLE VII
This compact shall be liberally construed so as to effectuate the purposes thereof. The provisions of this compact shall be severable and if any phrase, clause, sentence or provision of this compact is declared to be contrary to the constitution of any party state or of the United States or the applicability thereof to any government, agency, person or circumstance is held invalid, the validity of the remainder of this compact and the applicability thereof to any government, agency, person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby. If this compact shall be held contrary to the constitution of any state party thereto, the compact shall remain in full force and effect as to the remaining states and in full force and effect as to the state affected as to all severable matters.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>