<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-26"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-26"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17b-26"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-26/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-26/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-26/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17b-26/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319o">
        <num>319o</num>
        <heading>Personal Care Assistance</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17b_26">
          <num>17b-26</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 17-577). Department designated as state agency responsible for implementation of social services block grants and community services block grants. Development of outreach program. Report</heading>
          <subsection eId="17b_26__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Social Services shall act as the single state agency to coordinate, plan and publish annually the state social services plan for the implementation of social services block grants and community services block grants as required by federal law and regulation. Said department shall furnish copies of said plan to the joint standing committees of the General Assembly having cognizance of matters relating to appropriations and the budgets of state agencies and human services, at least sixty days prior to publication, for their review and recommendations, and shall consult with and furnish to said committees any additional information on such plan which they may request.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_26__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Social Services shall provide for the development of all mandated outreach programs in accordance with any mandate of the federal government as required by federal law and regulation for the implementation of social services block grants and community services block grants.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_26__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Social Services shall, on or before December fifteenth, annually, report to the Governor and said joint standing committees with regard to the activity of the department in the implementation of social services block grants and community services block grants, including but not limited to, fiscal data on expenditures of state and federal funds thereunder, and any recommendations for needed program legislation to insure the receipt of all federal funds available to the state from such grants.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="17b_26__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any organization receiving block grants pursuant to this section shall be subject to the provisions of section17b-99.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>