<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-281"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-281"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17a-281"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-281/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-281/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-281/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-17a-281/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_319c">
        <num>319c</num>
        <heading>Early Childhood Programs</heading>
        <section eId="sec_17a_281">
          <num>17a-281</num>
          <heading>(Formerly Sec. 19a-455). Voluntary admission to facility for persons with intellectual disability. Termination of admission</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Sec. 17a-281. (Formerly Sec. 19a-455). Voluntary admission to facility for persons with intellectual disability. Termination of admission.Any person who is a resident of Connecticut at the time an application is made by or on behalf of such resident under the provisions of this section, and who is, or appears to be, or believes such resident to be a person with intellectual disability, may apply, in writing, to the Commissioner of Developmental Services, on a form prescribed by the commissioner, for admission to any facility for persons with intellectual disability. Such application shall be accompanied by a medical history of the applicant, including any medical or physical condition requiring special attention, treatment or precautions, a written psychological report provided by a psychologist either licensed under the provisions of chapter 383 or employed by the Department of Developmental Services, who has personally examined the applicant prior to the filing of application for residential placement or a copy of the determination of eligibility made in accordance with section17a-212and the regulations adopted thereunder. The written psychological report shall include (1) a statement that the psychologist has personally examined the applicant not more than ninety days prior to the date of filing of the application, (2) the results of a psychometric assessment conducted not more than one year prior to the date of filing of the application, and (3) an evaluation of the applicant's current level of adaptive functioning, including self-care, mental health, social, academic and vocational needs. In the event of an emergency, admission to a residential facility may be made and the required medical history and psychologist's report may be submitted not later than thirty days after the date of such admission. The application for such person, if such person is a minor, may be made by a parent, legal representative of, or person having custody of, such minor. If such person is an adult who has had a plenary or limited guardian appointed pursuant to sections45a-669to45a-683, inclusive, such person's guardian may apply for admission and the commissioner may admit such person, provided the commissioner is satisfied that there is no conflict concerning the admission between the guardian and the protected person or the protected person's next of kin. If such conflict exists, the applicant may only be admitted under the provisions of section17a-274. The commissioner may approve any such application for admission if the person on whose behalf application is made is suitable for admission and if space is available and may terminate such admission at any time when the commissioner feels such person will not profit from continued placement. The provisions of this section shall not apply to persons who apply to the commissioner for respite care services for a period not to exceed thirty days.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>