<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-285b"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-285b"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-285b"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-285b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-285b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-285b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-285b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_214">
        <num>214</num>
        <heading>Business Tax Credits</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_285b">
          <num>12-285b</num>
          <heading>Licensure of cigarette manufacturers. Fees</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_285b__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every tobacco product manufacturer, as defined in section4-28h, selling cigarettes to consumers within this state, whether directly or through a distributor, dealer, or similar intermediary or intermediaries, shall secure a cigarette manufacturer's license from the Commissioner of Revenue Services. Such license shall be renewable annually. The annual fee for a cigarette manufacturer's license shall be five thousand two hundred fifty dollars. The commissioner shall not include or retain in the directory of tobacco product manufacturers developed and maintained in accordance with section4-28mthe name or brand families of any tobacco product manufacturer that has failed to secure and retain a cigarette manufacturer's license in accordance with this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_285b__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall not issue or reissue a cigarette manufacturer's license to an applicant if any of the following conditions apply:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_285b__subsec_b__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The applicant is neither (A) a participating manufacturer, as defined in Subsection II(jj) of the Master Settlement Agreement, as defined in section4-28h, nor (B) in full compliance with section4-28i;</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12_285b__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_A">
                <num>(A)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a participating manufacturer, as defined in Subsection II(jj) of the Master Settlement Agreement, as defined in section4-28h, nor</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12_285b__subsec_b__subsec_1__subsec_B">
                <num>(B)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>in full compliance with section4-28i;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_285b__subsec_b__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the applicant has imported cigarettes into the United States in violation of 19 USC 1681a; or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_285b__subsec_b__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the applicant has imported or manufactured cigarettes that do not fully comply with the federal Cigarette Labeling and Advertising Act, 15 USC 1331 et seq.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_285b__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such license shall be valid for a period beginning with the date of license to the thirtieth day of September next succeeding the date of license unless sooner revoked in the same manner provided in section12-295for revocation of the license of a dealer or distributor or unless the person to whom it was issued discontinues business. Upon revocation or discontinuance of business, the holder of the license shall immediately return such license to the commissioner. In the event of mutilation or destruction of such license, a duplicate copy, marked as such, shall be issued by said commissioner upon application accompanied by a fee of fifteen dollars.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>