<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-306b"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-306b"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-306b"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-306b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-306b/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-306b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-306b/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_214">
        <num>214</num>
        <heading>Business Tax Credits</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_306b">
          <num>12-306b</num>
          <heading>Penalty for wilful failure to submit a required report or pay the tax, or for wilful delivery of a document known to be false</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_306b__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person required under this chapter to pay any tax, or required under this chapter or by regulations adopted in accordance with the provisions of section12-313to make a report, keep any records or supply any information, who wilfully fails to pay such tax, make such report, keep such records, or supply such information, at the time required by law or regulations, shall, in addition to any other penalty provided by law, be fined not more than one thousand dollars or imprisoned not more than one year or both. Notwithstanding the provisions of section54-193, no person shall be prosecuted for a violation of the provisions of this subsection committed on or after July 1, 1997, except within three years next after such violation has been committed. As used in this section, person includes any officer or employee of a corporation or a member or employee of a partnership under a duty to pay such tax, to make such report, keep such records or supply such information.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_306b__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who wilfully delivers or discloses to the commissioner or the commissioner's authorized agent any list, report, account, statement, or other document, known by such person to be fraudulent or false in any material matter, shall, in addition to any other penalty provided by law, be guilty of a class C felony. No person shall be charged with an offense under both subsections</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_306b__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_306b__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section in relation to the same tax period but such person may be charged and prosecuted for both such offenses upon the same information.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>