<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-359"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-359"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-359"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-359/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-359/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-359/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-359/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_216">
        <num>216</num>
        <heading>Sales and Use Taxes</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_359">
          <num>12-359</num>
          <heading>Reports of representatives of transferors</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_359__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <heading>Succession tax returns and amendments thereto</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Except as herein provided, within six months after the death of the transferor the administrator, executor, administrator for tax purposes, administrator c.t.a. or administrator d.b.n. or administrator d.b.n., c.t.a. or, if there is no such fiduciary, any transferee of property, the transfer of which may be taxable under the provisions of section12-341,12-341b,12-342,12-343,12-345or sections12-345bto12-345e, inclusive, shall file with the court of probate for the district within which the transferor resided at the date of his or her death or, if the transferor died a nonresident of this state, with the court of probate for the district within which the real estate or tangible personal property is situated, a return, in duplicate, prescribed as to form by the Commissioner of Revenue Services and bearing notice to the effect that false statements made therein are punishable and containing all items necessary to the correct computation and assessment of the tax. Such return shall include among other things:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_359__subsec_a__subsec_1">
              <num>(1)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A copy of the written instrument evidencing any transfer which may be taxable under the provisions of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_359__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_359__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-341or12-341bor of section12-342,12-343,12-345or sections12-345bto12-345e, inclusive, or, if there is no written evidence, a written statement fully disclosing the circumstances under which the transfer was made; provided, in the case of a transfer evidenced by an insurance, annuity, pension plan, profit-sharing plan or other similar contract with an insurance company, in lieu of such copy of the written instrument, a summary thereof may be so filed;</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12_359__subsec_d__subsec_2">
              <num>(2)</num>
              <content>
                <p>an appraisal by the fiduciary or transferee, at its fair market value on the date of decedent's death, of each item of property, the transfer of which may be taxable under the provisions of section12-341,12-341b,12-342,12-343,12-345or sections12-345bto12-345e, inclusive;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_359__subsec_d__subsec_3">
              <num>(3)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a statement as to whether, or to what extent, the reported transfers are conceded taxable;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_359__subsec_d__subsec_4">
              <num>(4)</num>
              <content>
                <p>all items claimed as deductions under the provisions of section12-350or12-352, with an explanation of the circumstances under which each deduction is allowable;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_359__subsec_d__subsec_5">
              <num>(5)</num>
              <content>
                <p>a statement containing the name and relationship to the transferor of each individual, corporation, institution, society, association or trust benefiting by reason of any succession or transfer of property as set forth in sections12-340to12-343, inclusive, sections12-345and12-345bto12-345e, inclusive, and the value of the estate passing to each such beneficiary;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12_359__subsec_d__subsec_6">
              <num>(6)</num>
              <content>
                <p>such other information as the Commissioner of Revenue Services may deem necessary for the correct computation and assessment of the tax and the proper administration thereof. The fiduciary or transferee may correct any item on the succession tax return by filing with the probate court an amendment thereto in duplicate, prescribed as to form by the Commissioner of Revenue Services and bearing notice to the effect that false statements made therein are punishable and containing such changes in the return as the fiduciary desires to make, but no such amendment shall be permitted which would change the reported value of any property or withdraw a concession of taxability after a hearing has been held thereon pursuant to the provisions of subsection</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_359__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this section and no such amendment shall be permitted after the computation of the tax has become final. The probate court shall, within ten days of the filing of such return or an amendment thereto, forward a certified copy thereof to the Commissioner of Revenue Services.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_359__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <heading>Hearing on objections of Commissioner of Revenue Services</heading>
            <content>
              <p>Within one hundred twenty days after the receipt of such return, or any amendment thereto, the Commissioner of Revenue Services shall file with the fiduciary or transferee and with such court of probate a statement in writing setting forth in detail such objections as he may have to the valuations or concessions of taxability appearing thereon. Unless such fiduciary or transferee concedes the correctness of the Commissioner of Revenue Services' opinion or the Commissioner of Revenue Services withdraws his objection, the Commissioner of Revenue Services, fiduciary or transferee may file in the court of probate for the district within which the transferor resided at the date of his death or, if the transferor died a nonresident of this state, in the court of probate for the district within which the real estate or tangible personal property is situated, an application for a hearing upon those items set out in such return as to which the Commissioner of Revenue Services objects. Such court shall assign a time and place for a hearing upon the Commissioner of Revenue Services' objections to the return or amendment thereto and shall cause a copy of the order of hearing to be sent to the Commissioner of Revenue Services, such fiduciary or transferee and all other parties in interest at least fifteen days before the time of such hearing. The commissioner or any other party in interest may appear before such court at such hearing and be heard concerning the objections of the Commissioner of Revenue Services. If there is no appearance on behalf of the commissioner and it appears to the court that his position with respect to any matter in dispute ought not to be sustained, such hearing shall be adjourned for not less than ten days and notice of the time and place of such adjourned hearing shall be given to the commissioner, who may appear and be heard thereon. At such hearing, or adjournment thereof, the court shall hear such objections and determine the fair market value of </p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_359__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section12-367shall be the basis for computing the succession tax.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_359__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <heading>Extension of filing time</heading>
            <content>
              <p>For cause shown, the Commissioner of Revenue Services may, on the written application of the fiduciary or transferee filed with said commissioner within six months after the death of the transferor, extend the time for filing such return. Such application shall set forth the extension desired and the reasons therefor and a copy thereof shall be filed in the court of probate for the district within which the transferor resided at the date of his death or, if the transferor died a nonresident of this state, in the court of probate for the district within which the real estate or tangible personal property is situated. Unless, not later than sixty days after his receipt of such application, the Commissioner of Revenue Services files in the court of probate, a copy of his order denying or modifying the extension requested, the extension requested shall be deemed granted. If the extension request is denied or modified, the fiduciary may not later than thirty days of the receipt of such order from the Commissioner of Revenue Services, file in such court of probate an application for an extension of time to file the return setting forth the extension desired and the reasons therefor. The court of probate shall assign a time and place for a hearing upon such application not less than two nor more than four weeks after the filing thereof and shall cause a copy of the order of hearing to be sent to the commissioner and to the fiduciary or transferee at least ten days before the time of such hearing. The commissioner or any party in interest may appear before such court at such hearing and be heard concerning the requested extension. For cause shown, the court of probate may, after hearing on such application, extend the time for filing such return. Such court, after such hearing, shall forthwith send to the Commissioner of Revenue Services and the fiduciary or transferee a copy of any order extending or denying extension of the time for filing such return. Further extensions </p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_359__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <heading>Transferee defined</heading>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this chapter the word transferee shall include, but not be limited to, a donee and a beneficiary under a will, trust or power of appointment or under the laws of this state relating to descent and distribution.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_359__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <heading>Applicability</heading>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section shall not apply to estates of decedents dying on or after January 1, 2005.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>