<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ct-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-307"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-307"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ct-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ct"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-307"/>
          <FRBRname value="CGS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ct/act/cgs/sec-12-307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ct-legislature" href="https://www.cga.ct.gov" showAs="Connecticut General Assembly"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_214">
        <num>214</num>
        <heading>Business Tax Credits</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12_307">
          <num>12-307</num>
          <heading>Procedure on sale after confiscation</heading>
          <subsection eId="12_307__subsec_a">
            <num>(a)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When any property has been seized under the provisions of section12-305, the commissioner may, at his discretion, after a hearing as provided in this section, advertise such property for sale in a newspaper published or having a circulation in the town in which the seizure took place, at least five days before the sale.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_307__subsec_b">
            <num>(b)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person claiming an interest in such property may make written application to the commissioner for a hearing within thirty days after the date of such seizure, stating his interest in the property and his reasons why it should not be forfeited. Upon receipt of such application, the commissioner shall, within thirty days, assign a date for such hearing and give written notice as to the time thereof to any person or persons making such application. At such hearing, the commissioner shall determine whether such cigarettes should be forfeited and written notice of such determination shall be forwarded to each applicant claiming to have an interest in such cigarettes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_307__subsec_c">
            <num>(c)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person aggrieved by any such determination may appeal therefrom to the superior court for the judicial district of New Britain, as provided in section12-312.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_307__subsec_d">
            <num>(d)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No sale of any property under the provisions of section12-305shall be made while an application for a hearing is pending before the commissioner, but the pendency of an appeal under the provisions of section12-312shall not prevent the sale unless the appellant posts a satisfactory bond, with surety, in an amount double the estimated value of the property, conditioned upon the successful termination of the appeal.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12_307__subsec_e">
            <num>(e)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When any such sale has been consummated, the proceeds thereof shall become the property of the state, provided any person who has an interest in such property shall have the same rights with respect to the proceeds of such sale as such person had in relation to such property prior to sale.
(Return to ChapterTable of Contents)(Return toList of Chapters)(Return toList of Titles)</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>